<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Punch, or the London Charivari, Vol. 150, March 29, 1916</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <idno type="gutenberg">22688</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>This text is freely available for re-use under US and UK law, consult
                            your local legal restrictions if elsewhere.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This text is a TEI version of a Project Gutenberg text originally located at
                            <ptr target="http://www.gutenberg.org/dirs/2/2/6/8/22688/"/>. As per their license agreement we have removed
                        all references to the project's trademark, however have included this
                        pointer to the original in case you want the plain text, or their XHTML
                        version. </p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2008-06-27T16:13:17.261+01:00"/>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <figure>
                <graphic url="images/209.png"/>
            </figure>
            <div xml:id="d1e49" type="div2">
                <head>CHARIVARIA.</head>
                <p>"His seventy-one years sit lightly on
Mr. <name rend="sc">Gibson Bowles</name>," says the Special
Correspondent of <title>The Evening News</title>.
No doubt Mr. <name rend="sc">Bowles</name> has some good
reason for permitting this familiarity,
for he is not a man to be lightly sat
upon.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"In particular," says a report on the
resources of German East Africa, "the
President of the Silk Association has just
directed attention to the wild silk
of the anaphe worm." The animal
the great two-horned silkworm discovered by Sir
<name rend="sc">Harry Johnston</name>, before whose furious
charges, according to the report of
natives, even the elephant will give way.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A telegram from Rome states that it
is generally believed that Admiral
<name rend="sc">Tirpitz</name> resigned because he could not
take the German Fleet out. Others
again maintain that it was because
he could no longer take the German
people in.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>It was recently stated in a Parliamentary
Report that verminous uniforms
had been purchased by the
Government for the sum of £2,650 and
immediately resold for £400.  The
difference is accounted for by the fact
that they were sold as going concerns.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A white rook has been observed at
Boston Road, Brentford, and a local
ornithologist writes to say that the bird
is probably an accidental straggler from
King's Bishop's Fourth.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"To-day in many English homes,"
says a patriotic contemporary, "alien
birds are carolling all unconscious of
their countries' doom." One had independently
noticed how the modulated
of the Turkey buzzard had
taken on a mournful tone.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"It is not unusual for horses to go
to sleep as they walk along," said a
sagacious coroner last week. How often
in the old four-wheeler days, when we
were going <title>ventre a terre</title> from Buckingham
Palace to the National Liberal
Club, conversation was rendered impossible
by the snores of the flying steed.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The price of admission to Kew for
perambulators is 3d. on ordinary days,
1s. on student days. The extra charge
has been found necessary because of
the fact that large numbers of horticulturists,
in order to escape military
service, have taken to travelling in
these vehicles.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>According to the author of <title>In a
College Garden</title> "it is not advisable
to encourage any but educated ladies
to become gardeners." It is always
pleasant to note the extent to which a
simple thing like a potato will recognise
and respond to gentility in those
who associate with it.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"The Italian Ambassador opened the exhibition
of the Royal Society of Brush Artists at
the society's premises in Suffolk-street."</p>
                    <p>
                        <title>Evening Paper.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>Mr. Punch welcomes the implicit admission
that there are others.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"What is needed is that we should have on
each of the main lines of our overseas communications
at least one ship that is faster
than anything else afloat."—<title>Manchester
Guardian</title>.
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>Is it not extraordinary that the Admiralty
should never have thought of
this simple device?</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>From a theatre programme:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"All the Male Members of the above Company
are either attested under Lord Derby's
Scheme, or are otherwise Ineligible for
Service."
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>The erroneous impression that to be
attested is the short road to ineligibility
has evidently spread from the platform
to the stage.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page210" n="pg 210"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e170" type="div2">
                <head>FOR THEY ARE JOLLY POOR FELLOWS.</head>
                <quote>
                    <p>
[The fine example of patriotism shown by the Universities of
Oxford and Cambridge throws into painful relief the action of some
of the obscure remnant, including College Fellows, who have excused
themselves from service or adopted an attitude of superior detachment
in relation to the War.]
</p>
                </quote>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>You Intellectuals of Cam and Isis,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Pale phantoms in the dawn of Freedom's light,</l>
                        <l>And you that in this hour of England's crisis</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Haven't the conscience (or the heart) to fight;</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>You cosmopolitans without a country,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Who go aloof on philosophic quests,</l>
                        <l>Sucking the fruit of knowledge from the Hun-tree</l>
                        <l rend="i2">And spiritual milk from alien breasts;</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>False to that Brotherhood, who for the splendour</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Of a great cause, with gallant hearts and gay,</l>
                        <l>Of youth and youth's high promise made surrender,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Because their courage knew the nobler way;</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>I envy not your chance on their returning;</l>
                        <l rend="i2">When, scarred with war, they come from overseas,</l>
                        <l>There should be trouble in those Seats of Learning</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Where you sat tight and took your pedants' ease.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Short shrift you'll get for your convenient scruples;</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Conducted thither where the wet stream winds</l>
                        <l>You shall receive as elementary pupils</l>
                        <l rend="i2">An object-lesson good for little minds.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Somewhere about the Guts of Cam and Isis,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">May I be well in front to see you then</l>
                        <l>Taught by immersion what the local price is</l>
                        <l rend="i2">To pay for being prigs instead of men.</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <p>O. S.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e279" type="div2">
                <head>PHILOGAMUS.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e283" type="div3">
                    <head>(<title>A Socratic Fragment</title>.)</head>
                    <p>"... It is plain, therefore," said Socrates, "that the
man whose soul is afflicted with illness will desire above
all things to have it cured as quickly as possible, and for
this purpose he will submit himself to one who understands
the curing of souls. So far, I think, we are agreed, are
we not?"</p>
                    <p>"Yes, indeed," said Agathon, "that would appear to be
the wisest course."</p>
                    <p>"Then why," said Socrates, "do we find that men who
are generally eager to be cured of an ague are indisposed to
take care of their soul when it is manifestly suffering?
You yourself have declared that your soul is sick within
you, yet you consult nobody and take no steps."</p>
                    <p>"Nay, nay, Socrates, I cannot allow you to catch me
like this. Perhaps I spoke thoughtlessly when I mentioned
my soul just now. Certainly I had not intended that you
should tie me up with your questions and draw conclusions
which it was impossible for me to foresee."</p>
                    <p>"Then I suppose the fault must be mine, for in truth I
had not designed to catch anyone, least of all yourself, my
dear Agathon. But we will defer the consideration of the
matter to a more favourable time, for I see Philogamus
approaching and, if we may judge by the outward signs, he
seems to be, as one might say, in a terrible state."</p>
                    <p>Hereupon we turned to observe Philogamus, to whom
indeed something painful and calamitous must have happened,
for his garments were disarrayed and his hair was
unkempt, and anger was seated upon his frowning brow,
and he was muttering to himself and calling the gods to
witness that he was unjustly treated and that no such misfortune
had ever before happened to any other man; and
he was beating his hands wildly together and was forgetting
to salute his friends. Seeing him thus distraught
Socrates plucked him by the sleeve as he passed and
addressed him.</p>
                    <p>"Hail, Philogamus," he said, "what great misfortune
do you announce to us? Have the Barbarians at last
seized upon the Piræus, and are they even now marching
irresistibly on the Acropolis? Are you sent out to summon
us to arms? Here are a few of us who will join with you,
laying aside even their most pressing private business, and
will help to defend the State and themselves to the last
gasp. Only do you deliver your message and let us know."</p>
                    <p>"This," said Philogamus, "is no moment for laughing,
though in laughter, O Socrates, you are always easily first,
as they say, and the rest nowhere. But have you not
heard what has happened?"</p>
                    <p>"No," said Socrates, "and we much desire to know.
I can speak confidently for myself, and Agathon here is,
I am sure, in a fever of impatience."</p>
                    <p>"Listen, then, and, by the gods, you shall be made aware
of an injustice that calls for immediate redress. They are
even now on the point of calling up the married men to go
to the War."</p>
                    <p>"That is very interesting; and what do the married men
say to it?"</p>
                    <p>"What do they say?" shouted Philogamus. "They
say they will not go unless, according to the promises of
Darbius and Ascuthius, all the unmarried men are taken
first;" and he began once more beating his breast and
glaring with his eyes like a dog who has been for long
without water.</p>
                    <p>"Softly, my good friend," said Socrates, "softly. As to
the promise, I know it is being rigidly kept. All the willing
single men are gone or going, and the unwilling are being
compelled to join as quickly as is possible. What more
can be done?"</p>
                    <p>"Something ought to be done."</p>
                    <p>"That is very true," said Socrates; "something ought
always to be getting itself done, and the something at this
moment is that the Barbarians ought to be beaten. But
tell me, with regard to the married men, are they not
concerned in the safety and welfare of the State?"</p>
                    <p>"That, indeed, they are," said Philogamus; "none more
so."</p>
                    <p>"In that case why do they hang back and complain
when the State declares that its safety and welfare demand
that they should be ready to go? Because one here and
there has concealed himself, is it for you, a married man, to
retire when by going you might help to thrust back the
Barbarians? Are you one of those that are called the
attested ones?"</p>
                    <p>"Yes, that I am," said Philogamus, proudly displaying
his brown armlet with the red crown.</p>
                    <p>"Then it is you, as it appears to me, who have given a
pledge and made a promise, and that promise, I am sure,
you will fulfil to the best of your ability. When the time
comes it is for you to go at once and not to weary the
market-place with empty noise and murmurs of complaint.
For remember this: the man who has taken a wife and has
brought up children under the State's protection owes more,
if it be possible...."</p>
                    <p>(<title>Here the fragment ends.</title>)</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>From a description of the German <name rend="sc">Crown Prince</name>:—</p>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Before the war he liked to imitate the English, and posed as
a German megalomaniac."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Daily News</title>.
</p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Yes, we believe there were some English like that—before
the War.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page211" n="pg 211"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e384" type="div3">
                    <head>THE MARKS OF THE BEAST.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/211.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page212" n="pg 212"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/212.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e404" type="div2">
                <head>THE SCOTTISH REEL THING AT LAST.</head>
                <p>Now that Sir J. M. <name rend="sc">Barrie</name> has
shown us the Transatlantic kinema
man's idea of the perfect <title>Macbeth</title>, it is
up to the purveyor of American films
to retaliate by presenting one of his
plots for ordinary stage performance
in the Kirriemuir manner. Here and
there an inadvertent touch of Western
colour may be anticipated.</p>
                <p rend="it">
                    <name rend="sc">Scene</name>— Kensington Gardens. The
Heroine—oh, the little love!—is
taking a dander round the "Keep off
the Grass" boards. Her feet are bare,
and this is probably the reason why
from time to time she dances among
the trees.  In the background the
Hero, wearing a divided kilt, rides
about on a horse. Having
thus given the audience time
to settle, the play starts.
         </p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="it">Heroine ( perceiving <name>Hero</name>)</hi>.
Gee! there's that rube I met
up North.  Sic a bonny lad
too! (<hi>sighing sadly</hi>) But he
hasna much siller, I'm sair
misdootin'. Guess there's no
twelve-pound look about him.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Hero</title> (<title>dashing up and dismounting</title>).
Wal, I wanter
know. Say, ain't you the peach
I useter see from my window
in Thrums?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Heroine</title> (<hi rend="it">coyly</hi>). Havers!</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Hero</title> (<title>not to be outdone</title>),
Dagont!</p>
                <p rend="it">[She strolls away with her
chin in the air, her shoes
and stockings in her hands,
and the famous red light in
her eye. She goes behind a
tree, and the <name>Hero</name>, thinking
she has retired there to
greet sadly, follows to console her.
However, he discovers that she is
merely resuming her footgear, and
he retreats modestly.]</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Hero</title> (<title>rolling his eyes wildly to denote
love</title>). A snod bit lassie, that. I mean to
say—I—ay! Juist so! Ay, ou ay!</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Heroine</title> (<title>returning with her shoes on</title>).
For the love of Mike—I mean Losh
keep's!—are you still here?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Hero.</title> That's so. I wanter put you
wise about me. I ain't no boob, as
you seemter think. You can bet your
rubbers on that. Maybe you're thinkin'
that I'm but a puir laddie. Wal, let <hi rend="it">me</hi>
tell <hi rend="it">you</hi> you're guessin' wrong. I'm
an author—I do writin' stunts. And
if I don't swell around in new pants all
afternoon it's only because I have to
keep all my cheques among the crumbs
in my tobacco pouch. I <hi rend="it">have</hi> to do it.
All the best Scots writers do it. We
call it Arcadian Mixture.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Heroine.</title> Guess that rollers out the
course of true love some. But let <hi rend="it">me</hi>
tell <hi rend="it">you</hi> there's another feller after me—a
puir feckless body of a villain.
And, Losh preserve us, here he comes!</p>
                <p rend="it">[The <name>Villain</name> enters. He looks rather
like a revue-producer who has seen
better nights. The <name>Hero</name>, overcome
by bashfulness at being discovered in
conversation with a female, conceals
himself behind his accent.]</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Villain.</title> See here, gal, you just gotter
marry me.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Heroine.</title> Shucks! I should say,
Dinna blether, ma mannie.</p>
                <p rend="it">[The <name>Hero</name> creeps cautiously out of
ambush.]</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Villain</title> (<hi rend="it">caressingly</hi>). I have always
loved my little Mary.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Hero</title> (<title>subtly ironic</title>). Imphm! Imphm!
Ou ay, imphm!</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Villain</title> (<title>surprised but finding a way</title>).
Oh, the dears! oh, the darlings!</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Hero</title> (<hi rend="it">bewildered</hi>). What's all that
blatherskite, any old way?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Villain</title> (<title>privily drawing bludgeon</title>).
It was Sneeky Hobart who never went
to kirk again after they substituted
tin plates for the usual cloth collecting-bags.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Hero</title> (<title>perplexed and off his guard</title>).
Guess you've gone bughouse, sonny.
I mean, I'm no quick in the uptak'——</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Villain.</title> Are ye no? (<title>brandishing
bludgeon</title>). Well, I am! (<hi rend="it">He fells the
<name>Hero</name> senseless to the ground.</hi>) And noo,
lassie, I can sorter concentrate on you.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Heroine</title> (<title>in the most ladylike way</title>).
Help! oh, help!</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Villain.</title> Say, you don't seemter
freeze on to me, somehow. But you
must and shall be mine! Come awa',
lassie.</p>
                <p rend="it">[He seizes her and she resists. Meanwhile
the <name>Hero</name>, who fell on to a
clump of genuine thistles, makes a
superbly-rapid recovery from his
unconsciousness.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Villain</title> (<title>pausing to mop his brow</title>).
Say, you'll got my goat for sure if you
kick up like this, lassie.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Heroine.</title> Gee! That's a great idea.
If only Peter Pan's goat——</p>
                <p rend="it">[The <name>Hero</name>, inspired, crawls away unnoticed.]</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Villain</title> (<title>preparing to renew the struggle</title>).
Lassie, I'm quite sweered o' you.
There's an awesome look in your eye.
And can ye no be more ladylike in your
fechting? Remember whose heroine
you are.</p>
                <p rend="it">[He again strives to bear her off. The
<name>Hero</name>, having broken off a couple of
branches and affixed them to his
head—a little trick he learned from
the Admirable Crichton—now
returns disguised as a
goat. He rushes at Villain,
who flees and scales the park
railings. But his overcoat
collar catches in the spikes,
and he hangs suspended
and helpless. In that position
he slowly starves, and
dies inconspicuously as the
<name>Hero</name> and <name>Heroine</name> finish
the play.]</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Hero</title> (<title>extending his arms</title>).
Say, is it a deal? I mean, will
ye ha'e us, lassie?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Heroine</title> (<title>with little wells of
gladness in her eyes</title>). It's a
cinch. Guess you're Mr.
Smart from Smartville. Ay,
I'm thinkin' I'll tak' you.
But you men are fickle callants—that's
what every
woman knows. Come awa'
and let's find a little meenister
at once.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Hero.</title> Oh, joy! oh, rapture! oh, rosy
rapture!  [<title>They embrace and exeunt</title>.]</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Audience</title>. Hoots!</p>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">Curtain</name>.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e719" type="div3">
                    <head>Journalistic Anticipation.</head>
                    <p>"THE COMING GREAT SEA BATTLE.</p>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Exclusive Pictures.</name>"</p>
                    <p>
                        <title>"Sunday Herald" Poster.</title>
                    </p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page213" n="pg 213"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e742" type="div2">
                <head>AT THE FRONT.</head>
                <p>The subtlety of the Military mind
beats and will beat me to the end.
Yesterday we lived in a row of earthen
dwellings in a depression in the ground,
which anyone might be excused for referring
to, if not as trenches, at least as
dugouts. These alone of all the marvels
of military engineering I have observed
during the War admitted of being
shelled with equal exactitude from due
in front and due in rear; and water
seemed to have been laid on throughout.
Taking all these things into consideration
some Authority labelled them, once
for all, "Billets."</p>
                <p>Last night we moved into a commodious
cellar of a house which still
leans against the next. It is only
five minutes from town, and tramlines
pass the door. Nay more, they stop
abruptly at the door—such are the
improvements effected by R.E. Inside
the cellar are three bits of chairs, a
table-top on boxes, and an inimitable
ancestral smell that no deodorizer
known to modern warfare can cope
with. And all this is called "Trenches!"
Our servants do their best to support
the official illusion by neglecting to
clean our boots and regarding with
surprise and some little sadness any
tendency on our part to wash.</p>
                <p>But you must not imagine that life
here is all honey. Even here we do a
bit for our eight-and-sixpence. Every
evening there comes down from the
front line a report that our men there
want more food. A stricter or less
beneficent C.O. than ours might at once
institute a court of inquiry into what
has happened to all the food we gave
them last night. But not so with us.
"The boys want food," he says to the
Adjutant, "and, by Heaven, the boys
shall have it."</p>
                <p>No sooner said than handed on to
someone else to do. The Adjutant
works off a little bit of his strong personal
dislike for me in a note, couched,
if you please, in the most friendly terms,
intimating that he has raised heaven
and earth to get me off, but the C.O.
insists that I (as the only competent
officer for the task) shall supervise the
conduct of our rations to the front,
middle and back lines to-night.  He
adds that the Intelligence Corps report
that information received from deserters
leads us to suppose that Fritz intends
to strafe all roads and communication
trenches in our sector to-night.</p>
                <p>The carrying party is supplied by a
sister battalion, and makes the night
thoroughly well acquainted with its
views about a unit that can't supply
blanks to carry their blanked rations
for their blanked selves. Sometimes a
second or a third trip may be necessary,
and then the carriers' patriotic fervour
expresses itself in terms almost potent
enough to do the carrying for them.
For some reason or other the R.E., who
design material for our porterage, consider
its end and not its portability.
Their special line of ready-made wire
entanglements would entangle a hippopotamus;
and when it comes to carrying
one a mile-and-a-half you find it
has no wheels, no handles, and simply
won't fold up into the pocket. The
usual procedure is for a man or two to
roll on one of these barbed-wire death-traps
until they are well stuck on them
and then crawl to the point of delivery.</p>
                <p>Sometimes, of course, we have accidents.
<pb xml:id="page214" n="pg 214"/>
Last night, for instance, two
men were proceeding (by the way the
great point about being a soldier is that
you never walk, run or otherwise ambulate—you
proceed, or proceed at the
double, which of course is much nicer
for you)—yes, were proceeding, one at
each end of an entanglement, along the
top of a slope, when the leader missed
his footing altogether and rolled down
to the morass below. The second, after
a brief struggle, followed with the entanglement.
This movement involved
not only the man behind, who was
bearing a footboard, but also the remainder
of the section. The entire
avalanche was precipitated on to the
leaders, and remained there struggling
like the population of a fly-paper until
a squad arrived with wire-cutters.
When the R.E. heard of it they wanted
the episode published in Corps Orders
as a testimonial. But what the men
wanted done about the R.E. I dare not
tell you.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e769" type="div2">
                <head>THE TRUTH ABOUT CINEMALAND.</head>
                <p>A <name rend="sc">distinguished</name> neutral observer,
who has just returned from a visit to
Cinemaland, has furnished our representative
with the following interesting
account of his experiences and conclusions.</p>
                <p>One of the first things (he says)
that impressed me was that in the
great cities of Cinemaland there is,
outwardly at least, little or no sign
of scarcity. On the contrary, at the
various hotels and restaurants, as well
as several private entertainments that
came under my observation, a note of
almost wanton luxury appeared to be
aimed at. Evening dress is worn whenever
possible, and the costumes of the
ladies are invariably the last word in
ultra-fashionable extravagance. Food
is as yet obviously plentiful; what is
not consumed being frequently flung
about, especially by the humorous
elements of the population, and wasted
with reckless prodigality.</p>
                <p>In spite however of this ostentation
signs are not wanting that the true
condition of the country is increasingly
precarious. Crime of all sorts is
rampant. Judging even by what I
myself witnessed within a short period,
the detectives of Cinemaland must all
be working overtime. Quite recently
a gang, under the leadership of a ruffian
who elected to be known as The Clutching
Hand, made large sums of money by
working upon the terrors of its victims.</p>
                <p>Another significant symptom is that
respect for law and authority as such
appears to be almost non-existent. The
police force of Cinemaland is a body
of men who are most of them of conspicuously
full habit. I can vouch for
it that the appearance of these officials
is almost invariably greeted with derision;
and should they (as frequently
happens) incur physical maltreatment
or other misfortune in the exercise
of their duties popular sympathy is
almost always on the side of their
opponents.</p>
                <p>A notable exception to this feeling
is found in the attitude of the populace
towards their chosen ruler, the Emperor,
or Film-Lord, Charlemagne-Chaplin. It
is only fair to record that recent spectacular
(and carefully stage-managed)
appearances of the monarch have been
greeted with every demonstration of
unswerving loyalty and affection.</p>
                <p>More significant perhaps to an outside
spectator is the undeniable fact
that the Wild Western portions of
Cinemaland are to-day in a state of turbulence
bordering upon anarchy. The
Cowboys, who are its chief denizens,
would seem, so far as my experience
goes, to spend their entire time in exploits
of murderous violence; though
here (as elsewhere among this remarkable
people) the influence of sentiment
is often unexpectedly potent. It can
hardly be doubted that a populace so
emotional and ill-balanced as that of
Cinemaland will have little power to
withstand the strain of disaster.</p>
                <p>Despite my apparent freedom from
restraint I am persuaded that I was
kept under the observation of a number
of uniformed officials during the whole
course of my stay in Cinemaland; and
I am bound to confess that my departure,
which was made under cover
of darkness, was not unattended with
a sense of personal relief.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e800" type="div2">
                <head>PARABLES FOR BOSCHES.</head>
                <p>Once upon a time there was a Father
who was devoted to his child. He fed
it and nursed it and watched it grow
and gave it toys to play with—both
soldiers and boats. Also he made it
promises that some day he would extend
their house and garden until no
house and garden were bigger. Every
year he took it to the top of a high
precipice and showed it beautiful lands
and water which should some day be
theirs.</p>
                <p>The child had heard this promise so
often that it used to ask, "When?
when?" And always the answer
was, "Some day, some day."</p>
                <p>And then at last the day came, and
the Father took the child to the high
precipice yet once more, but behold it
chanced that they both fell over and
were smashed, the Father hopelessly
and the child very, very badly, so that
it would for long years or perhaps for
evermore be a cripple.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e815" type="div2">
                <head>ONE OF OUR ALLIES.</head>
                <p>Somewhere in France—no, let me
be bold and say in Paris—there is a
young French soldier named Charles.
Less than two years ago he was a
plumber and whole; to-day he has but
one arm, his left; the other and a piece
of his shoulder with it having gone in
saving his country from the foe.</p>
                <p>Charles is shy and very modest, and
no bigger than so many French youths—he
is only twenty-two—with dark-brown
hair and blue eyes with very
black centres, and a moustache that
never succeeds in looking more than
three weeks old. Being, however, brave,
he does not let his maimed condition
unduly trouble him, but runs his
errands (all that he can now do) and
whistles as he runs, and is glad to be
alive at all, instead of dead, as so many
of his comrades are and as his Colonel
is, as I shall tell.</p>
                <p>At the Front Charles's duties were
these. A despatch—a <hi rend="it">pli</hi>, as they call
it—would be given him either back of
the lines to deliver in the trenches, or
in the trenches to deliver back of the
lines, and in order to get there, if fighting
was in progress, it was necessary
for him to crawl for perhaps one or two
kilometres on his stomach. On a certain
day of intense activity, Charles in
his trench was handed one of these
critical missives for the commanding
officer, who was a kilometre or so
behind, and this he placed in his satchel
and then began the hazardous journey.</p>
                <p>No one ever knows when the supreme
moment of his life is coming; nor did
Charles, but it was then.</p>
                <p>This being a terrific day—as a
matter of fact it was during the famous
battle for the Maison du Passeur,
when the French and Germans were
losing and retaking trenches for hours—he
had to crawl all the way, only to
come suddenly upon the body of the
commanding officer himself stretched
dead in a carrot field.</p>
                <p>To Charles's mind there was then
but one thing to do, and that was, as he
had been unable to deliver the message,
to take it back to the sender. He
therefore started on the return journey,
and was only a few yards from
his trench, and still un-hit, when he
found a wounded officer on the ground.
Here was a new problem, but necessarily
having to stand up and throw
aside all precautions, Charles got him
as well as he could on his back and,
still un-hit, half carried, half supported,
him to the trench, and was at once
away again with his despatch. It
was at this moment that an exploding
shell hurled the satchel from big
hands and flung it on the open ground
<pb xml:id="page215" n="pg 215"/>
between the French trenches and the
enemy's, which were here separated
only by a few yards. At any cost the
despatch must not fall into German
hands, and Charles, who miraculously
had not been injured by the explosion,
began instantly to climb out of the
trench to recover it, and this in spite of
a sergeant, who called to him to keep
under cover. But Charles, having one
idea and one only, and that was to save
from the foe the despatch that had
been entrusted to him, succeeded in
reaching it and securing it; and then
came another shell that shattered his
arm.</p>
                <p>That is all he remembers; but he
must have rolled back to the bottom of
the trench, where he was found, two
days later, still clutching the satchel.
And after that, although he remembers
the coffee he was given to drink, all is a
haze until he came fully to himself in
hospital and found that no longer had
he a right arm.</p>
                <p>Such is the story of Charles's effort
for his country.</p>
                <p>Now I do not claim for Charles that
he is any braver or has a finer sense
of duty than many another French
soldier; but this I know, that when he
recovered he was summoned to the
Invalides to receive not only the <title>Croix
de Guerre</title> but the <title>Médaille Militaire</title>
with the palm, which corresponds to
our Victoria Cross, and that now,
although, having left the Army, he no
longer wears uniform but merely such
poor civilian clothes as he can afford
as a messenger, when he walks along
the Boulevards—which he does as
seldom as he can, so shy is he—there
is not an officer, seeing the
ribbons on his coat, who does not
salute this little plumber with as much
punctilio as though he were General
<name rend="sc">Joffre</name> himself; and, blushing crimson,
Charles returns the salute.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/215.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"Mrs. Humphry Ward seems to have gone
for inspiration to contemporary characters,
and now in 'Tasker Jevons' it is difficult not
to find the lineaments of a well-known writer."</p>
                    <p>
                        <title>Evening Standard.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>Quite so: and Miss <name rend="sc">May Sinclair</name> made
<title>A Great Success</title> of it.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e895" type="div2">
                <head>NURSERY RHYMES OF LONDON TOWN.</head>
                <p>II.—<name rend="sc">King's Cross.</name>
                </p>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>King's Cross!</l>
                        <l rend="i2">What shall we do?</l>
                        <l>His purple robe</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Is rent in two!</l>
                        <l>Out of his crown</l>
                        <l rend="i2">He's torn the gems!</l>
                        <l>He's thrown his sceptre</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Into the Thames!</l>
                        <l>The Court is shaking</l>
                        <l rend="i2">In every shoe—</l>
                        <l>King's Cross!</l>
                        <l rend="i2">
                            <title>What</title> shall we do?</l>
                        <l>
                            <title>Leave him alone</title>
                        </l>
                        <l rend="i2">
                            <title>For a minute or two.</title>
                        </l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <p>III.—<name rend="sc">Bishopsgate</name>.</p>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Bishopsgate Without,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Bishopsgate Within!</l>
                        <l>What a clamour at the gate,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">O what a din!</l>
                        <l>Inside and outside</l>
                        <l>The Bishops bang and shout,</l>
                        <l>Outside crying, "Let me in!"</l>
                        <l>Inside, "Let me out."</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page216" n="pg 216"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/216.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1013" type="div2">
                <head>THE ADJUTANT.</head>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>In that great Room which military error</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Has miscalled Orderly (for it is not,</l>
                        <l>But full of tumult and debate and terror,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">And worried writers growing rather hot,</l>
                        <l rend="i4">For ever floundering in seas of chits</l>
                        <l rend="i4">And forms and counterfoils and wrathful writs),</l>
                        <l rend="i4">Alone unfevered mid the storm he sits</l>
                        <l rend="i2">And tells them all exactly what is what.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Who so alert to solve the frequent riddle,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">To judge if Jones should have his train-fare free,</l>
                        <l>Whether the band requires another fiddle,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">And which is senior, Robinson or me?</l>
                        <l rend="i4">Who shall indite such circulars as his</l>
                        <l rend="i4">To Officers Commanding Companies</l>
                        <l rend="i4">About their musketry, or why it is</l>
                        <l rend="i2">So many men take sugar in their tea?</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>And when at times he shuns the sacred table</l>
                        <l rend="i2">And like some eagle swoops upon parade,</l>
                        <l>Men mark his coming and there bursts a babel</l>
                        <l rend="i2">As with new zeal the subalterns upbraid,</l>
                        <l rend="i4">Lecture and illustrate, and on the right</l>
                        <l rend="i4">Form sullen squads, and hope they're being bright—</l>
                        <l rend="i4">Save those white-livered ones who at the sight</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Hide their commands in some convenient glade.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>For he is terrible; and few folk relish</l>
                        <l rend="i2">The words of doom which shake his diaphragm;</l>
                        <l>Yet is the heart of him not wholly hellish,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">But in his playing-hours he's like a lamb;</l>
                        <l rend="i4">And who'd have said that one so skilled to strafe</l>
                        <l rend="i4">And, when I err, too truculent by half,</l>
                        <l rend="i4">Could own so rich, so rollicking a laugh,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Would see so well how humorous I am?</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Yet if with leave unasked I quit the barrack,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Ever behind I dread that he will call,</l>
                        <l>Speed up the street in some avenging Darracq</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Or on the Underground retrieve his thrall;</l>
                        <l rend="i4">Nor in my home can quite escape the spell</l>
                        <l rend="i4">But freeze with horror at the front-door bell,</l>
                        <l rend="i4">For fear the parlour-maid may speak my knell,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">May knock and say that <hi rend="it">he</hi> is in the hall.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>And, sleeping, still I have to brook his blusters;</l>
                        <l rend="i2">A monstrous Adjutant is always nigh</l>
                        <l>At dream-reviews and endless dreamy musters,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Laden with lists and schemes and syllabi;</l>
                        <l rend="i4">And, though he find no failing anywhere,</l>
                        <l rend="i4">But all are present and correct and fair,</l>
                        <l rend="i4">
                            <title>I</title> never fail to make the fellow swear,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">
                            <title>I</title> always seem to catch his horrid eye.</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page217" n="pg 217"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e1202" type="div3">
                    <head>TO THE GLORY OF FRANCE.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/217.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page218" n="pg 218"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1215" type="div2">
                <head>ESSENCE OF PARLIAMENT.</head>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/218.png"/>
                </figure>
                <p>
                    <title>Tuesday, March 21st.</title>—Returning
from Westminster this afternoon I
stumbled in Whitehall upon a Member
whom I had not seen in his place this
Session. "Going down to the House?"
I asked. "What, is it sitting?" he
replied; and then it appeared that he
was just home on short leave after
working hard "somewhere on the Continent,"
and had no present interest in
political controversy. As I reflected
on a speech I had just listened to, it
occurred to me that the attitude of
some of the stay-at-home Members
towards the War is much the same as
that of my hon. friend towards the
House. "What, is it still going on?"</p>
                <p>If the Germans were in occupation
of the Black Country, if Oxford were
being daily shelled, as Rheims is, and if
with a favouring breeze London could
hear the dull rumble of the bombardment,
as Paris can, I wonder if Members
would still be encumbering the
Order-paper with the sort of trivialities
that now find place there.</p>
                <p>An exception may be made in favour
of Mr. <name rend="sc">Joe King</name>. He has discovered
a little late in the day that a war
is going on in Europe, and that it
affects a little country called Belgium,
whose neutrality was guaranteed by
the Powers. He was anxious to know
whether Belgium had formally renounced
her neutrality, and was no
doubt greatly surprised to learn from
Sir <name rend="sc">Edward Grey</name> that, owing to one
of the guaranteeing Powers having
invaded her, Belgium had become a
belligerent.</p>
                <p>I do not know whether Mr. <name rend="sc">Pringle</name>
was in the House when this announcement
was made. But if so it evidently
created no impression on his mind. In
the debate on the Army Estimates he
followed Captain <name rend="sc">Tryon</name>, who had delivered
an urgent appeal to the Government
from the text, "A strong Army
and a shorter War." Mr. <name rend="sc">Pringle's</name>
ideal is just the reverse. In his view
the Army is too big already, and
is taking too great a toll from our
industrial and commercial population.
The great men who won the Napoleonic
War—after twenty-three years—had
not a big army; and the consequence
was that, while it was going on, British
trade expanded by leaps and bounds.
To-day, owing to our disastrous military
policy the demands upon our
tonnage were so heavy that people
had to go short of sugar and tobacco.
Let us conserve our resources and be
ready to dictate terms when Germany
has been financially ruined. When
Mr. <name rend="sc">Pringle</name> at last sat down after
three-quarters of an hour of this sort
of thing I longed for ten minutes of
Mr. <name rend="sc">Balfour</name> at his best. But he was
not present, and Mr. <name rend="sc">Long</name> was so much
occupied in defending the Government
against the charge of having broken
faith with the married men that Mr.
<name rend="sc">Pringle</name> never got the trouncing he
deserved.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Wednesday, March 22nd.</title>—One of
the most cherished beliefs of the House
of Commons is that upon the Second
Reading of the Consolidated Fund Bill
anything under the sun may be discussed.
Colonel <name rend="sc">Yate</name> was justly surprised,
therefore, when the <name rend="sc">Speaker</name>
ruled that he was out of order in criticising
the Indian Government for its
conduct of the Mesopotamian Expedition,
and advised him to reserve his
remarks for the Indian Budget discussion—equivalent
in these times to
the Greek Kalends.</p>
                <p>Mr. <name rend="sc">Chamberlain</name> was surprised too,
but, regardless of the ruling, proceeded
to make a carefully-prepared reply to
the speech which the Hon. and gallant
Member had not been allowed to
deliver. He frankly admitted that
there had been a lamentable breakdown
of the hospital arrangements,
but steps had been taken to improve
them, and a telegram from General
<name rend="sc">Lake</name> showed that the treatment of
the men wounded in the recent engagement
was satisfactory.</p>
                <p>Mr. <name rend="sc">Pemberton-Billing</name> essayed another
and a longer flight to-day, but
had a good deal of engine trouble. His
<pb xml:id="page219" n="pg 219"/>
Parliamentary friends ought to have
warned him that the House does not
care to listen to a man reading extracts
from his own leading articles, however
prophetic they may have been; that
the constant reiteration of a phrase
such as "I would like to suggest,
Mr. <name rend="sc">Speaker</name>," soon becomes tiresome,
and that to call somebody else "the
De Rougemont of the air" is to invite
the <title>tu quoque</title>. Members became more
and more impatient as the orator
became more and more dogmatic;
and when he rhetorically demanded
the name of "one man to whom
we could turn to solve the problem"
they derisively chorused, "<name rend="sc">Billing</name>!"
Mr. <name rend="sc">Tennant</name>, recognising the
feeling of the House, did not spend
much time in refuting Mr. <name rend="sc">Billing</name>'s
wild assertions, but devoted most of
his speech to replying to Mr. <name rend="sc">Joynson-Hicks</name>,
who had pleaded that the East-Coast
towns should be more promptly
warned of approaching air-raids. He
had personally investigated the arrangements
and was positively "staggered"
at "the wonderful network that had
been set up," and he invited Mr.
<name rend="sc">Joynson-Hicks</name> to come with him
privately and share his amazement.
Mr. <name rend="sc">Ellis Griffith</name> was not convinced.
He thought that there were still too
many strands of red tape in the network,
and reiterated the hope that the
<name rend="sc">Derby</name> Committee would soon develop
into a Ministry of the Air.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Thursday, March 23rd.</title>—A distressing
report in the papers this morning,
that the <title>Galloper</title> had been blown up
by the Germans, made the friends of
Sir <name rend="sc">Frederick Smith</name> anxious. Had
he, on one of his periodical visits to
the trenches to see Friend <name rend="sc">Winston</name>,
stumbled across an enemy mine?
Happily the report was grossly exaggerated.
The <title>Galloper</title> was only a light-ship,
and had not been destroyed by
the enemy but merely withdrawn by
the Trinity House; and on the Treasury
Bench this afternoon there was the
<name rend="sc">Attorney-General</name> very much alive.</p>
                <p>Mr. <name rend="sc">Trevelyan</name> had a motion on the
paper condemning the administration
of the Defence of the Realm Act, and
in support of it produced a sheaf of
cases, in which he said the Government
had abused its powers. Among
other acts of vile oppression they had
ravished from her home, on September
1st, while her father was away
shooting partridges, and had subsequently
interned without trial, a young
lady against whom no charge had been
formulated. It sounded very dreadful,
and someone called out, "Is this a
Russian case?"</p>
                <p>Then arose Sir F. E. <name rend="sc">Smith</name>, and
with a few forensic gestures demolished
the house of cards that Mr. <name rend="sc">Trevelyan</name>
had so laboriously erected. Most of his
cases were out of court because they
had already been in court, the decisions
he impugned being those of the
magistrates. As for the daughter of
the partridge-slayer she was an associate
of a notorious German spy, and
had come back from Switzerland with
a message for one of his agents. As
her case had been fully considered by
the late <name rend="sc">Home Secretary</name> he suggested
that Mr. <name rend="sc">Trevelyan</name> should talk to him
about it.</p>
                <p>This was the most pungent speech
of the afternoon. The most amusing
was that of Mr. <name rend="sc">Ginnell</name>, who kept
the House in fits of laughter for ten
minutes while in his most rasping
tones he jerked out epigrams against
"this thing calling itself a Government."
The Coalition was described
as "two poisons blended, which could
not make a wholesome drink." Never
before has he had such a success. I
only hope it will not turn his head
and encourage him to attempt conscious
humour.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/219.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"<name rend="sc">The World at War at —— Theatre
Only."</name>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <title>Advt. in Evening Paper.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>We are relieved to find that the area
of conflict has been so much restricted.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page220" n="pg 220"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1407" type="div2">
                <head>FROM SOMEWHERE IN AFRICA.</head>
                <p>We have just returned from another
of those little expeditions which are
becoming almost a habit with the —— Frontier
Force when in search of an
enemy whose discretion is only rivalled
by that of the German High Seas Fleet.
We moved out four days ago with
all the pomp of war—horse, foot and
guns, ambulances and long trains of
transport waggons, the fierce vivid
fighting of the desert before us. We
rode seventeen miles that day and
camped at some wells. As we rolled
ourselves in our blankets round the
camp-fires to rest for the glorious contest
of the morrow our hearts should
have been filled with dreams of undying
fame. But we were really wondering
when the squadron transport would
arrive with our porridge and sausages
for breakfast.</p>
                <p>Next morning we were in
the saddle by 3 <name rend="sc">A.M.</name>, and
after some ten or twelve
hours of unbroken and undisputed
progress we captured
two Arab shepherds
in charge of as many as
eight sheep. This <title>succès
fou</title> was the cause of justifiable
satisfaction.</p>
                <p>In the first place we
scented liver and bacon for
breakfast. In the second
place it seemed to promise
a settlement of the long-standing
dispute between
me and the General. The
General has a preposterous
theory about the existence
and hostility of a vast number of
mythical Arabs in our immediate
neighbourhood. Now this is obviously
absurd. With the exception
of three palm-trees, which belong
to us, there is nothing but sand for
about two hundred miles in all directions,
and even an Arab cannot subsist
entirely on sand. Of course, if there
were any Arabs near us, they would be
so enraged at finding themselves at a
spot two hundred miles from anything
except sand that they would be violently
hostile to anyone, especially to
the people who had engaged the only
three palm-trees in the neighbourhood.
But it is their existence that I dispute
with the General. It is true he took a
most unfair dialectical advantage, about
a fortnight ago, by having a large battle.
But my contention is that the enemy
on this occasion were merely orange-sellers
from the nearest town, hired by
the General for the purpose of argument.</p>
                <p>These two shepherds, however, did
seem to support his theory of the existence
of Arabs, but as to their hostility
there was still room for doubt. They
were both extraordinarily old and unbelievably
dirty. Also they were, as
was very natural, extremely frightened.
Seeing that they knew themselves to
be the only living people for quite a
number of miles round, it must have
appeared to them that the entire —— Frontier
Force had come out solely
for the purpose of capturing them, and
that, as it had ridden some forty miles
to do it, it would not be in a good
temper. It was therefore rather hard
to judge of their hostility, because as
soon as they were confronted with the
General and the interpreter they gave
one yell of "Allah!" and fell flat, face
downwards, in the sand, from
which position they refused to move.
They would not even budge when the interpreter
took all their clothes off with
a view to searching them. They probably
thought this was merely a preliminary
to skinning them. When
they were finally induced to speak, I
believe they were understood to say
that we were the first men they'd seen
for eight years. I don't wonder they
were frightened. If you have lived all
your life all alone in the middle of a
howling desert with Grandfather it's a
very frightening thing when a complete
Frontier Force marches forty miles for
the sole purpose of capturing you.</p>
                <p>But the day's excitement was not
over yet. Towards evening I took my
troop off at a gallop in person and
captured a camel. It was a very young
camel, hardly bigger than a sheep on
stilts, and it cried like a child at the
sight of me. This, I hope, was not so
much due to my frightful appearance
in my red moustaches as to the fact
that it had probably never seen a man
at all (not being eight years old), let
alone an army.</p>
                <p>The curious aversion which it conceived
for my moustache threatened to
hold up the entire Frontier Force for
the rest of the day, for it would neither
be led nor driven. Fortunately, however,
we had a very black Soudanese
camel-driver with us as guide, and he
came and spat at it, which soothed it
considerably, and it followed him like
a lamb. We got it back to camp next
day and it is tied up near my tent. It
has apparently made up its mind to
waive the moustache question, and we
now spit at one another in the friendliest
fashion whenever I pass. I hope
in time to train it to bring up my bath
water in the morning from the three
palm-trees.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Later.</title>—The camel was the last
episode of the campaign, and we returned
to —— yesterday. The total
bag of a four days' expedition was—sheep,
8; shepherds, 2; camel, 1. The
human section was subsequently released
on the grounds that their
political views were satisfactory.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/220.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1451" type="div2">
                <head>ON THE MENACE OF HOME-BAKERY.</head>
                <quote>
                    <p>
["Women <hi rend="it">can</hi> bake bread if
they will. It is much easier than
trimming hats."—<title>"Housewife,"
in "The Daily News."</title>]
</p>
                </quote>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Aminta, be not led away</l>
                        <l>By words that sanguine women say;</l>
                        <l>Though simpler be the baking bread</l>
                        <l>Than trimming gear for your fair head,</l>
                        <l>Let your concern remain, I ask,</l>
                        <l>The sterner and the nobler task.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>The nobler task: I'll tell you why.</l>
                        <l>Shall Bloggs, our baker, wilt and die</l>
                        <l>For loss of trade, his brood of eight</l>
                        <l>Left destitute and desolate?</l>
                        <l>And must <title>I</title> perish 'neath the stress</l>
                        <l>Of culinary frightfulness?</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>No, dear. The millinery art</l>
                        <l>Is where I'd have you play your part;</l>
                        <l>For, though your hats may work intense</l>
                        <l>Despite on my aesthetic sense,</l>
                        <l>Whatever pain their crudeness brings</l>
                        <l>At least I needn't eat the things.</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e1541" type="div3">
                    <head>Commercial Candour.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"You never know your luck when you get
our <name rend="sc">FRUIT</name>."—<title>Advt. in Irish Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"<title>Mr. Hayes.</title> Certainty is defined in Webster
as the maximum of our expectations.
(Loud laughter.)</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>The Judge</title> (<hi rend="it">laughing</hi>). Let us get on. This
is more like <title>Punch</title> than anything else.
(Laughter.)"—<title>Pall Mall Gazette.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>It will now have to be called the
Supreme Court of Punch and Judicature.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page221" n="pg 221"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/221.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1598" type="div2">
                <head>PULP FAMINE NOTICES.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e1602" type="div3">
                    <head>(<title>A Hint to Reviewers.</title>)</head>
                    <p>A <name rend="sc">WRITER</name> in a recent issue of <title>The
Daily Chronicle</title> prefaces a column of
novel notices with the following remarks:
"The smaller papers consequent
upon the famine in 'pulp' have
made the reviewing of the new novels
rather a job, but at least it is possible
to give news of them."</p>
                    <p>But the writer tackles his job in a
half-hearted manner, using such ponderous
polysyllables as "international"
and "acquisition." Now Mr. Punch,
always ready to lend a hand in a good
cause, has instructed one of his young
men to rewrite two of <title>The Chronicle</title>
reviews in words of one syllable, and
presents them to his contemporary as
models for imitation in the future.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi>I.—Mrs. Ward.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">A Great Hit.</name> By Mrs. Hump. Ward.
Lond., Smith, Eld., <title>3s. 6d.</title> net.</p>
                    <p>For the most part Mrs. <name rend="sc">Ward</name> writes
long yarns, and those who read her
books look to her for more than five
score thou. words. Here she gives us
a short tale in which the three chief
<title>rôles</title> are filled by a man who earns
lots of dibs by his pen, his wife, and
their, or his, friend—a peer's wife,
who takes him up for her own ends.
She tries in her hard bright way to
shape his course as she views it, which
means a place in the sun for <hi rend="it">her</hi>. The
wife, who has brains as well as a warm
heart, will not be robbed of her man
like this, puts up a good fight, and in
the end has the best of the bout with
the pale witch with dark eyes who had
waved her wand o'er the knight of the
pen. It is not poss. to deal with all the
points of Mrs. <name rend="sc">Hump. Ward's</name> book in
words of one syll., but we can at least
say here is a good tale to speed the
flight of the hours of eve.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi>II.-The Bills.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">The Shop Girl.</name> By C. N. and A. M.
Sons o' Bill. Lond., Meth., <title>6s.</title>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <title>Miss Child</title> is a nice sweet girl with
lots of sense who goes to the land of
the Yanks and makes things hum a bit
in a nice sweet way. She meets her
fate on board the big ship on the way
out; but a long and bright yarn has to
be read ere she makes the Port of Joy.
We see a Yank store in full swing,
learn much of the way it is worked,
and the folk who run it are well drawn.
To be frank one could scarce think that
so <hi rend="it">chic</hi> a tale could be made out of the
prose of New York. But to the Bills—if
I may so call them—all the world is
a stage, and they see through the heart
of the New Eve with a gaze that is
quite weird. In fine this is a tale in
which the Bills, while they take new
ground, write with all their old <hi rend="it">flair</hi>
and charm.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1684" type="div3">
                    <head>FORAIN.</head>
                    <p>When <name rend="sc">M. Raemaekers</name> went to Paris
the other day to receive his decoration
and be fêted for his fine pro-Ally spirit,
it was M. <name rend="sc">Forain</name>, as the head of living
French cartoonists, who received him
in the name of France and conferred
the Order. M. <name rend="sc">Forain's</name> public appearances
are nowadays few and far between,
but he still wields—and none
more searchingly—a pencil keen and
swift as a sword, and he never takes
it in hand but to create something
memorable. A selection of his recent
work is now on view in London at
22, Montagu Square, the residence of
Mr. <name rend="sc">Campbell Dodgson</name>, the Keeper of
the Prints at the British Museum, the
proceeds of the entrance fees being
intended for a hospital for French
wounded soldiers at Arc-en-Barrois.
The little exhibition, which should be
seen by all who love great draughtsmanship
and France, remains open
until April 1.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page222" n="pg 222"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1707" type="div2">
                <head>AT THE PLAY.</head>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">"The Barton Mystery."</name>
                </p>
                <p>One of the most difficult feats of
juggling is, I understand, the deft tossing
up and catching of a heavy weight
(say a dumb-bell), a very light weight,
such as a champagne cork, together
with any old thing of irregular shape,
a bedroom candlestick, for instance.
Mr. <name rend="sc">Walter Hackett's</name>
                    <title>The Barton
Mystery</title> is a most ingenious turn of
this sort.</p>
                <p>The <title>fiancé</title> of the sister of the wife of
<title>Richard Standish, M.P.</title>, is under sentence
of death for the murder of <title>Mr.
Barton</title>. He happens to be innocent,
though he admits at the trial that he
quarrelled violently with and even
threatened <title>Barton</title> on the night of the
murder, and his revolver has been found
by the dead man's side. That vindictive
relict, <title>Mrs. Barton</title>, is holding back some
material evidence which could save the
condemned man, or so <title>Standish</title> thinks,
and she is adamant. Now <title>Barton</title> was
unquestionably a bad egg, but the
widow doesn't want the whole world
to know it—at least not till she finds
the woman. Some woman, who had
incidentally written some, shall we say,
very impetuous love letters, is being
shielded. Who is she? Is it <title>Standish's</title>
wife, for instance? Ah!... This is
the dumb-bell.</p>
                <p>A <title>Lady Marshall</title>, the wife of a <title>Sir
Everard Marshall</title>, a comic scientist in
perpetual flight from his overwhelming
spouse, is one of the sort that finds a
new religion every few months and is
now in the first fast furious throes of
her latest, which is some form of psychomania,
whereof the high priest is one
<title>Beverley</title>, a plausible ringletted charlatan
of alcoholic tendencies (<title>Sludge the
Medium</title>, without his cringe and snarl),
who ekes out his spasmodic visitations
of genuine psychic illumination with
the most shameless spoof. This is
the cork.</p>
                <p>The candlestick is the dream <hi rend="it">motif</hi>,
always a ticklish business to handle,
and in this particular case—well, no, I
won't be such a spoil-sport as to go into
that, for the chief pleasure of this kind
of an entertainment is the succession
of pleasant unexpected shocks which
are deftly administered to the audience
by the author.</p>
                <p>There were times indeed when the
latter nearly dropped his dumb-bell—times
when it was in imminent peril
of barging into the cork; and most
certainly the candlestick very nearly
slipped out of his hand. But it just
didn't, so you will see that it was really
a most exceptional piece of jugglery.
Of course I will admit you have to
swallow the robust assumption that
into a household over which the shadow
of death in its ugliest form hovers so
threateningly two fatuous people, to
wit the scientist and his wife, can
come and babble about their own
trivial domestic troubles or their latest
philosophy of life. But then mystery
plays always are like that, and this is a
jolly good one of its kind—a kind which
it pains me, as a superior person, to
confess that I liked enormously.</p>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/222.png"/>
                </figure>
                <p>Mr. <name rend="sc">H. B. Irving</name> as the preposterous
<title>Beverley</title> was in his very best form.
<title>Beverley</title> is really a creation. How
much the author's and how much the
player's it would be an impertinence
to inquire. This imperturbable trickster
with his thin streak of genuine sensitiveness
to psychic influence; his
grotesquely florid style—the man certainly
has style; his frank reliance on
apt alcohol's artful aid; his cadging
epicureanism; his keen eye for supplementary
data for his inductions and
prophecies; his cynical candour when
detected, is presented to us with Mr.
<name rend="sc">Irving's</name> rich-flavoured and most whimsical
sense of comedy, with all his
exuberant abundance of gracious or
fantastic gesture and resourceful business.
In the trances, sometimes real,
sometimes simulated, he gives you a
plausible sketch of how a modicum of
psychic power (whatever that may be),
laced with whisky neat, might colour
a séance. Mr. <title>Hackett</title>, by way of
showing that he has not ignored the
literature of his subject, has adapted
from the admirable, but, I regret to
say, entirely untrustworthy, because
incurably original, <name rend="sc">Maeterlinck</name> an entirely
new definition of psychometry.
But we certainly will not go into that.</p>
                <p>Mr. <name rend="sc">Holman Clark</name> as the sceptical
<title>Sir Everard</title>, completely spoofed by
<title>Beverley</title> in the end, with an elaborate
make-up ruthlessly reminding us of
our simian ancestry, potters cleverly
about the stage with that admirable
and amiable craft which he has at such
easy command. Miss <name rend="sc">Marie Illington</name>
as <title>Lady Marshall</title>, the seeker after
light, kept the burlesquerie of her part
skilfully within bounds—indeed this
matter of key was extraordinarily well
handled by the three players entrusted
with what I have ventured to call the
cork <hi rend="it">motif</hi>.</p>
                <p>As to the more serious business, Mr.
<name rend="sc">H. V. Esmond</name> seemed to behave very
much as one would imagine a decent
M.P. behaving in such embarrassing
circumstances. He suspected his wife
with all the ardour which public
men on the stage always exhibit. His
little turn of desperate tragedy carried
conviction—almost too much conviction,
as you will find—but I won't
explain.</p>
                <p>Miss <name rend="sc">Jessie Winter</name>, as his wife,
very adroitly contrived an ambiguous
effect of likely guilt but possible innocence.
She more than fulfils the promise
of her last performance in this
theatre, but she must (may I tell her?)
arrest the development of "the Fatal
Cæsura," that exasperating histrionic
device whereby every salient phrase
is broken up for no conceivable reason
into two halves. In the secondary
stages there is but slender hope of a
cure; in the tertiary there is none.</p>
                <p>Miss <name rend="sc">Darragh</name> was, as required, the
vindictive widow to the life (this kind
of life, you understand), and Miss <name rend="sc">Hilda
Bayley</name> played very charmingly the
little wilful <title>fiancée</title> who—but no, I must
keep my promise.</p>
                <p>With much less evidence than the
applause and generally keyed-up attitude
of the Savoy audience afforded me,
I could risk a psychic communication
in the authentic manner of a Beverley
séance. "All is dark.... It is getting
light.... I see a man.... He leans
eagerly to a telephone.... He thrusts
something into envelopes. He goes on
thrusting things into envelopes. The
telephone keeps ringing.... It is....
Can it be? Yes, it <hi rend="it">is</hi> a Box Office." An
institution which at the Savoy should be
busy for many months to come.</p>
                <p>T.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e1864" type="div3">
                    <head>A Misnomer.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"In memory of the name of the late Dr.
F. C. Batchelor it is proposed that the name
of the Forth Street Maternity Hospital (Dunedin)
be altered to that of the Batchelor
Hospital."—<title>Southland Times</title> (<title>N.Z.</title>)
</p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page223" n="pg 223"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/223.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1891" type="div2">
                <head>MUSIC IN WAR TIME.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e1895" type="div3">
                    <head>The Converted Collector.</head>
                    <p>(<title>An Order in Council prohibits the importation
of all musical instruments.</title>)</p>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>In ancient, peaceful <title>ante-bellum</title> days—</l>
                            <l>Now far remote as <name rend="sc">Hannibal's</name> or <name rend="sc">Hanno's</name>—</l>
                            <l>I had a weakness, possibly a craze,</l>
                            <l>For buying Hun pianos.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>I let no patriotic sentiment</l>
                            <l>My honest inclination curb or fetter;</l>
                            <l>On foreign articles my cash I spent,</l>
                            <l>Because I liked them better.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>Nor would I now proscribe Germanic Art,</l>
                            <l>Their one surviving claim to lasting glory,</l>
                            <l>Or bar <name rend="sc">Beethoven, Wagner, Bach, Mozart—</name>
                            </l>
                            <l>
                                <name rend="sc">Strauss</name> is another story.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>But while our enemy unshattered stands</l>
                            <l>In any single theatre or sector,</l>
                            <l>I take no interest in German "grands,"</l>
                            <l>As player or collector.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>I will not have them broken up or burned,</l>
                            <l>Although they cease to give me delectation,</l>
                            <l>That mean to keep them suitably interned</l>
                            <l>Throughout the War's duration.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>But now the Board of Trade, those lynx-eyed gents,</l>
                            <l>Our economic needs severely scanning,</l>
                            <l>The importation of all instruments</l>
                            <l>Have just resolved on banning.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>No matter; I possess a set of pipes</l>
                            <l>Made in the land whose emblem is the Thistle;</l>
                            <l>Three Indian tom-toms of peculiar types</l>
                            <l>And a Bolivian whistle.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>I've a Peruvian nose-flute, made of bone,</l>
                            <l>A war-conch brought me from the South Pacific,</l>
                            <l>Which, by a leather-lunged performer blown,</l>
                            <l>Is really quite horrific.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>I have some balalaikas, few though fit,</l>
                            <l>Whose strings I have acquired some skill in tweaking;</l>
                            <l>And several pifferi, whose tubes emit</l>
                            <l>A most unearthly squeaking.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>I am, alas! too old and weak to fight,</l>
                            <l>But on these non-Teutonic pipes and tabors</l>
                            <l>I hope a martial spirit to incite</l>
                            <l>In "conscientious" neighbours.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>And when my time, as soon it must, shall come,</l>
                            <l>My epitaph perhaps might thus begin well:</l>
                            <l>"He 'did his bit' upon the Indian drum;</l>
                            <l>He played the mandolin well.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>Others who stayed at home to criticize</l>
                            <l>More vocal proved; he, on a falling rental,</l>
                            <l>In furthering the cause of the Allies</l>
                            <l>Was always instrumental."</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>In an account of a <name rend="sc">Burns</name>' celebration
given by the <title>North Battleford News</title>
(Saskatchewan), it is remarked that "the
absence of any kind of spirituous liquors
around the festive board and the fact
that the ladies were present" were
unique features of the entertainment.
But, according to the same report, there
was yet another: "'The Immoral
Memory' was given by Rev. D.
Munro."</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page224" n="pg 224"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e2121" type="div2">
                <head>OUR BOOKING-OFFICE.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e2125" type="div3">
                    <head>(<title>By Mr. Punch's Staff of Learned Clerics.</title>)</head>
                    <p>It is a tragic coincidence that, just as <name rend="sc">Rupert Brooke's</name>
now famous sonnets were published in volume form after
his own death, the appearance of his <title>Letters from America</title>
(<name rend="sc">Sidgwick and Jackson</name>) follows immediately upon the
death of Mr. <name rend="sc">Henry James</name>, who had written the preface
to them. Thus in one book we have the last work of two
writers, widely separated in age and circumstance, but
united by a very real bond of artistic and personal
sympathy. How generous was the elder man's appreciation
of the younger may be seen in this preface; it is at its best
and simplest in dealing with that charm of personality by
which all who knew <name rend="sc">Rupert Brooke</name> will most vividly
remember him. Elsewhere it must be confessed that the
preface is by no means easy reading, so that one emerges
at last a little breathless upon the transparent and sunlit
stream of the <title>Letters</title> themselves. Many who recall these
from their publication in <title>The Westminster Gazette</title> will be
glad to meet them again. Those who knew the writer only
as the poet of 1914 will perhaps
wonder to find him the
whimsical and smiling young
adventurer who moves with
such boyish enjoyment through
these pages. There is holiday
humour in them, even in the
occasional statistics—holiday
tasks, these latter; and everywhere
the freshness of an unclouded
vision. "Only just in
time," one thinks, sharing the
happiness that his <title>Letters</title>
reflect, and grateful for it as
for a beautiful thing snatched
so narrowly from fate.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>Mrs. <name rend="sc">Belloc Lowndes</name> has
written a story of the War
that has at least the distinction
of being absolutely
fair. She has indeed got so
far away from the perhaps
excusable error of painting
Germans uniformly black that her Huns in <title>The Red
Cross Barge</title> (<name rend="sc">Smith, Elder</name>) are made upon the average
quite as attractive as their enemies. This by way of
warning, so that if you are in no mood to look for
pearls amid swine you may avoid some impatience and
a feeling that impartiality can be carried too far. Not by
any means that <title>The Red Cross Barge</title> is a pro-German
book.... There is an attractive sense of atmosphere about
Mrs. <name rend="sc">Lowndes</name>' picture of the little French town in which
a group of Germans are left during what appears to them
the triumphal march to Paris. Here <title>Herr Doktor Max
Keller</title> meets and falls in love with a French girl who is
looking after certain wounded of both nations. The peaceful
and picturesque air of the little place during this quiet
occupation is well contrasted with the horrors that befall
it when the draggled and drink-sodden soldiery come surging
back in their retreat from the Marne. Eventually, just as
the Germans are leaving, <title>Keller</title> is fatally wounded, and
dies holding the hand of the enemy who has become so
dear to him. One can hardly call the tale anything but
sentimental, but it is sentiment of a fragrant and wholesome
kind. In the years to come such stories will no
doubt multiply indefinitely, but there will be few more
gracefully and gently told.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/224.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>Mr. <name rend="sc">Richard Pryce</name>, true to the fashion of describing
the childhood of heroes at great length, has in <title>David
Penstephen</title> (<name rend="sc">Methuen</name>) out-<name rend="sc">Comptoned Mackenzie</name>. <title>David</title>
in fact dallied so persistently in the nursery that I began
to wonder if he would ever emerge; but, when he does
get a move on, his story is strangely appealing. His father
and mother, having ideas of their own, had excused themselves
from the formalities of wedlock, and before <title>Mrs.
Penstephen</title> broke down under the strain of this omission
<title>David</title> and his sister, <title>Georgiana</title>, were born. Subsequently
the parents were married, and had another son. But before
this legitimate addition to the family a boating accident had
deprived the world of two cousins of <title>Penstephen père</title>, and
in consequence he inherited a baronetcy. This change of
fortune affected his views, and as time passed by he became
as orthodox a baronet as any you could wish to find in <title>Burke</title>.
All of which was galling to <title>David's</title> mother, who loved and
was jealous for those children who were born to suffer for
their parents' original morals. The situation required very
delicate handling, and Mr. <name rend="sc">Pryce</name> is to be congratulated
warmly upon the manner in which he has developed it.
Perhaps a little more humour
would have added salt to the
tale, but however that may be
we have a careful study of a
boy and an exquisitely sympathetic
portrait of a mother.
The latter part of the book
is admirable both in what it
tells and in what it merely
suggests. More is the pity
that Mr. <name rend="sc">Pryce</name> has weighed
down <title>David's</title> childish back
with too heavy a load of detail.
My advice to you is to skip
some of the earlier pages, and
so husband your strength for
the better enjoyment of the
remainder.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>
                        <title>The Duel</title> (<name rend="sc">Allen and
Unwin</name>) is a study in the
<name rend="sc">Gorky</name> tradition, by <name rend="sc">Alexander
Kuprin</name>, of life in an
obscure Russian regiment and
an out-of-the-way provincial town before the great awakening
that followed Mukden and Port Arthur purged away
much dross and prepared the way for these latter days of
sacrifice and heroism. It is a mournful document, a piece
of devil's advocacy, a Russian counterpart of Lieutenant
<name rend="sc">Bilse's</name>
                        <title>Life in a Garrison Town</title>, identical in temper and
astonishingly similar in some of its detail. It is clear that
the author, who was for seven years an infantry lieutenant
and probably little fitted for the military life even at its best,
endured much unhappiness, for the marks of suffering have
burnt themselves into the book so savagely that the English
translation, though characterized by a crudity which might
reasonably be expected to accomplish much in the way of
eliminating the personality of the author, cannot quite
rob his work of its impression of power and intimate
tragedy.  Those who are not in search of light refreshment
and who will remember that this last decade of
Russian national regeneration and reorganisation has
rooted up the incompetence, the false standards, the irregular
discipline and the inhuman barriers between officers
and men here commented upon, may read these bitter
chapters with profit. As for the translator, he might do
well to study one of the <name rend="sc">Garnett Turgenieffs</name>, and see
how this kind of thing should be done.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>








               <!--Gutenberg License information removed.-->
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>