<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Punch, or the London Charivari, Vol. 147, July 15, 1914</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <idno type="gutenberg">23658</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>This text is freely available for re-use under US and UK law, consult
                            your local legal restrictions if elsewhere.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This text is a TEI version of a Project Gutenberg text originally located at
                            <ptr target="http://www.gutenberg.org/dirs/2/3/6/5/23658/"/>. As per their license agreement we have removed
                        all references to the project's trademark, however have included this
                        pointer to the original in case you want the plain text, or their XHTML
                        version. </p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2008-06-26T23:49:52.885+01:00"/>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb xml:id="page61" n="pg 61"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e46" type="snippets">
                <head>CHARIVARIA.</head>
                <p>Two men carrying bombs were arrested last week on the outskirts
of Paris, and are suspected of a plot against the <name rend="sc">French President</name>. They alleged that the bombs were made
for the <name rend="sc">Tsar of Russia</name>, but the
<name rend="sc">Tsar</name> denies that he gave the
commission.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The town of Criccieth, it is reported, has decided to give up
gas in favour of electricity. This, of course, is not meant as a
slight on its most illustrious resident.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Posted at Ventnor, Isle of Wight, on July 14, 1904, a postcard
has just been delivered at the Grapes Hotel in Cowes. The recipient
is said to have expressed the opinion that it would have been
quicker, almost, to have telephoned the message.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>
                    <persName>Miss <name rend="sc">Nina
	 Boyle</name>
                    </persName>, of the <name>Women's Freedom League</name>, has sent to the papers a list of ladies on whom she
considers the <name rend="sc">King</name> ought to bestow honours.
Among the writers there is one notable omission, and <persName>Miss
<name rend="sc">Marie Corelli</name>
                    </persName> is said to be more of an
anti-Suffragette than ever.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"NEW THEATRE FOR LONDON,<lb/>
                    <name rend="sc">all seats in the house to be booked</name>."</p>
                <p>So the great difficulty has been solved at last! So many theatres
fail because the seats are not taken.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A movement is on foot to induce Mr. <name rend="sc">Charles
Garvice</name> to change the name of his play, <title>A Heritage of
Hate</title>, as so many patrons of melodrama have experienced
difficulty in pronouncing the title as it stands at present.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>In a struggle between a British sailor and a German policeman at
Wilhelmshaven the other day honours seem to have been fairly even.
The policeman, who used his sword, lost his head, and the sailor a
piece of his nose.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Two men of good position were tried last week before the State
Court of Berlin for refusing to address a policeman as "Mr." That
will surprise no one who knows his Prussia. It is the sequel which
takes our breath away. The two men were acquitted!</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Volume 10 of the Census of 1911 shows that in the preceding ten
years clergymen of the Established Church declined from 25,235 to
24,859. "The decrease is accounted for by the lack of young men
taking orders." The wonder is that such orders were not at once
snapped up by alert Germans.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Miss <name rend="sc">Laura Wentworth</name>, of Nebraska, known
as "The Big Hat Girl," has, we are told, sailed from New York in
the <title>Imperator</title> with a hat which measures 58 inches in
diameter. These giant liners are justifying themselves.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>We are glad that the <name rend="sc">Postmaster-General</name>
has promised a Bill against foreign sweeps. Only the other day we
received a circular headed "Schimneys Scheaply Schwept."</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>While we are ready to grant that it is not always easy to find
the apt quotation, we cannot help thinking that <title>The Daily
Telegraph</title> would have caused less offence if it had published
the following paragraph without any tag at all:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>The Mayor and Mayoress of Kensington, Alderman and Mrs. W. H.
Davison, held a reception at the Kensington Town trail last
evening, their guests numbering between 400 and 500.</p>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Oh, how peaceful is their sleep,</l>
                        <l>They who "Keating's" always keep.</l>
                    </lg>
                </quote>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"Cheerful Company at all the Cafés. Soup to Cheese 1/-,"
announces an advertisement in <title>The Manchester Guardian</title>. We
have heard of lively cheese before, but the chatty soup must be
something of a novelty.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"Strawberries are going out," reports <title>The Evening News</title>.
We are in a position to confirm this statement. We met one out the
other evening.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>According to <title>La France Militaire</title> the French Navy is about
to try the experiment of enlisting black sailors. We should say
that they will be found to make the most admirable stokers, not
showing the dirt like the white men.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Describing a recent visit of a party of Congressmen and State
officials to one of the teetotal battleships of the American Navy,
a contemporary says, "The distinguished guests took water with what
grace they could." Evidently they thought it scarcely worth saying
grace for.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The statement made last week in the course of a certain trial
that "as a man grows older he becomes riper" has had a curious
sequel. Orders are pouring in from the Cannibal Isles for
consignments of centenarians.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e216" type="cartoon">
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/61.jpg"/>
                    <p>One advantage about these absolutely remote country
	    cottages is that you can wear out some of the costumes in
	    which you went to the fancy balls this season.</p>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e227" type="poem">
                <head>THE PROFESSIONAL ATTITUDE.</head>
                <p rend="it">(The modern girl, according to a daily paper, is not to be
won by love-making. She prefers a cheerful and amusing
companion.)</p>
                <lg>
                    <l>
                        <hi rend="sc">Dear</hi>, of old I swore devotion</l>
                    <l rend="i2">In the manner knights employed,</l>
                    <l>Wrote epistles with emotion</l>
                    <l rend="i2">(Which I trust have been destroyed);</l>
                    <l>Now at last, a practised lover,</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Boasting conquests not a few,</l>
                    <l>I am told to put a cover</l>
                    <l rend="i2">On my sentiments for you.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>Cupid's chat is out of fashion;</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Sloppy words are never said;</l>
                    <l>Voices once a-throb with passion</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Shake with merriment instead;</l>
                    <l>Poets qualified to tackle</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Lyric metres when inspired</l>
                    <l>Stoop to make the ladies cackle—</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Nothing further is required.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>Doubtless one whose occupation</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Has a dull and solemn trend</l>
                    <l>Might enjoy, as relaxation,</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Jesting with a female friend;</l>
                    <l>But, corrupted by the money</l>
                    <l rend="i2">That my written humours bring,</l>
                    <l>How on earth can I be funny</l>
                    <l rend="i2">For the pleasure of the thing?</l>
                </lg>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e321" type="snippets">
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>
                    <title>The Daily Chronicle</title> on the latest submarine:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>"It will also be equipped with a quick-firing gun, which
disappears when the vessel is submerged."</p>
                </quote>
                <p>This is far the best arrangement; it would never do for it to be
left floating where any passer-by could pick it up.</p>
            </div>
            <pb xml:id="page62" n="pg 62"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e344" type="prose">
                <head>A WARM HALF-HOUR.</head>
                <p>Whatever the papers say, it was the hottest afternoon of the
year. At six-thirty I had just finished dressing after my third
cold bath since lunch, when Celia tapped on the door.</p>
                <p>"I want you to do something for me," she said. "It's a shame to
ask you on a day like this."</p>
                <p>"It <hi rend="it">is</hi> rather a shame," I agreed, "but I can always
refuse."</p>
                <p>"Oh, but you mustn't. We haven't got any ice, and the Thompsons
are coming to dinner. Do you think you could go and buy three
pennyworth? Jane's busy, and I'm busy, and——"</p>
                <p>"And I'm busy," I said, opening and shutting a drawer with great
rapidity.</p>
                <p>"Just three pennyworth," she pleaded. "Nice cool ice. Think of
sliding home on it."</p>
                <p>Well, of course it had to be done. I took my hat and staggered
out. On an ordinary cool day it is about half-a-mile to the
fishmonger; to-day it was about two miles-and-a-quarter. I arrived
exhausted, and with only just strength enough to kneel down and
press my forehead against the large block of ice in the middle of
the shop, round which the lobsters nestled.</p>
                <p>"Here, you mustn't do that," said the fishmonger, waving me
away.</p>
                <p>I got up, slightly refreshed.</p>
                <p>"I want," I said, "some——" and then a thought
occurred to me.</p>
                <p>After all, <hi rend="it">did</hi> fishmongers sell ice? Probably the large
block in front of me was just a trade sign like the coloured
bottles at the chemist's. Suppose I said to a Fellow of the
Pharmaceutical Society, "I want some of that green stuff in the
window," he would only laugh. The tactful thing to do would be to
buy a pint or two of laudanum first, and <hi rend="it">then</hi>, having
established pleasant relations, ask him as a friend to lend me his
green bottle for a bit.</p>
                <p>So I said to the fishmonger, "I want some—some nice
lobsters."</p>
                <p>"How many would you like?"</p>
                <p>"One," I said.</p>
                <p>We selected a nice one between us, and he wrapped a piece of
<title>Daily Mail</title> round it, leaving only the whiskers visible, and
gave it to me. The ice being now broken—I mean the ice being
now—well, you see what I mean—I was now in a position
to ask for some of his ice.</p>
                <p>"I wonder if you could let me have a little piece of your ice,"
I ventured.</p>
                <p>"How much ice do you want?" he said promptly.</p>
                <p>"Sixpennyworth," I said, not knowing a bit how much it would be,
but feeling that Celia's threepennyworth sounded rather mean.</p>
                <p>"Six of ice, Bill," he shouted to an inferior at the back, and
Bill tottered up with a block about the size of one of the lions in
Trafalgar Square. He wrapped a piece of <title>Daily News</title> round it
and gave it to me.</p>
                <p>"Is that all?" asked the fishmonger.</p>
                <p>"That is all," I said faintly; and, with Algernon, the
overwhiskered crustacean, firmly clutched in the right hand and
Stonehenge supported on the palm of the left hand, I retired.</p>
                <p>The flat seemed a very long way away, but having bought twice as
much ice as I wanted, and an entirely unnecessary lobster, I was
not going to waste still more money in taxis. Hot though it was, I
would walk.</p>
                <p>For some miles all went well. Then the ice began to drip through
the paper, and in a little while the underneath part of <title>The
Daily News</title> had disappeared altogether. Tucking the lobster
under my arm I turned the block over, so that it rested on another
part of the paper. Soon that had dissolved too. By the time I had
got half-way our Radical contemporary had been entirely eaten.</p>
                <p>Fortunately <title>The Daily Mail</title> remained. But to get it I had
to disentangle Algernon first, and I had no hand available. There
was only one thing to do. I put the block of ice down on the
pavement, unwrapped the lobster, put the lobster temporarily in my
pocket, spread its <title>Daily Mail</title> out next to the ice, lifted
the ice on to the paper, and—looked up and saw Mrs. Thompson
approaching.</p>
                <p>She was the last person I wanted at that moment. In an hour and
a half she would be dining with us. Algernon would not be dining
with us. If Algernon and Mrs. Thompson were to meet now, would she
not be expecting him to turn up at every course? Think of the
long-drawn-out disappointment for her; not even lobster sauce!</p>
                <p>There was no time to lose. I decided to abandon the ice. Leaving
it on the pavement I turned round and walked hastily back the way I
had come.</p>
                <p>By the time I had shaken off Mrs. Thompson I was almost at the
fishmonger's. That decided me. I would begin all over again, and
would do it properly this time.</p>
                <p>"I want," I said boldly, "threepennyworth of ice."</p>
                <p>"Three of ice, Bill," said the fishmonger, and Bill gave me
quite a respectable segment in <title>The Morning Post</title>.</p>
                <p>"And I want a taxi," I said, and I summoned one.</p>
                <p>We drove quickly home.</p>
                <p>As we neared the flat I suddenly remembered Algernon. I drew him
out of my pocket, red and undraped.</p>
                <p>This would never do. If the porter saw me entering my residence
with a nice lobster, the news would soon get about, and before I
knew where I was I should have a super-tax form sprung on me. I
placed the block of ice on the seat, took off its <title>Morning
Post</title>, and wrapped up Algernon. Then I sprang out, gave the man
a shilling, and got into the lift.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"Bless you," said Celia, "have you got it? How sweet of you!"
And she took my parcel from me. "Now we shall be
able——Why, what's this?"</p>
                <p>I looked at it closely.</p>
                <p>"It's—it's a lobster," I said, "Didn't you say
lobster?"</p>
                <p>"I said ice."</p>
                <p>"Oh," I said, "oh, I didn't understand. I thought you said
lobster."</p>
                <p>"You can't put lobster in cider cup," said Celia severely.</p>
                <p>Of course I quite see that. It was rather a silly mistake of
mine. However, it's pleasant to think that the taxi must have been
nice and cool for the next man.</p>
                <signed>A. A. M.</signed>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e511" type="verse">
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <head>At the tower</head>
                <lg>
                    <l>Upon the old black guns</l>
                    <l rend="i2">The old black raven hops;</l>
                    <l>We gave him bits of buns</l>
                    <l rend="i2">And cakes and acid-drops;</l>
                    <l>He's wise, and his way's devout,</l>
                    <l rend="i2">But he croaks and he flaps his wings</l>
                    <l>(And the flood runs out and the sergeants shout)</l>
                    <l rend="i2">For the first and the last of things;</l>
                    <l>He croaks to Robinson, Brown, and Jones,</l>
                    <l>The song of the ravens, "<title>Dead Men's Bones!</title>"</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>For into the lifting dark</l>
                    <l rend="i2">And a drizzle of clearing rain,</l>
                    <l>His sire flapped out of the Ark</l>
                    <l rend="i2">And never came back again;</l>
                    <l>So I always fancy that,</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Ere the frail lost blue showed thin,</l>
                    <l>Alone he sat upon Ararat</l>
                    <l rend="i2">To see a new world in,</l>
                    <l>And yelped to the void from a cairn of stones</l>
                    <l>The song of the ravens, "<title>Dead Men's Bones!</title>"</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>When the last of mankind lie slain</l>
                    <l rend="i2">On Armageddon's field,</l>
                    <l>When the last red west has ta'en</l>
                    <l rend="i2">The last day's flaming shield,</l>
                    <l>There shall sit when the shadows run</l>
                    <l rend="i2">(D'you doubt, good Sirs, d'you doubt?)</l>
                    <l>His last rogue son on an empty gun</l>
                    <l rend="i2">To see an old world out;</l>
                    <l>And he'll croak (as to Robinson, Brown and Jones)</l>
                    <l>The song of the ravens, "<title>Dead Men's Bones!</title>"</l>
                </lg>
            </div>
            <pb xml:id="page63" n="pg 63"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e632" type="cartoon">
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/63.jpg"/>
                    <figDesc>The Liberal Cave-men</figDesc>
                    <head>THE LIBERAL CAVE-MEN;</head>
                    <head>OR, A HOLT FROM THE BLUE.</head>
                    <p>Harassed Chancellor. "It's not so much for my feet that I mind —
they're hardened against this kind of thing; but I do hate rocks on
my head."</p>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <pb xml:id="page65" n="pg 65"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e654" type="cartoon">
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/65.jpg"/>
                    <head>The March Of Civilisation In Ireland.</head>
                    <p>Tim. "Well, Patsy, are ye after building an addition to yer
house?</p>
                    <p>Patsy. "Sure and the hins likes a place to thimsilves."</p>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e673" type="verse">
                <head>TEMPERING THE WIND;
or, The Indemnification of
Antonio.</head>
                <p rend="center">[<title>In the Census returns for 1911, recently
published, organ-grinders are no longer counted as
musicians.</title>]</p>
                <lg>
                    <l>When buffets from the frowning Fates demoralise,</l>
                    <l rend="i2">And all the spirit yearns for honeyed death;</l>
                    <l>When limply on the harper's brow the laurel lies</l>
                    <l rend="i2">And something in his bosom deeply saith,</l>
                    <l>"N.G. I give it up! Behold! misshapen is</l>
                    <l rend="i2">The bowler that surmounts my glorious mane;</l>
                    <l>Life is all kicks without the boon of halfpennies;</l>
                    <l rend="i6">The rates are here again;"——</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>'Tis sweet, 'tis very sweet to gaze at Helicon</l>
                    <l rend="i2">And think, "On me the sacred fire has dropped,</l>
                    <l>The lute, at any rate, still hangs, a relic, on</l>
                    <l rend="i2">This diaphragm, although the shirt is popped;"</l>
                    <l>And so it was, I ween, with your position,</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Ansonia's sunny child, from house to house</l>
                    <l>Aye wandering: still you ranked as a musician,</l>
                    <l rend="i6">The same as Dr. <name rend="sc">Strauss</name>.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>People were rude to you: they said, "Be gibbetted!"</l>
                    <l rend="i2">In many a ruthless road your cheek grew wan</l>
                    <l>Where hawkers and street-music were prohibited</l>
                    <l rend="i2">And stout policemen urged you to get on;</l>
                    <l>Yet still that stubborn heart, the heart of <name rend="sc">Cato's</name> kin,</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Stayed you, and still the gleam that cannot die,</l>
                    <l>Though every now and then an old potato skin</l>
                    <l rend="i6">Did welt you in the eye.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>Tattered and soiled, an exile and an alien,</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Somehow you touched the Cockney nymphs with awe;</l>
                    <l>You lit the cold clay statue, like Pygmalion,</l>
                    <l rend="i2">To blood-red raptures; you were sib to
	       <name rend="sc">Shaw</name>;</l>
                    <l>Others might hale the town in cushioned chariots</l>
                    <l rend="i2">To see them dance or daub, to hear them strum;</l>
                    <l>You also had your moments: jigging Harriets</l>
                    <l rend="i6">Joyed in your simian chum.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>And how shall these things change? Shall childish galleries</l>
                    <l rend="i2">That deemed you once Apollo's minister,</l>
                    <l>Say, "Garn, old monkey!" Shall colossal salaries</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Reward the Muse and not the dulcimer?</l>
                    <l>Not gleaming eyeballs, not the soul illuminate?</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Shall old faiths falter and Antonio's heart</l>
                    <l>Sicken the while he churns, and chilly ruminate,</l>
                    <l rend="i6">"This is no longer Art"?</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>So be it then. But lest the slight unparalleled</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Shall cause extinction of a breed so stout,</l>
                    <l>And scatter to the winds what tags his barrel held</l>
                    <l rend="i2">And doom him to go under and get out;</l>
                    <l>Lest he despair and pine from this now streak of ills,</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Not ranked with virtuosi's shining shapes,</l>
                    <l>Let him he classed anew amongst Pithekophils,</l>
                    <l rend="i6">An amateur of Apes.</l>
                </lg>
                <signed>
                    <name rend="sc">Evoe.</name>
                </signed>
            </div>
            <pb xml:id="page66" n="pg 66"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e869" type="prose">
                <head>PAYMENT IN KIND.</head>
                <p>I argued that one and threepence was too much to pay for the
delivery of a telegram which had only cost sixpence itself; I also
argued that one and threepence was too little for a wealthy
institution like the G.P.O. to worry about, but the messenger
wouldn't reduce the price. I had had my telegram, said he, and I
must pay for it. I offered to give him the telegram back, but he
guessed it was only from Carr and wasn't having any. It was my
money he wanted and that, unhappily, was some miles away in a
bank.</p>
                <p>For reasons best known to myself, and not too clearly
appreciated even in that quarter, I am always full of petty cash at
the beginning of the month and out of it at the end. My wife never
draws any at all, knowing it is much safer where it is, and as for
Albert, our only son, he takes no interest in the stuff. When we,
in moments of self-denial, slip a coin into the slit of his
money-box, he is merely bored, being as yet unable to unlock the
box and get the coin out again, owing to ignorance of the
whereabouts of the key. I explained all this to the telegraph boy,
but his heart didn't soften; so, still parleying with him in the
porch, I sent the maid to my wife to see what she could do to ease
the financial position.</p>
                <p>The maid returned with a shilling, which was my wife's limit,
and this I tendered to the boy, explaining to him the theory of
discount for net cash. But he was one of those small and obstinate
creatures who won't learn, so I sent him round to the back premises
to get some tea, while I retired to the front to do some thinking.
It was at this moment that Albert chose, imprudently, to make an
important announcement from the top of the stairs with regard to a
first tooth, which he had lost by extraction the day before but had
not yet been able to forget. His idea was that he should come down
and inspect it once more; but I paid no heed to this. His mention
of the matter suggested, when I came to think of it, a solution of
my difficulty with the telegraph boy.</p>
                <p>Later, I asked my wife to step into my study and to shut the
door behind her. "This has become a serious matter," said I; "nay,
it threatens to be a grave scandal. You remember Albert's
tooth?"</p>
                <p>She did. These things are not easily forgotten. "I wish," I
pursued, "to interview Albert's nurse as to it," and I rang the
bell sternly.</p>
                <p>"She hasn't got it," said my wife; "we have," and she took from
the mantelpiece a small packet tied up with pink ribbon.</p>
                <p>I explained that it wasn't the child's molar but the child's
funds that I was concerned with. "You will recollect that I
compensated him for the loss of it with a shilling. It makes it all
the more poignant that it was my last shilling. I put it into his
money-box, the key of which is accessible to miscreants. That
shilling is gone!"</p>
                <p>My wife smiled. "How did you find out?" she asked.</p>
                <p>"I had reason to be looking in the box," I said airily, "and
happened by chance to notice that the shilling had been
stolen."</p>
                <p>"You mean," said she, "that you were proposing to steal it
yourself?"</p>
                <p>I disregarded the question. "I never did trust that nurse," said
I. "But to steal the treasured capital of a defenceless
infant!"</p>
                <p>"I am the thief," said my wife, "and you are the receiver.
Whether or not the telegraph-boy will be jointly charged with us is
for the police and Albert to decide between them."</p>
                <p>At this moment the nurse entered and asked what we required of
her. My wife was confused, but not so I. I told nurse we required
nothing of her but much of Albert. Would she ask him to step
downstairs?</p>
                <p>We assembled in the porch, my wife, Albert, the nurse, and the
telegraph boy. I took the chair.</p>
                <p>"Ladies and gentlemen," said I, "I have a proposal to lay before
the meeting with a view to adjusting the acute crisis. Let me
remind you of the facts:—The gentleman on my right," and I
indicated Albert, whose attention wandered a little, "was recently
possessed of a tooth, two parents, and a godfather of the name of
Carr. The tooth, as teeth will, had to be removed; the parents, as
parents may, advanced a shilling upon it; and the godfather, as
godfathers needn't, telegraphed to say he was coming forthwith to
the <title>locus in quo</title>. Things were so when Mr. (I didn't catch
your name, Sir," and I turned to the telegraph boy) "threatened to
liquidate us unless his debt was satisfied. Business is, as he very
properly remarked, business. "Now for my suggestion: Albert," and I
turned to him again, "will have, the telegram, which, being from
<hi rend="it">his</hi> godfather, is rightly his. He will, however, take it
subject to encumbrances, of which, I understand, he has already
discharged all but threepence. Happily his parents are willing to
withdraw their first charge on his personal assets, and I have much
satisfaction, Sir"—I bowed to the telegraph boy—"in
presenting you with the goods, which were as recently as yesterday
valued at no less than a shilling, and in asking you to keep the
balance as a mark of our unshaken affection and esteem."</p>
                <p>And I handed him Albert's tooth.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e930" type="cartoon">
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/66.jpg"/>
                    <head>More Sacrifices To Speed.</head>
                    <head>The "Minim kid-fit."</head>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e945" type="snippets">
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>"Accused, who gave the name of Janet Arthur, quoted Scott's 'Wha
Hae' and other works."—<title>Lincolnshire Echo.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>Such as the Wha-Haeverley Novels.</p>
            </div>
            <pb xml:id="page67" n="pg 67"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e964" type="cartoon">
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/67.jpg"/>
                    <head>The World's Workers.</head>
                    <p>Little Girl. "Please, Mrs. Murphy, Muvver says, if it's
	    fine to-morrer, will you go beggin' with 'er?"</p>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e980" type="prose">
                <head>THE "THORNS OF PRAISE."<lb/> "HIS PURPLEST SIN."</head>
                <p rend="center">By <name rend="sc">Vernon Blathers</name> (Jack
Short, 6/-).</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Weekly Scotsman.</title> "... vivacious narrative ..."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Strathpeffer Courant.</title> "Replete with up-to-date
sentiment ... knowledge of the <title>beau monde</title> ... racy, but
never transcending the bounds of decorum."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Buttevant Despatch.</title> "Passages which the author of
'The Rosary' might be proud to have written ... high ideals ...
love interest well sustained ... careful punctuation."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Nether Wallop News.</title> "Mr. Blathers is a benefactor ...
reminds us of <name rend="sc">T. P. O'Connor</name> ... luscious
word-painting ... well-chosen epithets."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Machrihamish Mirror.</title> "Stylish writing ... Mr.
Blathers is evidently a <title>persona grata</title> in the most
<title>recherché</title> circles."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chowbent Eagle.</title> "Edifying, yet entertaining ...
faithful portraiture, but ... not in the least like <name rend="sc">Zola</name> ... undoubtedly readable."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Criccieth Sentinel.</title> "... inside knowledge of Mayfair
... redolent of humanity at its best ... fluid and flexible style
... suitable for a country congregation."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Kilmarnock News.</title> "... cannot remember any book which
... better than this is."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Pilworth Post.</title> "... redundant with wit ..."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Peebles Advertiser.</title> "Mr. Blathers ... go far."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Worcester Academy.</title> "Mr. Blathers is to be most
heartily congratulated."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The N. Wales Dictator.</title> "... masterly delineation of the
Smart Set."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Peak News.</title> "... witty to excess."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Bermondsey Examiner.</title> "Few books so well worth re- and
re-reading."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Poplar Courier.</title> "A fine novel."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Sligo Spectator.</title> "... marked ability ..."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Rutland Observer.</title> "... meritorious ..."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Winchester Tribune.</title> "... feast of entertainment. Mr.
Blathers' next should be ... awaited with impatience."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Isle of Wight Critic.</title> "... clever novel ..."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Cader-Idris Athenæum.</title> "... psychology ...
humour ... passion."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Bucklaw Post.</title> "... emotional depths ..."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Sunday Deliverer.</title> "... remarkable book ..."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Simla Gazette.</title> "... verdict ... profoundly
enthralling work of fiction."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Geelong Times.</title> "... better than
	 ... <name rend="sc">George Eliot.</name>"</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Cork Pall Mall.</title> "A brilliant first effort."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Hackney Examiner.</title> "... well written ..."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Tooting Express.</title> "... amusing ..."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Monthly Citizen.</title> "The characters have life and
movement."</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1183" type="snippets">
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>"Before lunch each section held its annual meeting in private,
and at two o'clock the company sat down to a substantial and very
acceptable repast, which was greatly relished by the visitors.
After being operated upon by a photographer the party split."</p>
                    <p rend="i4">
                        <title>Ledbury Guardian.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>We were rather afraid they had overdone it.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>From a photographic catalogue:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>"This is a most complete little Projector.... It is quite
self-contained and will protect a thirty-inch picture anywhere at a
moment's notice."</p>
                </quote>
                <p>It should be installed at the Royal Academy without delay.</p>
            </div>
            <pb xml:id="page68" n="pg 68"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e1221" type="prose">
                <head>BLANCHE'S LETTERS.<lb/>
            Some Outstanding Features.         </head>
                <p rend="right">
                    <hi>Park Lane.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">Dearest Daphne</name>,—The outstanding
features of the season have certainly been the Friendship
Fête, the Kamtchatkan Scriptural opera-ballet, "<title>Noé
s'embarque sur l'Arche</title>," and the Cloak!</p>
                <p>The Friendship Fête, to celebrate our not having had any
scraps with any foreign country for some little time, was simply
immense. There were descriptive tableaux and groups, and the one
undertaken by your Blanche—swords being turned into
ploughshares and the figure of Peace standing in the middle, with
Bellona crouching at her feet—was said to be an easy winner.
I was Peace, of course, in chiffon draperies, with my hair down. I
hadn't the faintest notion what sort of thing a ploughshare was,
but I'd clever people to help me, and so it was all right. But oh,
my best one! the difficulty I had in getting a Bellona! They all
wanted to be Peace, and some of them were so absolutely horrid
about it that I couldn't help telling them they were only showing
how <hi rend="it">fit</hi> they were to be Bellona! (I will tell <hi rend="it">you</hi> in
confidence that I believe one of them was responsible for some of
my swords and ploughshares falling down with an immensely odious
crash just as the opening ceremony was going on.) Norty was given
the group of all nations, called, "All Men are Brothers," and he
said on the whole it was rather a rotten job; there was a lot of
friction, and at one time he was afraid things might get almost to
<hi rend="it">diplomatic</hi> lengths; however, it all went smoothly at last.
Still he told me <title>à l'oreille</title> that he was glad it was
well over, as two or three Friendship Fêtes would be enough
to shake the peace of Europe to its foundations!</p>
                <p>But nothing matters much while one can go and see the wonderful,
<hi rend="it">wonderful</hi> Kamtchatkans in "<title>Noé s'embarque sur
l'Arche</title>"—a feast of beauty—a riot of colour—a
mass of inner meanings. Who am I, dearest, that I should try to
word-paint it? Being an opera-ballet, there are two Noahs, a
singing one and a dancing one. While that glorious Golliookin, the
singing Noah, is giving the marvellous Flood Music in a gallery
over the stage, our dear wonderful Ternitenky, the dancing Noah, is
going into the Ark in a series of the most delicious <title>pas
seuls</title>. Then his dance of Astonishment and Alarm as he sees the
waters rising—and afterwards his dance of Joy and
Thankfulness at finding himself quite dry! The <title>Pas de Six</title> of
Noah's Sons and their Wives! And the <hi rend="it">ensemble</hi> dancing of the
Animals! My dearest, you positively must and shall leave your
solitudes and come and see the Kamtchatkans in Scriptural
opera-ballet! Only second to <title>Noé</title> is <title>La Femme de
Lot</title>, with dear Sarkavina, in clouds of white, doing a
sensational whirling dance as she turns into the Pillar, while that
amazing soprano, Scriemalona, sings the mysterious Salt Music.
Bishops quite <hi rend="it">swarm</hi> at these performances. They say they
consider it their <hi rend="it">duty</hi> to go, and that they never
<hi rend="it">really</hi> understood the true character of <name rend="sc">Noah</name> till they saw Ternitenky's beautiful flying leap
into the Ark, or quite grasped the personality of <name rend="sc">Lot's</name> Wife before seeing Sarkavina's Pillar-of-Salt
dance.</p>
                <p>On <title>Noé</title> and <title>Lot</title> nights it's correct to carry
a little darling Old Testament, bound in velvet or satin to match
or contrast with one's toilette, and generally with jewels on the
cover; and the Old Testament is quite often mentioned at dinner
just now, people pretending they've been reading it, and so on.
<title>À propos</title>, Mrs. Golding-Newman, one of the latest
climbers, excused herself for being late at dinner somewhere the
other night by saying, "I was reading Deuteronomy and didn't notice
how the time was going." The Bullyon-Boundermere woman was present
and, determined to trump her rival's trick, chipped in with, "Oh,
<title>isn't</title> Deuteronomy <hi rend="it">charming</hi>? But I think of <hi rend="it">all</hi>
the books of the Old Testament my favourite is In Memoriam!"</p>
                <p>The Cloak, my Daphne, which is one of the most interesting
arrivals in town this summer, is, <title>à mon avis</title>,
something quite <hi rend="it">more</hi> than a garment—it is a great big
test of all that a woman most prides herself on! You may see a
thousand women with cloaks on, but how many will be <title>really
wearing</title> them! As one criticised the cloaks and their wearers in
the Enclosure at Aswood one couldn't help murmuring with a small
sigh, "Who is sufficient for these things!" People who have the
cloak fastened on <title>in just any way</title>, my dear, are simply
begging the question; in its true inwardness, in its loftiest
development, the cloak should be a separate creation, kept in its
place only by the grace and knack of its wearer. There should be
<hi rend="it">character</hi> about it, a fascinating droop, a sweat crookedness
that can only happen when it is worn with the art that—you
know the rest.</p>
                <p>Shall I confide to you my little secret, dearest? Would you know
why it is given to your Blanche to be easily best of the few women
who do really <hi rend="it">wear</hi> the cloak? When I'm ready, all but nay
cloak, I run away from Yvonne down the stairs; she follows,
carrying the cloak, and when she's beginning to overtake me she
throws the cloak and I catch it on my shoulders. Result—I'm
the envy and despair of all my best beloved enemies!</p>
                <p>People have been trying to find new places to wear their
watches. A small watch on the toe of each shoe (plain for day wear,
jewelled for the evening) had quite a little vogue, though as
watches they were no good, for no one could see the time by them.
Then little teeny watches on the tips of glove-fingers were liked a
little. But the latest development is that Time is
<title>démodé</title>, and anyone mentioning hours and
half-hours is stamped as an outside person.</p>
                <p>Isn't this a <hi rend="it">fragrant</hi> idea about our not being to blame
for anything we do, because it's all owing to the <hi rend="it">colours</hi> we
live with? Everybody's <hi rend="it">charmed</hi> about it. Instead of going to
<hi rend="it">lawyers</hi> when things run off the rails a little, if one just
called in a <title>colour-expert</title> all sorts of horrors might be
avoided, for he would prove that people are like that owing to the
colours of their curtains and upholsteries, and aren't to blame
themselves, poor, dears, the very least little bit! The Thistledown
<title>ménage</title>, for instance. For ages it's been tottery,
because Thistledown never understood Fluffy, and Fluffy, poor
little thing, seemed to understand everybody except Thistledown.
We've all been so sorry for her, for several times he's been on the
point of dragging things into public. And now it turns out that
nothing is Fluffy's fault and that, if she hadn't always had her
own, own room done in pinky-bluey shades, she might have been quite
a serious domestic character! T. says, if that's so, she'd better
have her own, own room done in some other colour, but Fluffy says,
No, she likes pinky-bluey shades, only he must remember, when he's
inclined to be hard on her, that the pinky-blueys are to blame and
not herself.</p>
                <p>Then there's old Lady Humguffin, easily the most miserly old
dear who ever wore a transformation (she even has a taxi-meter
thing in her own motors and anyone driving with her is expected to
pay what it registers!). Colour-experts say that if it weren't for
the frightfully dull dusty purple in which all her rooms are
furnished she might part quite freely!</p>
                <p>So there it is, my dear! People say there's been no such
important discovery since Gallienus—that fearful old man, you
know, who said something moved when everyone else said it didn't.
(I hardly know <hi rend="it">how</hi> I know these things. Please, please don't
think I'm becoming a <title>femme savante</title>!).</p>
                <p>Ever
thine,<name rend="sc">Blanche</name>.</p>
            </div>
            <pb xml:id="page69" n="pg 69"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e1395" type="prose">
                <head>TOO MUCH CHAMPIONSHIP.</head>
                <p>Once life was an easy thing.</p>
                <p>Yorkshire or Surrey or Kent were cricket champions. <name rend="sc">Ranji</name> or W. G. headed the batting averages;
<name rend="sc">Rhodes</name> or <name rend="sc">Richardson</name> the bowling. The office boy who knew these
details plus the Boat Race winner and the English Cup-holders could
keep his end up in conversation. He even found time to do a little
work.</p>
                <p>But now! That poor brain must know that McGinty of Fulham
fetched £1,000 when put up for auction, that the front line
of Blackburn Rovers represents an expense of £11,321
13<title>s.</title> 4<title>d.</title>, and that Chelsea have played before 71,935
spectators. He must know the champions of the First, Second,
Southern, Midland, and Scottish Leagues, and the teams that gained
promotion.</p>
                <p>Then there is cricket—all worked out to "those damned
dots," as Lord <name rend="sc">Randolph</name> said in an inspired
moment. Think of the strain of remembering that Middlesex stands at
78.66 and Surrey at 72.94. And the sporting papers are publishing
lists of catches made; and lists of catches missed are sure to
follow. Think of it—you may have to name the Champion
Butterfingers in 1915!</p>
                <p>Come to tennis. You must know the names of the Australian
Terror, the New Zealand Cyclone, the American Whirlwind. You must
at a glance be able to pronounce on the nationality of Mavrogordato
or Froitzheim. You have the strain of proving that the victory of a
New Zealander over a German proves the vitality of the dear old
country.</p>
                <p>Or boxing. How can an ordinary mind retain the names of all the
White Hopes or Black Despairs. At any moment some Terrible Magyar
may wrest the bantam championship from us. You must learn to
distinguish between <name rend="sc">Wells</name>, the
reconstructor of the universe, and Knock-out <name rend="sc">Wells</name>. You must be acquainted with the doings and
prospects of Dreadnought Brown and Mulekick Jones. You must know
the F. E. Smithian repartees of <name rend="sc">Jack
Johnson</name>.</p>
                <p>Let us talk of golf. No, on second thoughts, let us notably
refrain from talking about golf. Only if you don't know who
defeated <name rend="sc">Travers</name> (<hi rend="it">plus</hi> lumbago) and
who eclipsed America's Bright Boy, you must hide your head in
shame.</p>
                <p>We come to rowing. Once one could stay, "Ah, Leander," and with
an easy shrug of the shoulders pass from the subject. But when
international issues are involved, and the win of a Canadian or
American or German crew may cause <title>The Daily Mail</title> to declare
(for the hundredth time) that England is played out, a man simply
has to keep abreast of the results.</p>
                <p>There are a score of other things. Name for me, if you can, the
Great American Four, the hydro-aeroplane champion, the M.P.
champion pigeon-flyer, and the motor-bike hill-climbing
champion.</p>
                <p>And the Olympic games are coming! Who are England's hopes in the
discus-throwing and the fancy diving? What Britisher must we rely
on in the javelin hop-skip-and-jump?</p>
                <p>Your brain reels at the prospect. We must decide to ignore all
future championships. We must decline to be aggravated if a
Japanese Badminton champion appears. We must cease to be interested
if Britain's Hope beats the Horrible Peruvian at Tiddly-winks.</p>
                <p>There are three admirable reasons for this.</p>
                <p>The first is that we must play some games ourselves.</p>
                <p>The second, that, unless a check be put to championships, the
Parliamentary news will be crowded out of the papers and we shall
find ourselves in an unnatural state of peace and goodwill.</p>
                <p>The third, which one puts forward with diffidence, is that
somebody, somewhere, somehow, sometime must do a little work.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1483" type="cartoon">
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/69.jpg"/>
                    <p>Wife (with some sadness). "Ah, well, Henry, I suppose
	    it's a bit too late for you to think of that now."</p>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <pb xml:id="page70" n="pg 70"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e1496" type="verse">
                <head rend="gothic">To the Memory <lb/> of <lb/> Joseph Chamberlain</head>
                <head rend="sc">Born 1836.  Died July 2nd, 1914.</head>
                <lg>
                    <l>Ere warmth of Spring had stirred the wintry lands—</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Spring that for him had no renewing breath—</l>
                    <l>He went apart to wait with folded hands</l>
                    <l rend="i6">The lingering feet of Death.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>Long had he laid his burnished armour by,</l>
                    <l rend="i2">But still we flew his banner for a sign,</l>
                    <l>Still felt his spirit like a rallying-cry</l>
                    <l rend="i4">Hearten the fighting line.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>But he—ah, none could know the heavy strain,</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Patiently to accept the watcher's part</l>
                    <l>While yet no weakness sapped the virile brain</l>
                    <l rend="i6">Nor dulled the eager heart.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>He should have died with all his harness on,</l>
                    <l rend="i2">As those the Valkyr bore from out the fight,</l>
                    <l>In ringing mail that still unrusted shone,</l>
                    <l rend="i4">Up to Valhalla's height.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>Yet solace flowed from that surcease of strife:</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Love found occasion in his need of care,</l>
                    <l>And time was ours to prove how dear the life</l>
                    <l rend="i6">An Empire ill could spare.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>And generous foes confessed the magic spell</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Of greatness gone, that left the common store</l>
                    <l>Poor by his loss who loved his party well,</l>
                    <l rend="i6">But loved his country more.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>And ancient rivalries seemed very small</l>
                    <l rend="i2">Beside that courage constant to the end;</l>
                    <l>And even Death, last enemy of all,</l>
                    <l rend="i6">Came to him like a friend.</l>
                </lg>
                <signed>O. S.</signed>
            </div>
            <pb xml:id="page71" n="pg 71"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e1621" type="cartoon">
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/71.jpg"/>
                    <head>JOSEPH CHAMBERLAIN.</head>
                    <head>July 2nd, 1914.</head>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <pb xml:id="page73" n="pg 73"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e1637" type="report">
                <head>ESSENCE OF PARLIAMENT.</head>
                <head rend="sc">(Extracted from the Diary of Toby,
M.P.)</head>
                <p>
                    <hi>House of Commons, Monday, July 6.</hi>—All heads were
bared when the <name rend="sc">Prime Minister</name> rose to move
adjournment of <name rend="sc">House</name> in sign of sorrow at
the passing way of a great Parliament man. To vast majority of
present House <name rend="sc">Joseph Chamberlain</name> is a
tradition. His personal presence, its commanding force, is varied
and invariable attraction are unknown. Since his final re-election
by faithful Birmingham, where, like the Shunamite woman, he dwelt
among his own people loving and loved, he only once entered the
House.</p>
                <p>It was a tragic scene, perhaps happily witnessed by few.
Appointed business of sitting concluded and Members departed, a
figure that once commanded attention of a listening Senate slowly
entered from behind the <name rend="sc">Speaker's</name> chair. It
was the senior Member for Birmingham come to take the oath. The
action was indicative of his thoroughness and loyalty. No longer
were oaths, rolls of Parliament and seats on either Front Bench
matters of concern to him. His manifold task was done. His
brilliant course was run. But, until he took the oath and signed
the roll, he was not <title>de jure</title> a Member of the House of
Commons, and his vote might not be available by the Whips for a
pair on a critical division.</p>
                <p>Accordingly here he was, moving haltingly with the aid of a
stick, supported by the strong arm of the son whose maiden speech
his old chief <name rend="sc">Gladstone</name> years ago welcomed
as "dear and refreshing to a father's heart." He took the oath and
signed the roll—an historic page in a unique volume. With
dimmed eyes he glanced round the familiar scene of hard fights and
great triumphs, and went forth never to return.</p>
                <p>To-day he lived again in speeches delivered by the <name rend="sc">Prime Minister</name>, by the <name rend="sc">Leader of the Opposition</name>, and by the Cabinet
         colleague and leader to whom he was loyal to the last. The
         practice of delivering set eulogies to the memory of the
         departed great is the most difficult that falls to the lot of
         a Leader on either side of House of Commons. In some hands it
         has uncontrollable tendency to the artificiality and
         insipidity of funeral baked meats. <name rend="sc">Disraeli</name> was a failure on such occasions;
         <name rend="sc">Gladstone</name> at his best. <name rend="sc">Prince Arthur</name>, usually supreme, did not
         to-day reach his accustomed lofty level.</p>
                <p>In fineness of tone and exquisite felicity of phrasing,
<name rend="sc">Asquith</name> excelled himself. The first time
the House of Commons caught a glimpse of profound depths of a
nature habitually masked by impassive manner and curt speech was
when he talked to it in broken voice about <name rend="sc">Campbell-Bannerman</name>, just dead. Speaking this afternoon
about one with whom, as he said, he "had exchanged many blows," he
was even more impressive, not less by reason of the eloquence of
his speech than by its simplicity and sincerity.</p>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/73-1.jpg"/>
                    <head>TIM BUONAPARTE.</head>
                </figure>
                <p>
                    <title>Business done.</title>—In the House of Lords <title>le
brave</title>
                    <name rend="sc">Willoughby de Broke</name> was, if the
phrase be Parliamentary, broken in the Division Lobby. Insisting on
fighting the Home Rule Amending Bill to the last, he found himself
supported by ten peers, a Liberal Ministry having for an important
measure the majority, unparalleled in modern times, of 263.</p>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/73-2.jpg"/>
                    <p>"Prospective first Speaker of a modern Irish
	    Parliament."</p>
                    <head>(<name rend="sc">Mr. Swift MacNeill</name>)</head>
                </figure>
                <p>When figures were announced <name rend="sc">Lord Crewe</name>,
reminiscent of the farmer smacking his lips over a liqueur glass of
old brandy, remarked to <name rend="sc">Viscount Morley</name>, "I
should like some more of that in a moog."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Tuesday.</title>—Interesting episode preceded main business
of sitting. Sort of rehearsal of meeting of Parliament on College
Green. Opened by <name rend="sc">Sheehan</name> rising from Bench
partially filled by O'Brienites to move issue of new writ for North
Galway. Had it been an English borough nothing particular would
have happened. Writ would have been ordered as matter of course,
and there an end on't.</p>
                <p>Things different on College Green. When <name rend="sc">Sheehan</name> sat down, up gat <name rend="sc">Captain
Donelan</name> from Redmondite camp, which when moved to Dublin will,
by reason of numerical majority, be analogous to Ministerialists at
Westminister. <name rend="sc">Donelan</name> remarked that in his
capacity as Nationalist Whip he intended to move issue of writ next
Monday. This fully explained why <name rend="sc">O'Brien's</name>
young man moved it to-day.  Otherwise cause of quarrel obscure. What
they fought each other for dense mind of Saxon could not make out.</p>
                <p>Ambiguity partly due to <name rend="sc">Donelan</name>. Lacking
the volubility common to his countrymen he had prepared heads of
his speech jotted down on piece of notepaper. This so intricately
folded that sequence of remarks occasionally suffered. Situation
further complicated by accidental turning over of notes upside
down. House grateful when presently <name rend="sc">Tim
Healy</name> interposed. He being past-master of lucid statement,
we should now know all about circumstances which apparently, to the
temporary shouldering aside of Ulster, rocked Ireland to its
centre.</p>
                <p>Unfortunately <name rend="sc">Tim</name> was embarrassed by
attempt to assume a novel oratorical attitude. Usually he addresses
House with studied carelessness of hands lightly clasped behind his
back. Presumably in consideration of supreme national importance of
the question whether <name rend="sc">Sheehan</name> should move
issue of writ to-day or <name rend="sc">Donelan</name> on Monday,
he essayed a new attitude. It recalled <name rend="sc">Napoleon</name> at Fontainebleau folding his arms majestically
as he bade farewell to remnant of the Old Guard.</p>
                <p>Attempt, several times repeated, proved a failure. Somehow or
other <name rend="sc">Tim's</name> arms would not adjust
themselves <pb xml:id="page74" n="pg 74"/> to novel circumstances, and fell back
into the old <title>laissez-faire</title> position. Speech repeatedly
interrupted on points of order by compatriots on back benches. What
was clear was that some one had filed a petition in bankruptcy.
Identity of delinquent not so clear.</p>
                <p>However, as a foretaste of debate in Home Rule Parliament,
proceedings interesting and instructive. Disposed of slanderous
suggestions of disorder. Never, or hardly ever, was a more decorous
debate. To it <name rend="sc">Swift MacNeill</name>, prospective
first Speaker of a modern Irish Parliament, lent the dignity and
authority of his patronage. Pretty to see him, as debate went
forward, glancing aside at his wigged-and-gowned brother in the
Chair, as who should say, "What do you think of this, Sir?"</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Business done.</title>—With assistance of Ministerial
forces, O'Brienite motion for issue of writ for Galway defeated by
Redmondite amendment to adjourn debate. <name rend="sc">William
O'Brien</name> took swift revenge. House dividing on <name rend="sc">Premier's</name> motion allotting time for remaining stages of
Budget Bill, he led his little flock into Opposition Lobby,
assisting to reduce Ministerial majority to figure of 23. In this
labour of love he found himself assisted by abstention of two
groups of Ministerialists, one objecting to procedure on Finance
Bill, the other thirsting for blood of the Ulster gun-runners.</p>
                <p>If <name rend="sc">Premier</name> still hesitates about Autumn
Session this incident should help him to make up his mind. The
Government will be safer with its Members on the moors or the golf
links than daily running the gauntlet at Westminster.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>House of Lords, Thursday.</title>—When noble lords take
their legislative business seriously in hand they show the Commons
a better way. Their dealing with the Amending Bill has been a model
of businesslike procedure. Speeches uniformly brief because kept
strictly to the point. Amendments carefully considered in council
and moved from Front Opposition Bench were carried by large
majorities.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Business done.</title>—Home Rule Amending Bill turned
inside out in two sittings. Own father wouldn't know it.
<name rend="sc">Sark</name> sums up situation by paraphrase of
historic saying. "They have," he remarks, "made a new Bill and call
it Peace."</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/74.jpg"/>
                    <head>AN EX-VICEREGAL BAG.</head>
                    <p>(<name rend="sc">Earl Curzon</name>
                    </p>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1861" type="prose">
                <head>ELECTION INTELLIGENCE.<lb/>
Great American Invasion.        </head>
                <p>The prospects of the forthcoming campaign in the East
Worcestershire Division have been greatly brightened by the
decision of the well-known sportsman, Mr. Otis Q. Janaway, to stand
as an Independent Candidate with the express purpose of speeding-up
the British Legislature. Mr. Janaway, who graduated in sociology at
the University of Pensacola, and has recently been naturalised as a
British subject, has brought with him a team of baseball players,
four white and four coloured prize-fighters, and a chorus of
variety artistes who will appear and sing at all his meetings. He
is a powerful speaker with a great fund of anecdote, and his
programme includes Compulsory Phonetic Spelling, the establishment
of Christian Science, Electrocution, and the introduction of
College Yells in Parliament. If her husband is elected, Mrs.
Janaway has announced her intention of embracing the Speaker at the
earliest opportunity.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Professor Thaddeus Mulhooly, who was until recently President of
the University of Tuskahoma, has taken up his residence at
Ballybunnion with a view to qualifying as Parliamentary Candidate
for North Kerry. Professor Mulhooly, whose grandparents resided at
Tralee, has made a very favourable impression by the filial
affection shown in his election war-cry, which runs, "Tralee,
Trala, Tara Tarara, Tzing Boum Oshkosh." His platform is that of a
Pan-Celtic Vegetarian, and he has secured the influential support
of Mr. <name rend="sc">Upton Sinclair</name>, who is acting as his
election agent, and who publicly embraced him at a meeting at
Dingle last week.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>General Amos Cadwalader Stunt, the well-known Colorado mining
magnate, who recently purchased the Isle of Rum, has announced his
intention of contesting the Elgin Burghs in the Liquid Paraffin
interest. At a political meeting at Lossiemouth last week he held
the attention of a crowded audience for upwards of an hour, during
which his bodyguard serenaded him with mouth-organs and banjos, the
interruptions of hecklers having been effectually discounted by a
liberal distribution of chewing gum. At the close of this great
effort General Stunt was publicly embraced by his wife's mother,
Mrs. Titania Flagler.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The by-election campaign at Hanley opened auspiciously on
Thursday with a demonstration in favour of Mr. Cyrus P. Slocum, the
eminent Pittsburg safety razor magnate, who has been selected by
the Association of American Manufacturers in England to represent
their interests at Westminster. Before Mr. Slocum rose the audience
sang "My Country, 'tis of Thee" continuously for forty-five minutes
and waved the Stars and Stripes for fully twenty minutes longer.
Finally, the popular candidate was carried shoulder-high from the
platform to his motor and smothered with kisses from his
compatriots, the vast assemblage dispersing to the jocund strains
of "John Brown's Body."</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Great satisfaction is felt in American golfing circles at the
announcement that Mr. Olonzo Jaggers has decided to contest the
Tantallon Division of Haddingtonshire. Mr. Jaggers, who has
recently erected a tasteful châlet on the Bass Rock, has just
issued his election address. The two main planks of his platform
are the legalising of the Schenectady putter for all golf meetings,
and of megaphones and mouth-organs in the House of Commons.</p>
            </div>
            <pb xml:id="page75" n="pg 75"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e1898" type="cartoon">
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/75.jpg"/>
                    <head>AN UNTRUSTWORTHY WITNESS.</head>
                    <p>Mother. "Gerald, a little bird has just told me
		that you have been a very naughty little boy this
		afternoon."</p>
                    <p>Gerald. "Don't you believe him, Mummy. I'll bet he's the one that
steals our raspberries.</p>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e1917" type="verse">
                <head>AMANDA.</head>
                <lg>
                    <l>When the thunders are still and the tempests are furled</l>
                    <l>There are sights of all sorts in this wonderful world;</l>
                    <l>But the best of all sights in the season of hay</l>
                    <l>Is Amanda Volanda McKittrick O'Dea.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>She can toss it as other girls toss up a cap,</l>
                    <l>And her eyes have a glow that can dry the green sap;</l>
                    <l>She's as good as the sun's most beneficent ray,</l>
                    <l>Is Amanda Volanda McKittrick O'Dea.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>Oh, her smile is a treat and her frown is the deuce;</l>
                    <l>She can always say "hiss me" or "bo" to a goose;</l>
                    <l>When she gives you her hand she just melts you away,</l>
                    <l>Does Amanda Volanda McKittrick O'Dea.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>In a field of soft clover I marked her one night,</l>
                    <l>And her foot it was dainty, her step it was light,</l>
                    <l>And I laughed to myself to behold her so gay,</l>
                    <l>Miss Amanda Volanda McKittrick O'Dea.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>Then the sound of her voice from December to June</l>
                    <l>And from June to December is always a tune;</l>
                    <l>All the elves when they hear it stop short in their play</l>
                    <l>For Amanda Volanda McKittrick O'Dea.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>When she sits on her chair like a queen on her throne</l>
                    <l>She has beautiful manners entirely her own;</l>
                    <l>But you'd better take care what you venture to say</l>
                    <l>To Amanda Volanda McKittrick O'Dea.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>P.S.—Since I managed to write the above</l>
                    <l>I've been round to her house and I've offered my love;</l>
                    <l>And she laughed and made jokes, but she didn't say nay,</l>
                    <l>My Amanda Volanda McKittrick O'Dea.</l>
                </lg>
                <signed>R. C. L.</signed>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e2031" type="snippets">
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>"At Easter this year the ladies gave their first public
performance by ringing a peal at a local wedding. The ladies now
ring regularly every week. Some idea of the work may be gathered
from the fact that the tenor bell weighs 11 cwt., and yet, through
all the training, not even a stay has been broken."—<title>Church
Monthly.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>Our feminine readers would like to know the name of the
bellringers' <title>corsetière</title>.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>From a letter to <title>The Daily Mail</title>:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>"One of our greatest poets was an apothecary's assistant, but
his 'Ode to a Skylark' is eternal."</p>
                </quote>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Hail to thee, blithe <name rend="sc">Shelley</name>!</l>
                        <l rend="i2">
                            <name rend="sc">Keats</name> thou never wert.</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>From a letter to <title>The Market Mail</title>:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>"I enclose my card and remains.—Yours truly, <name rend="sc">Victim</name>."</p>
                </quote>
                <p>We advise our contemporary to return the body.</p>
            </div>
            <pb xml:id="page76" n="pg 76"/>

         <!-- this ought to use lists -->
            <div xml:id="d1e2107" type="prose">
                <head>THE INQUISITION.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e2111" type="letter">
                    <head>
                        <name rend="sc">Letter I.</name>
                    </head>
                    <p rend="center">
                        <title>Julius Pitherby, Esq., to myself.</title>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Dear Sir</name>,—Henry Anderson, who is
an applicant for my temporarily vacant situation as working
gardener, assistant hedger and ditcher and superintending odd man
(single-handed), has referred me to you as to his character and
qualifications, stating that he was in your employment—I
gather some nine years ago—for a time. You will therefore, I
trust, forgive me if I take the liberty of asking you to be good
enough to answer the following questions concerning him and his
wife. He calls himself twenty-five, married, with no family.</p>
                    <p>(1) <title>Was</title> he in your employment?</p>
                    <p>(2) When?</p>
                    <p>(3) Is he twenty-five?</p>
                    <p>(4) Is he married?</p>
                    <p>(5) Has he no family?</p>
                    <p>(6) Is he <hi rend="it">strictly</hi> sober? (These words are to be taken
quite literally.)</p>
                    <p>(7) His wife ditto?</p>
                    <p>(8) Is he decent and morally respectable, careful in his habits
and guarded in his language?</p>
                    <p>(9) His wife ditto?</p>
                    <p>(10) Is he honest and reliable?</p>
                    <p>(11) His wife ditto, and <title>not one to answer back</title>?</p>
                    <p>(12) Are they both used to the country, contented in their
sphere, interested in rural surroundings, fond of children, fond of
animals, fond of fruit?</p>
                    <p>(13) Is he strong and healthy, neither shortsighted nor deaf? (I
have suffered much from both.)</p>
                    <p>(14) His wife ditto, <title>and always tidy</title>?</p>
                    <p>(15) Does he stammer? (I have been greatly inconvenienced by
this.)</p>
                    <p>(16) His wife ditto?</p>
                    <p>(17) Does he squint? (This has often been a trial to me.)</p>
                    <p>(18) His wife ditto?</p>
                    <p>(19) Is he active, industrious, enthusiastic and an early riser,
good-natured, equable and obliging?</p>
                    <p>(20) His wife ditto, and <title>no gossip</title>?</p>
                    <p>(21) Is he a heavy smoker?</p>
                    <p>(22) His wife ditto?</p>
                    <p>(23) Is he well up to the culture of vegetables, the upraising
of flowers and the education of fruit, both outside and under
glass?</p>
                    <p>(24) Is he capable of feeding hens, driving a motor, overhauling
a pianola, carving or waiting at table if required?</p>
                    <p>(25) To what Church do they belong? What are their favourite
recreations? Do they sing in the choir? if so, is he tenor or
baritone; his wife ditto?</p>
                    <p>(26) Are they on good terms with each other, and <title>no domestic
bickering</title>?</p>
                    <p>(27) What wages did you pay him?</p>
                    <p>(28) Why (on earth) did you part with him?</p>
                    <p>An immediate answer will greatly oblige. I enclose an addressed
envelope.</p>
                    <p>I am, &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Your
obedient Servant,</p>
                    <signed>
                        <name rend="sc">Julius Pitherby.</name>
                    </signed>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e2249" type="letter">
                    <head>
                        <name rend="sc">Letter II.</name>
                    </head>
                    <p rend="center">
                        <title>Myself to Julius Pitherby, Esq.,</title>
                    </p>
                    <p rend="right">
                        <title>Manor Orange, Pimhaven.</title>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Dear Sir</name>,—I thank you for your
letter. The answers to questions (1), (2), (25), (27) and (28) are
in the affirmative. With regard to the others you have, no doubt
unwittingly, put me in rather a dilemma. You see, Anderson left my
service when he was sixteen and I have not heard of him since,
though it is true that I did see his father (who belongs to this
neighbourhood) on the roof of the church one day last month. I
might make shots at them, of course, but I dare say it is better to
leave it. I am interested to learn that Henry is married.</p>
                    <p>I am, &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Yours
faithfully, &amp;c.</p>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e2277" type="letter">
                    <head>
                        <name rend="sc">Letter III.</name>
                    </head>
                    <p rend="center">
                        <title>Myself to Henry Anderson,</title>
                    </p>
                    <p rend="right">
                        <title>c/o Ezekiel Anderson, Slater, Crashie,
Howe.</title>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">My dear Henry</name>,—I do not think if I
were you I should accept Mr. Julius Pitherby's offer of a job. Your
marriage may, of course, have been—I hope it was—the
occasion of your turning over a new leaf. Still, I doubt if you are
quite the paragon he is looking for, and I am afraid that you may
find him a little inquisitive.</p>
                    <p>I am, &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Yours
faithfully, &amp;c.</p>
                </div>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e2309" type="prose">
                <head>ONCE UPON A TIME.<lb/>
The Power of the Press.         </head>
                <p>Once upon a time there was a quiet respectable little
spell-of-hot-weather, with no idea of being a nuisance or doing
more than warm people up a bit, and make the summer really feel
like summer, and add attraction to seaside resorts. Directly it
reached our shores every one began to be happy; and they would have
gone on being so but for the sub-editors, who cannot leave well
alone but must be for ever finding adjectives for it and teasing it
with attentions. Just then they were particularly free to turn
their attentions to the kindly visitor, because there was no good
murder at the moment, and no divorce case, and no spicy society
scandal, and therefore their pages were in need of filling. And
seeing the little spell-of-hot-weather they gave way to their
passion for labelling everything with crisp terseness—or
terse crispness (I forget which)—and called it a "heat wave,"
and straightway began to give it half the paper, and with huge
headings such as, "<name rend="sc">The Heat-Wave</name>,"
"<name rend="sc">Heat-Wave Still Growing</name>," "<name rend="sc">80
in the Shade</name>," "<name rend="sc">How to Support such
Weather</name>," so that the nice little spell-of-hot-weather was
gradually goaded into the desire really to justify this
excitement.</p>
                <p>"Very well," it said, "I never meant to be more than 80 in the
shade and a pleasant interlude in the usual disappointing English
June; but since they're determined I'm a nuisance I'll be one. I'll
go up to 84."</p>
                <p>And it did. It reached 84; and the wise people who like warmth
said, "How splendid! If only it would go on like this for ever! Not
hotter—just like this.".</p>
                <p>But the sub-editors were not satisfied. They had got hold of a
good thing and they meant to run it for all it was worth. So
"<name rend="sc">Hotter than Ever</name>" they sprawled across
their papers, there still being nothing of real public interest to
distract them, "<name rend="sc">Hotter Tomorrow</name>,"
"<name rend="sc">Heat-Wave Growing</name>," "<name rend="sc">Terrible Heat</name>."</p>
                <p>And now the spell-of-hot-weather was stimulated to be really
vicious. "I call Heaven to witness," it said, "that my sole desire
was to be genial and beneficial. But what can one do when one is
taunted and provoked, abused and nick-named like this? Very well
then, I'll go up to 90!"</p>
                <p>And it did. The sub-editors were delighted. "<name rend="sc">Appalling Heat</name>," they wrote, "<name rend="sc">Tropical
England</name>," "<name rend="sc">Gasping London</name>,"
"<name rend="sc">Heat-Wave Breaks all Records</name>,"
"<name rend="sc">Hottest Day for Fifty Years</name>,"
"<name rend="sc">No Signs of Relief</name>."</p>
                <p>And even the people who like warmth began to grumble a
little—hypnotised by the Press. But the spell-of-hot-weather
had had enough. "I'll go somewhere else, where I'm really welcome
and they don't have contents bills," it said, and it crossed the
Channel to Paris. It looked back to the English shores, deserted
now by the happy paddlers and bathers and baskers of the days
before. "I'm sorry to leave you," it said, "but don't blame
me."</p>
                <p>Yet the public did.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e2384" type="snippets">
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
            "The downpour of rain, which lasted for an hour, was preceded by
a remarkable shower of hailstones, some of which were almost as
large as marbles, and were as hard as ice."</quote>
                <p>
                    <title>Yorkshire Herald.</title>
                </p>
                <p>And then came the rain, some drops of which were as wet as
water.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"The tussle between Mr. Matheson and Mr. Anderson was carried to
the 18th green, where the latter stood one."—<title>Daily
Record.</title>
                </p>
                <p>"Mine's a gin and ginger," said Mr. <name rend="sc">Matheson</name>, as he holed the winning put.</p>
            </div>
            <pb xml:id="page77" n="pg 77"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e2416" type="cartoon">
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/77.jpg"/>
                    <head>THE CREATION OF A MASTERPIECE OF MILLINERY.</head>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <pb xml:id="page78" n="pg 78"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e2430" type="prose">
                <head>THE GUARDED GREEN.</head>
                <p rend="it">[It has been suggested that spectators at popular golf
competitions should be installed in grand stands and other
enclosures, and be restrained from wandering about the
links.]</p>
                <p>In playing his tee shot from in front of the Green Steward's
marquee, Mr. Tullbrown-Smith, who took the honour in the final
round of the 1916 Amateur Championship, unfortunately pulled his
ball, with the result that, narrowly missing the Actors' Benevolent
Fund stand, it entered the grand ducal box. The Grand Duke Raphael
graciously decided that Mr. Tullbrown-Smith should be presented to
His Imperial Highness before playing out. Pardonable nervousness
proved fatal to the shot, which, being badly topped, fell into the
Press pen, where it was photographed by <title>The Daily Mirror's</title>
special artist before it could be recovered by its owner.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>It is interesting to record that along the straight mile boarded
by the shilling enclosure Mr. Tanquery McBrail, who had been
playing with marvellously decorative effect, had his ball blown
into the bunker at the tenth by the laughter of the less
well-informed onlookers, while a regrettable incident was the
contribution of several empty ginger-beer bottles to the natural
difficulties of the hazard.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Some dissatisfaction was expressed among the occupants of the
cinema operators' cage. From the position allotted to them by the
publicity committee it was impossible to film the most interesting
moments in the Championship round, such as Mr. Tullbrown-Smith's
acceptance of a peeled banana from his caddie on emerging from the
particularly scenic bunker known as "Hell." Also a fine "picture"
was missed at the 13th tee, where Mr. Tanquery McBrail was
surrounded by a militant suffragist, who had invaded the course in
spite of the rabbit-wire and double <title>chevaux-de-frise</title>.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Owing to the fact that the fashionable audience assembled in the
Guards', Cavalry and Bath Club stands insisted upon encoring both
players' wonderful putts at the 16th green, and the consequent
delay of nearly ten minutes, there were some rather ugly
manifestations of impatience in the cheaper seats. In spite of the
fact that the Pale Pink Pierrots had been specially engaged to fill
the interval before the finalists passed, they were so loudly booed
upon their arrival that Mr. Tanquery McBrail put his mashie
approach into the Parliamentary compound, amidst the jeers and
hoots of the more unruly, who seemed to forget that the royal and
ancient game is not a music-hall entertainment.</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The fact that the links marshal had placed all the professional
players present in one row of fauteuils, opposite the long carry to
the 18th green, hardly seemed to further the interests of perfect
golf. The warmest acknowledgments are therefore due to a number of
ex-open champions, who kindly turned their backs on what proved one
of the most distressing episodes in the day's play.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e2470" type="prose">
                <head>A MARK OF DISTINCTION.</head>
                <p>When I passed our butcher's on my way to the station yesterday
morning, I noticed outside his shop a placard prominently
displayed, which read:—"Williamson's Spring Lamb. So
different from the ordinary butchers."</p>
                <p>There was no apostrophe before the "s" in "butchers," so the
reference was clearly to Williamson and not Williamson's Spring
Lamb.</p>
                <p>"Is Williamson really different from his rivals?" I said to
myself, crossing to the other side of the road to take a general
survey of the shop front. No, the same sort of joints seemed to be
hanging up as those in other butchers' windows; the same sort of
legends attached to those which passers-by were invited to note
particularly.</p>
                <p>I crossed the road again. Yes, as I feared. There were several
ordinary flies and at least one bluebottle exercising themselves on
the meat. The choice cutlets were not isolated or decorated with
garlands, or made a fuss of in any way. They just fraternised on
terms of equality with the rest. The usual "young lady" in a smart
blouse, with her bare pink neck served up in a ham-frill, sat
behind the usual window, probably trying to work out the usual sums
in butcher's arithmetic.</p>
                <p>The top half of Mr. Williamson was visible behind his
chopping-table. He saw me and touched his hat—a bowler;
nothing very extraordinary about the bowler. The brim was certainly
a great deal flatter than I like personally, but quite in keeping
with the general tastes of those who purvey meat.</p>
                <p>I thought it better to postpone further investigations, and
reflected that Honor might be able to enlighten me when I returned
home that evening.</p>
                <p>"No," she said, when I asked her about it, "I haven't noticed
anything exceptionally superior about him."</p>
                <p>"Bills any different?"</p>
                <p>"No," she said, "they take as long to pay; about as exorbitant
as most of the others."</p>
                <p>"Have you observed anything peculiar about his manners, then?" I
said; "does he ever throw chops at you, for instance, when you pass
the shop?"</p>
                <p>"No such luck," said Honor; "I'm a good catch."</p>
                <p>"Perhaps they give you tea," I said, "when you make an afternoon
call on the sirloins?"</p>
                <p>"Indeed they don't," said Honor, "not even when I go to pay
something off the book."</p>
                <p>"Then perhaps you have cosy little auction bridge parties in the
room behind the cashier's window? No? Butchers are behind the
times."</p>
                <p>"There ought," said Honor, "to be a good joke to be made out of
that—a newspaper joke; but I can't quite see how to make it
just yet."</p>
                <p>"That's something to the good," I said. "However, to our
muttons."</p>
                <p>"Rotten," said Honor.</p>
                <p>"What of his entourage?" I said, ignoring her comment; "his
steak-bearer and the like?"</p>
                <p>"Nothing unusual; just <title>épris</title> with Emily."</p>
                <p>"Then where, oh where," I said, "is this difference that
Williamson brags about?"</p>
                <p>"I don't know," Honor said helplessly.</p>
                <p>"I shall find out," I said, "even if I have to do the
housekeeping myself for a bit."</p>
                <p>"You can take it on," she said, "when you like."</p>
                <milestone rend="stars" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"Aha!" I said triumphantly, as I burst into the room this
evening. "I've solved the Williamson problem. He was standing at
his door as I passed just now, in all the regalia of his dread
office."</p>
                <p>"And you went up to him and said, 'Well, what about it?' and
pointed to the notice, I suppose."</p>
                <p>"Not at all," I said; "I merely looked at him and the scales
fell from my eyes. He butches in spats."</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e2562" type="snippets">
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>"In the open Golf Championship Treen won with
78."—<title>Malay Daily Chronicle.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>Next year it will be the saintly <name rend="sc">Andrew's</name> turn again.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>"With lightning-like repetition of his strides (his quick action
is the essence of his speed), Applegarth came flying down the home
straight."—<title>Yorkshire Post.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>Seeing that we were looking to <name rend="sc">Applegarth</name> to uphold British prestige at the next
Olympic games, we regret extremely that the secret of his speed
should have been given away to our rivals.</p>
            </div>
            <pb xml:id="page79" n="pg 79"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e2602" type="cartoon">
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/79.jpg"/>
                    <p>Counsel. "Prisoner is the man you saw commit the theft?" Witness (a
bookmaker). "Yes, sir".</p>
                    <p>Counsel. "You swear on your oath that prisoner is the man?"
Witness. "Yes, Sir."</p>
                    <p>Sporting Judge. "Are you prepared to give me five to two on the
prisoner being the man?"</p>
                    <p>Witness. "Ah, I'mn sorry me Lord, but I'm taking a holiday
to-day. Nothing doing.</p>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            <div xml:id="d1e2625" type="reviews">
                <head>OUR BOOKING-OFFICE.</head>
                <head rend="it">(By Mr. Punch's Staff of Learned Clerks.</head>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">Ellen Melicent Cobden</name> can certainly
            not be accused of writing too hurriedly. I don't know how
            many years it is since, as "<name rend="sc">Miles
            Amber</name>," she captured my admiration with that
            wonderful first novel, <title>Wistons</title>; and now
            here is her second, <title>Sylvia Saxon</title> (<name rend="sc">Unwin</name>), only just appearing. I may say at
            once that it entirely confirms my impression that she is a
            writer of very real and original gifts. <title>Sylvia
            Saxon</title> is not a pleasant book. It is hard, more
            than a little bitter, and deliberately unsympathetic in
            treatment. But it is grimly real. <title>Sylvia</title>
            herself is a character that lives, and her mother, Rachel,
            almost eclipses her in this same quality of tragic
            vitality. The whole tale is a tragedy of empty and
            meaningless lives passed in an atmosphere of too much
            money and too little significance. The "society" of a
            Northern manufacturing plutocracy, the display and
            rivalry, the marriages between the enriched families, the
            absence of any standard except wealth—all these things are
            set down with the minute realism that must come, I am
            sure, of intimate personal
            knowledge. <title>Sylvia</title> is the offspring of one
            such family, and mated to the decadent heir of
            another. Her tragedy is that too late she meets a man whom
            she supposes capable of giving her the fuller, more
            complete life for which she has always ignorantly yearned.
            Then there is <title>Anne</title>, the penniless girl,
            hired as a child to be a playfellow for
            <title>Sylvia</title>, who herself loves the same man, and
            dies when his dawning affection is ruthlessly swept away
            from her by the dominant personality of
            <title>Sylvia</title>. A tale, one might call it, of
            unhappy women; not made the less grim by the fact that the
            man for whom they fought is shown as wholly unworthy of
            such emotion. A powerful, disturbing and highly original
            story.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"<name rend="sc">Saki</name>" has been now for a number of
years a great delight to me, and his last work, <title>Beasts and
Super-Beasts</title> (<name rend="sc">Lane</name>), is as good as any
of its predecessors. Clothed in the elegant garments of
<title>Clovis</title> or <title>Reginald</title>, Mr. <name rend="sc">Munro</name>
makes plain to us how lovely this world might be were we only a
little bolder about our practical jokes. In the art of introducing
bears into the boudoir of a countess or pigs into the study of a
diplomat, and then clinching the matter with the wittiest of
epigrams, <title>Clovis</title> is supreme. He knows, too, an immense
amount about the vengeance that children may take upon their
relations, and ladies upon their lady friends. I like him
especially when he manœuvres some stupid but kind-hearted
woman into a situation of whose peril she herself is only cloudily
aware, while the reader knows all about it. That is the fun of the
whole thing. The reader is for ever assisting <title>Clovis</title> and
<title>Reginald</title>; in the course of their daring adventures he
connives from behind curtains, through key-holes, from ambushes in
trees, and always, whilst the poor creature is being harried by
wild boars or terrified by menacing kittens, <title>Clovis</title> may be
observed, with finger on lip, begging of the intelligent reader
that he will not give things away. Of the present collection of
stories I like best "A Touch of Realism," <pb xml:id="page80" n="pg 80"/> "The
Byzantine Omelette," "The Boar-Pig," and "The Dreamer;" but all are
good, and I can only hope that it will not be too long before
<title>Clovis</title> once again invites us to further delightful
conspiracies.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>
                    <title>Ars est celara artem</title>, and not to define and emphasise it
in a foreword to the reader. The motive of <title>The Last Shot</title>
(<name rend="sc">Chapman and Hall</name>) appears in due course in
the narrative; I would have preferred to discover it gradually for
myself rather than have the essence of it extracted and poured into
me in advance. The preface has not the excuse of a mere
advertisement; to open this book at any point is to read the whole,
and every page is the strongest possible incentive to the reading
of the others. If (as is not admitted) any personal explanation was
necessary, it should have been put at the end and in small type so
that those who, like myself, detest explanations might have avoided
this one. I am the more severe about this, because there can be no
two opinions as to Mr. <name rend="sc">Frederick Palmer's</name>
success in achieving his purpose, which, obviously, was to conceive
modern warfare as between two First-class Powers, fighting in the
midst of civilisation, and to reduce it to terms of exact realism,
showing the latest devices of destruction at work, but carefully
excluding those improbable and impossible agencies which the more
exuberant but less informed novelist loves to imagine and put in
play. Mr. <name rend="sc">Palmer's</name> conception, though based
upon some experience, is for the most part speculative, of course,
but I am confident that he gives us an excellent idea of how the
military machine would work in practice, how its human constituent
parts would feel inwardly, and what physical and moral effects a
battle would have upon those civilians who inhabited and owned the
battlefield. Whether or no the future will prove the truth of the
author's somewhat Utopian conclusions, he certainly founds them
upon a most exciting and convincing story, in which the "love
interest" is as powerful as could be desired.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Would you like to pay a round of visits to some delightful
Shropshire houses, as the friend and guest of a charming woman, who
knows all about what is most interesting in all of them, and has a
pleasantly chatty manner of telling it? Of course you would; so
would anyone. That is why I predict another success for Lady
<name rend="sc">Catherine Milnes Gaskell's</name> latest
house-book, <title>Friends Round the Wrekin</title> (<name rend="sc">Smith, Elder</name>). Perhaps you have pleasant memories of
her former volumes in the same kind; if so, I need say no more by
way of introduction; but, if not, I must tell you that her new book
is very fairly described, in the words of the publisher, as "a
further collection of history and legend, garden lore and character
study." What the publishers modestly refrain from mentioning is the
real charm with which it has been written, a quality that makes all
the difference. There are also photographs of a number of wholly
fascinating houses (the kind that make me wistful when I see them
in the auctioneers' windows), and the author has some personal
anecdote or quaint scrap of legend to tell you about each. I am
quite willing to admit that the rambling book has increased lately
to an extent imperfectly justified by its average quality. Too many
of them confuse rambling with drivelling. But for the reflections
of a cultivated woman, one who has steeped herself in the lore of a
country she evidently loves, and can transcribe it with such tender
and persuasive charm, there should always be room. I may
add—and your own tastes must decide whether this is a flaw or
a fresh merit—that Lady <name rend="sc">Catherine's</name>
sympathies, political and social, are undisguisedly with the past,
and that the "Education of the People" comes in, upon almost every
other page, for as shrewd raps as her gentle nature will allow her
to administer.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>I wish I were Mr. <name rend="sc">Justus Miles Forman</name>.
Because then, if I ever chanced to wake up suddenly and find that I
had been drugged in my sleep, and the six immense rubies, brought
here from the East by a far-off ancestor and set in a black agate
shield above my bed, to represent the "six <hi rend="it">gouttes</hi> (or
drops) <hi rend="it">gules</hi> on a field <hi rend="it">sable</hi>" of my immemorial
coat-of-arms, had been rudely reaved from me in the night by my
cousin, who had sent one each to his six sons, I should have no
fear. I should feel perfectly convinced that in a short time, by my
own personal exertions, but without exercising the least particle
of intelligence, I should recover those six rubies (representing
six <hi rend="it">gouttes</hi> or drops <hi rend="it">gules</hi>) and replace them in the
black agate shield (representing a field <hi rend="it">sable</hi>); and
naturally enough, like the autobiographical hero of <title>The Six
Rubies</title> (representing——I beg your pardon, I mean,
published by <name rend="sc">Ward, Lock</name>), I should not
dream of calling in the aid of the police. Another jolly thing that
would inspirit me would be the fact that each of my adventures in
search of the missing jewels would conform to a separate and
well-known type of magazine story: there would be one fire, one
notorious cracksman, one haunted castle, one cabinet with a secret
drawer, and so on. There would be plenty of excitement, plenty of
hairbreadth escapes. But I think that, when collating my
experiences and putting them into six-shilling form, I should
delete some of the tautologous references to the past which are one
of the stern necessities of serial publication. Otherwise my
readers might begin to feel slightly fatigued by my six ancestral
<hi rend="it">gouttes</hi>. They might even begin to feel that they did not
much care if I had hereditary sciatica.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e2786" type="cartoon">
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/80.jpg"/>
                    <p>Lady (to Nut who has talked of joining the Nationalist
Volunteers). "But you don't mean to say, surely, you're going to
fight?"</p>
                    <p>Nut. "Well, I rather thought of pairing with one of the Ulster
fellows."</p>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e2800" type="snippets">
                <quote>
                    <p>"In addition to excellent port, which furnished many prominent
features, the attendance was perhaps the best ever seen on a like
occasion."—<title>Sportsman.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>The most prominent feature would, of course, be the nose.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>