<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Punch, or the London Charivari, Vol. 150, February 16, 1916</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <idno type="gutenberg">23331</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>This text is freely available for re-use under US and UK law, consult
                            your local legal restrictions if elsewhere.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This text is a TEI version of a Project Gutenberg text originally located at
                            <ptr target="http://www.gutenberg.org/dirs//////"/>. As per their license agreement we have removed
                        all references to the project's trademark, however have included this
                        pointer to the original in case you want the plain text, or their XHTML
                        version. </p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2008-06-27T16:14:12.654+01:00"/>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <p>
                <graphic url="images/i-113.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                <title>V.A.D. wardmaid</title>, <title>M.A.</title> (<title>to
kitchen-maid</title>). <hi rend="sc">"I'm really a University
lecturer; but at a time like this we are <hi rend="it">all</hi> human
beings."</hi>
            </p>
            <div xml:id="d1e67" type="div2">
                <head>CHARIVARIA.</head>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="sc">Many</hi> early nestings are recorded as the
result of the mild weather, and at least one occasional visitor
(<title>Polonius bombifer</title>) has laid eggs in various parts of the
country.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Says a learned correspondent of <title>The Observer</title>: "There may be
fundamental differences between observed phenomena without affecting the
validity of a strict analogy; and after all an analogy is based upon
presented similarities. It is sufficient if the sameness should apply to
particular attributes or occurrences found by induction to have similar
relationships or consequences." It looks, after all, as if some of our
Museums wanted closing.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The "popular parts" of the Natural History Museum are to remain open,
though it is still felt by the Government that, at a time when the
practice of frugality is incumbent upon everybody, the spectacle of
stuffed animals may tend to have a demoralising effect upon the
young.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>From <title>The Evening News</title>:—</p>
                <p rend="center">"Our Daily War-time Menu.</p>
                <p rend="center">Fish Pie.<lb/>
Salt Beef. Turnips or Carrots.<lb/>
Baked Potatoes.<lb/>
Banana Pancake.<lb/>
Coffee."</p>
                <p>This will gratify those who believed that our contemporary's diet
consisted largely of brimstone.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>It is reported from Holland that Germans there are refusing German
notes. In the United States however they are still accepted at their
face value.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>It is understood that the Government recruiting authorities, with
whose
<title>jeu d'esprit</title> all Trafalgar Square is ringing, have definitely
rejected a proposed placard that says—</p>
                <p rend="center">
"WILL YOU 'ATE NOW<lb/>
OR WAIT TILL MARCH 8?"
</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The Admiralty has announced that sea-fishing is included among the
certified occupations exempted from the provisions of the Military
Service Act. The suggestion that the other kind of fishermen should be
rejected for psychopathic reasons has been bitterly resented by some of
our most persistent anglers.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"Many of the men," writes a correspondent at one of the Fronts, "have
apparently been without shirts for some time, and consequently the Army
authorities, with that kindly consideration which always distinguishes
them, have issued to the men a new pair of pants all round."</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A bird-eating spider has just arrived at the Zoo. While its diet is
commonly confined to quite small birds the animal is understood to have
expressed extreme confidence in its ability to eat eagles, if only to
show that its heart is in the right place.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"Germany's sea dogs," says the <title>Berliner Tageblatt</title>, "cannot
content themselves much longer with merely showing their teeth." This is
obviously unfair to <hi rend="sc">Tirpitz's</hi> tars, most of
whom have not hesitated to show their tails also.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The <hi rend="sc">Kaiser</hi> at Headquarters lifted his
glass to <hi rend="sc">King Ferdinand</hi>, this being the
kindliest way of intimating that he has Bulgaria on toast.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>It is rumoured that the Government has offered the control of our
anti-aircraft defences to the Office of Works, but that
Mr. <hi rend="sc">Lulu Harcourt</hi> has declined the
responsibility, adding, however, that he will gladly repair any damage
done by Zeppelins to the flower-beds in his department.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb n=" 114"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e189" type="div2">
                <head>THE WORD OF A GERMAN.</head>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>
                            <hi rend="sc">Your</hi> troth was broken ere the trumpets
blew;<lb/>
                        </l>
                        <l rend="i2">Into the fight with unclean hands you rode;<lb/>
                        </l>
                        <l>Your spurs were sullied and the sword you drew<lb/>
                        </l>
                        <l rend="i2">Bore stain of outrage done to honour's code.<lb/>
                        </l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>And you have played your game as you began.<lb/>
                        </l>
                        <l rend="i2">Witness the white flag raised by shattered ranks,<lb/>
                        </l>
                        <l>The cry for mercy, answered, man to man—<lb/>
                        </l>
                        <l rend="i2">And the swift stroke of traitor steel for thanks.<lb/>
                        </l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Once bitten we were twice a little shy,<lb/>
                        </l>
                        <l rend="i2">And then forgot; but with the mounting score<lb/>
                        </l>
                        <l>Our old good-nature, tried a shade too high,<lb/>
                        </l>
                        <l rend="i2">Stiffens its lip and means to stand no more.<lb/>
                        </l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>So now, when you protest with bleating throat,<lb/>
                        </l>
                        <l rend="i2">And broider round your wrongs a piteous tale,<lb/>
                        </l>
                        <l>Urging the Neutral Ones to take a note<lb/>
                        </l>
                        <l rend="i2">That we have passed outside the human pale;<lb/>
                        </l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>The world (no fool) will know where lies the blame<lb/>
                        </l>
                        <l rend="i2">If England lets your pleadings go unheard;<lb/>
                        </l>
                        <l>To grace of chivalry you've lost your claim;<lb/>
                        </l>
                        <l rend="i2">We've grown too wise to trust a Bosch's word.<lb/>
                        </l>
                    </lg>
                    <l rend="right">O. S.</l>
                </lg>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e319" type="div2">
                <head>THE BILLETING CAPTAIN.</head>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="sc">My</hi> job is to ride on ahead of the
regiment, whenever we leave the trenches, and secure accommodation for
men and horses in the place allotted to us. For billeting purposes there
are four kinds of villages behind our front: the good, the indifferent,
the positively bad, and the village of R——. It was to
R—— that I was ordered on my first errand of this kind. On
the road I met a friend who holds the same pest in his regiment as I do
in mine. I told him where I was going, and he grinned. "You'll find all
the doors locked when you arrive," he said. "The Mayor is away on
service and you won't get any help from his wife. She's the most
disagreeable woman I ever met, and is known for miles round as a holy
terror." When at length I reached my destination I sent the rest of the
party in search of barns and stables, proceeding myself towards the
village pump, which I had been told was always a good place to work
from. But there was little sign of life here. The <hi rend="it">place</hi> was
deserted, except for one old man who was supporting himself by the pump
handle, while with a stick in his other hand he tried to strafe a hen
that had inadvertently run between his legs.</p>
                <p>"Bon jour, M'sieur," I said by way of a start.</p>
                <p>"Cigarette anglaise!" replied the patriarch.</p>
                <p>I offered my case and was presently being entertained with
reminiscences of the war of <title>soixante-dix</title>. By the time that he had
finished his cigarette he had gone further back into history and was
vividly describing the retreat from Moscow under the First Napoleon, on
which occasion I gathered that he had caught a severe cold. There was
evidently little help to be gained here, so leaving my venerable friend
amid the Russian snows I went to the nearest house and knocked.
Presently a key turned and the door was opened for about three inches by
an old woman.</p>
                <p>"<title>Bon jour, Madame</title>," I said in my best French; "I seek a
bedroom, if possible one with a bed in it."</p>
                <p>She looked me up and down for a moment, then with a "<title>Pas
compris</title>" shut and locked the door again.</p>
                <p>In the next house they were more obliging. A stout gentleman opened
the door and informed me that unfortunately he possessed only one bed,
which was shared by himself and his family of six children. But as
M'sieu was a member of the <hi rend="it">entente</hi>, and if he could find no other
accommodation—— But here I fled. Thus it was from house to
house, and when later my N.C.O. reported his arrangements for men and
horses satisfactory I had only managed to secure one miserable little
room. So desperate had I become by this time that I determined to face
the Mayor's wife, in spite of my friend's advice. Accordingly I turned
towards a house labelled <title>Mairie</title>, and entered the garden, where a
small child was playing. I think without exception he was the ugliest
little boy I have ever seen, but I am a father when home on leave, and
he smiled at me in such a nice friendly way that I stopped and pecked at
his cheek as I passed.</p>
                <p>When I looked up I saw a grim face regarding me over a pot of
geraniums in the window. "Now for it!" I thought, and was presently face
to face with the formidable lady, who asked me in broken English what my
business might be. "Madame," I said, "you see a ruined captain before
you. I have been sent to this village to find twelve bedrooms for my
Colonel and brother-officers. Also a mess-room and an office. In one
hour I have secured one room, and even now the regiment is arriving,"
for as I spoke the O.C. and some of the others came riding up. On seeing
me they dismounted, and before Madame could say anything she and I were
the centre of a little group of officers.</p>
                <p>"Well," said the O.C., "what luck? We're looking forward to real beds
again, I can tell you!"</p>
                <p>I felt myself growing red. "The men and horses are arranged for,
Sir," I stammered, and then suddenly a voice at my side took up the
tale: "And if you will come wiz me I shall 'elp ze Captain to show to
you ze rooms 'e 'as found." Unable to utter a word, I bowed, and we
followed Madame to the first house at which I had earlier tried so
unsuccessfully. She knocked at the door like a fury, and no sooner was
it opened than she went in without more ado, and we after her. "I have
come to show M'sieu the Colonel the room that you have prepared for
him," she said in her own language to the old woman, who stood bowing
and smiling as hard as she could. Then she opened a door and took us
into the nicest room imaginable.</p>
                <p>"'Ere I 'ope you will be 'appy, my Colonel," she continued. "Zis is
ze best room ze Captain could find for you. Also I 'ope you will find
Madame aimable;" and here she looked at the old woman, who started
bowing again harder than ever. It was the same at all the other houses.
Passing from one to another she commandeered room after room, even
managing to wrest a bed from the father of six; and I verily believe
that the inhabitants would have burned their dwellings to warm us had
the little lady ordered it. All the while she maintained the fiction
that I had arranged things previously.</p>
                <p>"I 'ave just come wiz ze Captain to see everyting ees what you call
spick," she said on leaving us.</p>
                <p>"And a very good business you have made of it," said the O.C. to me
approvingly. Still greatly puzzled, I returned to thank my benefactress.
After expressing my gratitude I ventured to tell her that she had been
much kinder to me than I had been led to expect.</p>
                <p>"But 'ave I not see you kees my little son?" she said gravely.</p>
                <p>"Ah," I said to myself, "<title>that's</title> it!" and, stooping down to
where he was playing, I did it again with added warmth.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>From the transactions of the Royal Dublin Society:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>"Professor <hi rend="sc">Hugh Ryan</hi>, M.A.,
D.Sc., and Mr. M. J. <hi rend="sc">Walsh</hi>, M.Sc.—'On
Desoxyhydrocatechintetramethylether.'"</p>
                </quote>
                <p>We are not surprised that it took two of them to tackle it.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb n=" 115"/>
                <p>
                    <graphic url="images/i-115.png"/>
                </p>
                <div xml:id="d1e425" type="div3">
                    <head>SAINT VALENTINE'S DAY IN THE FATHERLAND.</head>
                    <p>It chanced that on the fourteenth day of February the boy Cupid
strayed into the precincts of Potsdam, and came all unawares upon the
War Lord; who deeming him to be an alien babe essayed to make a
characteristic end of him.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb n=" 116"/>
                    <p>
                        <graphic url="images/i-116.png"/>
                    </p>
                    <p rend="sc">
                        <title>Disgusted Instructor.</title> "Now then, none o'
	   them peace tactics! 'Ere I'm trying to teach yer 'ow to kill the enemy,
and yer goes and kisses 'im!"</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e450" type="div2">
                <head>BLANCHE'S LETTERS.</head>
                <p rend="center">
                    <hi rend="sc">War Fashions.</hi>
                </p>
                <p rend="right">
                    <title>Park Lane.</title>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="sc">Dearest Daphne</hi>,—People are going to
the theatre a good deal, but not in the old way. We wait in the queue
now, and work our way up into the gallery. We leave the stalls and boxes
to <title>ces autres</title>. "Olga" has created a simply charming queue-coat,
heavy grey frieze, with plenty of pockets and a cap to match with
ear-pieces. You take a parcel of sandwiches to eat while you're waiting
(the <title>dernier cri</title> is to wrap the parcel in a spotted
handkerchief), and, if you want to be immensely and utterly right,
you'll <hi rend="it">walk</hi> home and buy a piece of fried fish on the way for
your supper.</p>
                <p>À propos, there's quite a good little story being told about Lady
Goreazure and these topsy-turvy times. She was in the gallery at the
Incandescent the other night, and, on coming down, the gallery people,
finding it was pouring in torrents, crowded into the chief entrance for
shelter, to the enormous disgust of the stalls and boxes, who were just
coming out. A rose-coloured satin gown with ante-war bare arms and
shoulders, an ermine wrap, and a paste hair-bandeau was particularly
furious, and announced loudly that it was "an abominable shame to mix us
up with the gallery people in this way." Lady Goreazure thought she knew
the voice, and, turning, recognised in the angry pink-satin person her
maid, Dawkins, who left her some months ago to go into munition work.
She's a skilled hand now and simply coining money, as she told Lady G.
in a hurried furtive whisper, adding, "Please don't talk to me any more.
I shouldn't like my friends to see that I know anyone from the
gallery."</p>
                <p>One of the <hi rend="it">literally</hi> burning questions of the moment has been
how to dispose of the little lanterns one's obliged to carry after dark
now that so many people have given their motors to the country and stump
it or bus it everywhere. Your Blanche has solved the difficulty and at
the same time set a fashion. My evening boots (what a different meaning
that phrase has from what it once had, my Daphne!) have darling little
teeny-weeny lamps fixed to their toes, so that one can see exactly where
one's stepping. With these boots is worn a toque with a small lamp
fastened in a velvet or ribbon <hi rend="it">chou</hi> in front. The <hi rend="it">boots</hi>
are for <title>one's own guidance</title>; the <title>toque illuminante</title> is to
show <hi rend="it">other</hi> gropers in the darkness that one's coming. Some people
add a chic little hooter, which clears the way quite nicely and is
simply <hi rend="it">precious</hi> in crossing roads.</p>
                <p>Speaking of those who've given all their motors to the State and
those who haven't, a new social danger has bobbed up for the
latter—the chauffeuse. She's got to be reckoned with, dearest. In
threatening the single lives of people's eldest sons she's leaving even
the eternal chorus-girl down the course, and in releasing <hi rend="it">one</hi> man
for the Front she's quite likely to capture <title>another who counts
considerably more!</title>
                </p>
                <p>The Ramsgates thought they'd got a perfect jewel of a
chauffeuse—smart, businesslike, knew town well, knew when she
might exceed the speed limit and when she mightn't, thoroughly
understood her car and so on. And then one day Pegwell came back from
the Front on sick leave. As soon as he was well enough he went for a
drive every day. Someone said to his mother, "I wonder you trust your
boy out alone with that chauffeuse of yours." And Elizabeth
Ramsgate <hi rend="it">laughed</hi> at the caution. "I only wish Thompson were more
dangerous," she said. "There's safety in numbers, and if she were
younger and prettier perhaps she'd
<pb n="Pg117"/> switch Peggy's thoughts off that
fearful Dolly de Colty of the Incandescent."</p>
                <p>
                    <graphic url="images/i-117.png"/>
                </p>
                <p rend="sc">"I say, old girl, do let me carry something."</p>
                <p>And so Pegwell went on with his drives, and one day they were out so
long that his mother was anxious, and when at last they came back she
said, "Oh, Thompson, you've been driving Lord Pegwell too far; he's not
strong enough for such long drives; it was very inconsiderate of you,
Thompson." And the chauffeuse tossed up her chin and cried, "Not so much
'Thompson,' please!" And Pegwell chipped in with, "This is Lady Pegwell,
mother, and in future she'll drive no one but me!"</p>
                <p>Popsy, Lady Ramsgate, is even more furious about it than his parents.
"Ramsgate and Elizabeth have behaved like fools," she said to me
yesterday; "they don't know their world in the least, though they've
lived in it nearly half a century. What if the minx <title>wasn't</title>
particularly young and pretty. A chauffeuse is a novelty, and when
you've said that you've said everything."</p>
                <p>Your Blanche is enormously busy just now editing a book that's going
to be the sensation of the Spring crop of volumes. You're aware, of
course,
<title>m'amie</title>, that if a book's even to be <hi rend="it">looked</hi> at now it must
be either Somebody's Memories of Everybody Else or Somebody's
Experiences in an Enemy Country. Well, and so Stella Clackmannan and I,
in the hostel we run for poor dears who've lost their situations abroad
and have no friends to go to on coming back here, found among our guests
a bright little Cockney who's been what she calls an up-and-down girl in
the Royal Palace at Bashbang, the capital of Rowdydaria. My dearest, the
things that girl has climbed over and crawled under, and the weather
she's come through, in escaping from the Rowdydarians and getting back
here! And the things she's seen and heard in the Palace! It will throw a
flood of light on all sorts of things, and will certainly make our F.O.
sit up.</p>
                <p>With the help of a clever photographer and some imagination we've
reconstructed the up-and-down girl's adventures quite nicely. There are
photos of the King of Rowdydaria as head of his own army; in his uniform
as Colonel of the Hun Räuberundmörder Regiment; and in the Arab burnous
in which he is to lead an attack on Egypt. There's a photo of the
up-and-down girl sweeping a passage and listening through a key-hole to
a wonderful conversation between the King of R. and an Emperor who'd
come to see him (luckily it was in English and she remembers every
word): "You've got to say <hi rend="it">you</hi> did it." "But I haven't got any
navy—I <title>couldn't</title> have done it." "I'll give you the submarine
that did it—or <hi rend="it">lend</hi> it to you. There! now it's
yours—for a time. <title>You</title> don't depend on the Neutralians for
any supplies. So you can afford to tell them you did it—and be
quick about it." "But you can't expect even the <title>Neutralians</title> to
swallow that!" "Why, you fool, they'd swallow anything! That's the
meaning of their phrase 'rubber-neck.'" There's a photo of the Queen of
Rowdydaria coming up at this point, snatching the broom away, and
beating the up-and-down girl with it, and calling her "Spying English
Pig." Altogether, my dear, it's positively enthralling! Order your copy
early, for people will be slaying each other for this
book. <title>Astounding Disclosures of an Up-and-down Girl in the Royal
Palace at Bashbang</title> will certainly quite <hi rend="it">quite</hi> eclipse those
two other sensations, <title>What a Buttons Overheard in the Imperial
Pickelhaube Schloss</title> and <title>Amazing Revelations of a Tweeny in the
Perhapsburg Hof</title>.</p>
                <p>Ever thine,<lb/>
                    <hi rend="sc">Blanche.</hi>
                </p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e594" type="div3">
                    <head>How to put People at their Ease.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>"The officer in command, Lieut. Berg, was exceedingly pleasant, and
    did all in his power to put the passengers at their ease and make
    them feel comfortable.... He had a large bomb placed in the
    engine-room, and another on the bridge, which could be exploded
    easily by electricity."—<title>Daily News.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p rend="center">  "AMERICA'S LAST WORD FOR<lb/>
  THE HUN.<lb/>
  SIXTEEN PAGES TO-DAY."<lb/>
                        </p>
                        <p rend="right">
                            <title>Daily Mirror Poster.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>These American last words!</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb n=" 118"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e635" type="div2">
                <head>THE WATCH DOGS.</head>
                <p rend="center">XXXV.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="sc">My dear Charles</hi>,—Things go on here
from day to day in a businesslike and orderly fashion, the comic relief
being supplied by a temporary, very temporary, man from overseas, who
has operated for a while at our telephone exchange. Most people, myself
included, are overawed by the dignity and significance of our
environment here; not so this Canadian. One of our very greatest was
having words with his instrument the other evening. He supposed,
wrongly, that his antagonist was a hundred kilometres away, and he
adjusted his remarks and voice accordingly. Imagine his pain on being
informed, from the exchange, in quite a cheerful and friendly tone, "I
guess you're on the wrong string this time, Mister."</p>
                <p>There is also, of course, that never-failing source of satisfaction,
the military mess waiter. I think ours, the other night, excelled all
starters in the art of ellipsis. Our meal was interrupted by a loud
bump, crash, cataclysm and bang. We took it that two at least of the
enemy's great offensives had begun, centralising on us and opening with
the destruction of all our mess machinery, personnel and platter.
Shortly afterwards Alfred, slightly flushed, came into the room. We
asked him to let us know the worst. All we could get out of him was, "I
must 'a' trod on a bit o' fat, Sir."</p>
                <p>You will be touched, I am sure, by the pretty story now current
concerning the earnest young subaltern and the Brigadier. The former was
responsible for the training of an expert section, in no matter what
particular black art; the latter called in person one morning to witness
an experimental display. The apparatus was produced, the Brigadier
inspected it delicately, and the section was fallen in, standing near by
in an attitude of modest pride. From them the Brigadier eventually
singled out a private to do a star turn; silence was enjoined while the
subaltern should give the private the necessary detail orders. Now the
subaltern was one of the many of us civilians who have a burning
ambition not only to achieve perfection always, but also to maintain on
all occasions a superlatively military bearing. Confronted by the
private and expected to order him about, he hesitated, blushed and at
last made it clear that he simply must, before beginning, have a few
words apart in the General's private ear. With kindly toleration the
General eventually conceded this, and it was then made more than
apparent to him why it was that the earnest young subaltern was
reluctant to give his orders to the private without some explanation in
advance to the Brigadier. "The man's <hi rend="it">surname</hi> is Bhyll, Sir," he
whispered.</p>
                <p>Red-hats may not always know much about life in the trenches, but
they can tell you at first hand what strafing was like when there were
no trenches to live in. You will perhaps care to hear of an adventure of
the good old days, when men wandered about Flanders on their own,
sometimes attaching themselves to English units, sometimes to French,
and sometimes marching inadvertently with the Central Powers. Maps in
those days didn't show you clearly which was your bit and which was the
other fellow's, and many a time different parties, meeting in the dark,
would be quite affable in passing, little knowing it was each other's
blood they were after. My man, at the moment when we take up the
narrative, was walking about in a wood, looking for a job. Half an hour
earlier he had been busily engaged in a brisk battle, but, owing to his
not keeping his mind on it, he'd got detached and now found himself in
one of those peculiarly peaceful solitudes which only exist in the heart
of the war zone. Whether the battle was over and, if so, who'd won it,
he couldn't say. In fact, those being the early confused days, he didn't
rightly know whether it had been a battle at all or just a little
personal unpleasantness between himself and his private enemies.
Everything appeared to be exactly as it should not be; he felt that he
ought to be exhilarated with victory or depressed with defeat, exhausted
or maimed, and not merely covered from top to toe with mud. He found
himself walking along in a wood, just as he might do at home, smoking a
cigarette and thinking that this would be a most convenient moment for a
wash and a cup of tea. As he said, the very last thing he seemed to be
at was war, when suddenly, climbing over a small ridge, he discovered
himself face to face with a hostile sentry, and near him were, at
repose, a knot of other equally repulsive Bosches.</p>
                <p>It has struck everyone out here, sooner or later, that it is easy
enough to do the thing if only one could know at the moment what is the
thing to do. Here was a sentry whose whole recent education had been
devoted to learning exactly how to deal with new and unwelcome arrivals.
He was furnished for that very purpose with a rifle having a carefully
sharpened bayonet at one end of it and a nice new bullet at the other.
There he was, all prepared to deal with an emergency, and there was the
emergency confronting him. Having had a good look at it, he contented
himself with saying "Halt! wer da?" adding as an afterthought a
threatening move forward.</p>
                <p>On the other hand, here was our friend, young and vigorous, in full
possession of all his faculties, too surprised to be even alarmed. His
first tendency was to pass haughtily on or, at the most, to stop and
tell the man to be more respectful when addressing an officer. His
second was to call to mind, in a confused mess, all the brilliant and
dashing things a hero of fiction would, without a moment's hesitation,
have done in the circumstances. Lastly, it was borne in on him that this
was indeed a German; that all Germans were, under the new arrangement,
sworn to do in all Englishmen at sight, and that he himself was, beneath
his mud, one of the last-named. Being rather the quicker-witted of the
two, he had put in three thoughts to the other fellow's one; but the
position showed no improvement in the result, and the enemy's second
thought, slowly dawning, was obviously of a more practical and drastic
nature. His undecided fidgeting with his rifle made this abundantly
clear. No time was to be lost. Our friend realised dimly that at all
costs he must conceal his nationality. This promised to be a matter of
languages, never his strong point. But, there again, he was carefully
prepared with a series of useful phrases in various tongues, which he
had learnt up in small and inexpensive hand-books. The difficulty was to
get on to the right one; his mind, having got him thus far, refused
further assistance. Instead of furnishing him with the appropriate
remark, it merely suggested to him a clearly defined picture of the
outside of the text-book, particularly emphasizing the elegant but inept
phrase, "One Shilling net at all Booksellers." And what was the use of
that with the sentry's bayonet rapidly coming to the "On guard"
position?</p>
                <p>It's a long story, Charles, and it ended by our friend ingenuously
stating by way of a seasonable ruse, "Pardon, monsieur, je suis
français."</p>
                <p>I'd prefer to leave it at that, but you are one of those detestable
people who insist on going on after the climax. So I may as well tell
you that at this point our friend's legs took to action on their own, no
doubt remarking to themselves as they did so that this was but another
instance of damned bad Staff work. I sometimes wonder whether possibly
it isn't easier to be a limb than a brain.</p>
                <p>Yours ever,<lb/>
                    <hi rend="sc">Henry.</hi>
                </p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb n=" 119"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e686" type="div2">
                <head>MR. PUNCH'S POTTED FILMS. THE PASSIONATE DRAMA.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e689" type="div3">
                    <head>THE DEMON OF JEALOUSY.</head>
                    <p>
                        <graphic url="images/i-119a.png"/>
                    </p>
                    <p rend="sc">"Wretched woman! Who is this? Henceforth you are no wife of
mine!"</p>
                    <p>
                        <graphic url="images/i-119b.png"/>
                    </p>
                    <p rend="sc">A woman's anguish.</p>
                    <p>
                        <graphic url="images/i-119c.png"/>
                    </p>
                    <p rend="sc">"Die, scoundrel!"</p>
                    <p>
                        <graphic url="images/i-119d.png"/>
                    </p>
                    <p rend="sc">A strong man's rage.</p>
                    <p>
                        <graphic url="images/i-119e.png"/>
                    </p>
                    <p rend="sc">"He is my brother from Australia. You should not
	 be so hasty."</p>
                    <p>
                        <graphic url="images/i-119f.png"/>
                    </p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb n=" 120"/>
                    <p>
                        <graphic url="images/i-120.png"/>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <title>Grannie</title> (<title>dragged out of bed at
1.30 <hi rend="sc">A.M.</hi> and being hurriedly dressed as the
bombs begin to fall</title>). "<hi rend="sc">Nancy, these stockings</hi>
                    </p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e765" type="div2">
                <head>LITERARY PITFALLS.</head>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chronicle</title> publishes a most interesting letter received
from Mr. G. B. <hi rend="sc">Burgin</hi>, who lately, if our

writes:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>"A hitch has arisen about the publication of my novel, <title>The
      Rubber Princess</title>. It deals with an air raid on London, etc.,
      and it has been pointed out to me that if it appears before the
      War is over it will probably be suppressed, and that I shall be
      mulcted in pains and penalties. I have therefore withdrawn it and
      substituted (for the Spring), with Hutchinsons, <title>The Hut by the
      River</title>, of which I have great hopes. It is a Canadian romance,
      with a pretty love story and a nice little mystery at the
      end."</p>
                </quote>
                <p>It will, we are sure, be a consolation to
Mr. <hi rend="sc">Burgin</hi>, to whose agility and versatility
we desire to render our homage, to learn that he is not singular in his
experience.</p>
                <p>Only a few days ago we received a letter from Mr. Bimbo Posh, the
famous Suffolk realist, recounting the circumstances which have led to
the postponement of his eagerly-expected romance,
<title>The Synthetic Sovereign</title>.</p>
                <p>It appears that Mr. Posh, a man of a most scientific imagination,
assigned the <title>rôle</title> of hero in his story to a marvellous automaton.
Unfortunately for him he was not content with generalities, but
described the process by which this artificial superman was produced in
such minute detail that his publishers realised that it might be
positively prejudicial to our safety to make it known. The sequel had
best be told in Mr. Posh's own pathetic words:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>"At first I was fearfully upset, though convinced by the arguments
    of my publishers (Messrs. Longbow and Green-i'-th'-Eye). But a happy
    inspiration seized me as I was ascending the escalator at Charing
    Cross, and in exactly a fortnight I had finished another novel,
    entirely divorced from the present, entitled, <title>In Dear Old
    Daffy-land</title>. It is an idyllic story of Suffolk in the days of the
    Heptarchy, founded on an ancestral tradition of the Posh family. It
    runs to about 60,000 words, and Mr. Longbow, who read it at a
    sitting, thinks it the finest thing I have done."</p>
                </quote>
                <p>Curiously enough, just as we go to press comes a letter from Miss
Miriam Eldritch, apologising for the withdrawal of her volume of
poems, <title>Attar of Roses</title>, in view of the fact that one of the
leading establishments for the distilling of this perfume is in
Bulgaria. Miss Eldritch, however, has proved fully equal to the
occasion, for by a great effort she has composed, in little over one
hundred hours, a cycle of one hundred lyrics, to which she has given the
title, at once alluring and innocuous, of <title>Love in Lavender</title>.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e828" type="div3">
                    <head>"Perturbabantur Constantinopolitani
Innumerabilibus sollicitudinibus."</head>
                    <p>["Constantinople is much perturbed."</p>
                    <p rend="right">
                        <title>Daily Press.</title>]</p>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>
                                <hi rend="sc">In</hi> flouting Zeus and Themis, his</l>
                            <l>Heart set on cheating Nemesis,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">  The Constantinopolitan</l>
                            <l>Now rues his impious blunders,</l>
                            <l>And fears approaching thunders</l>
                            <l rend="i2">  Trinitrotoluolitan.</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>"Gentleman's dark grey fur lined motor coat, fit fairly big man,
    lined with about 150 selected natural musquash skins, real Persian
    lamb collar, the property of a peer, in the pink of
    condition."—<title>The Bazaar.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>We trust his lordship will remain so in spite of the inclemency of
the weather.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb n=" 121"/>
                    <p>
                        <graphic url="images/i-121.png"/>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="sc">Uncle Sam</hi>
(<title>to <hi rend="sc">Job</hi>
                        </title>). "SAY, PATRIARCH, THEY TELL
ME YOU HOLD THE WORLD'S RECORD FOR PATIENCE. WAL, WE CLAIM TO HAVE GOT A
MAN HERE THAT CAN KNOCK SPOTS OFF YOU!"
</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb n=" 122"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e911" type="div2">
                <head>ESSENCE OF PARLIAMENT.</head>
                <p rend="center">(<hi rend="sc">Extracted from the Diary of Toby, M.P.</hi>)</p>
                <p rend="center">
                    <hi rend="sc">The Last Chapter.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <title>House of Commons, Tuesday, 15th February.</title>—After, on
nomination of my revered master, Mr. Punch, representing Barkshire in
the Commons during three reigns, under nine Parliaments, captained in
succession by six Premiers, come to conclusion that I have earned the
right to retire. Two ways of voluntarily vacating a seat. One by a call
to the Lords. The other by application for Chiltern Hundreds. Not having
heard anything about the Peerage, have adopted latter course.
The <hi rend="sc">Member for Sark</hi>, loyal to the last,
insists on following my example.</p>
                <p>Accordingly, when House meets to-morrow, writs will be moved for
elections to fill two vacancies. In ordinary times this would lead to
interesting episode. Customary for the Chief Party Whip to move for writ
to fill casual vacancies in his ranks. Would the Ministerial Whip or the
Opposition Whip come forward to take preliminary step for elections
consequent on retirement of the <hi rend="sc">Member for
Barks</hi> and the <hi rend="sc">Member for Sark</hi>?</p>
                <p>The closest observer of Parliamentary procedure or comment is not
sure whether in Party politics they are Liberals or Conservatives.
Cannot indeed say on which side of the House they sit. As it happens
there is at this doubly memorable date no division of parties,
consequently no contending Whips. Writs for Barks and Sark will
accordingly be appropriately moved by Whip representing united
House.</p>
                <p>Thirty-five years ago Barks first sent me to Westminster. Of Cabinet
Ministers then seated on Treasury Bench none are alive
to-day. <hi rend="sc">Gladstone</hi>, just returned by
overwhelming majority, was
Premier; <hi rend="sc">Granville</hi>, with consummate skill and
dainty humour, led minority supporting Government in House of
Lords; <hi rend="sc">Harcourt</hi> was at the Home
Office; <hi rend="sc">Hartington</hi>, Secretary of State for
War; <hi rend="sc">Childers</hi> at the
Treasury; <hi rend="sc">Kimberley</hi> at the India Office; at
the Irish Office <hi rend="sc">Forster</hi>, with his rumpled
hair, his rugged speech and his gruff manner, "the best Stage
Yorkshireman of his time."</p>
                <p>Much history has been made since that time. Procedure in the Commons
has been revolutionised, with the result not only of accelerating
ordinary business and leading to final issue controversies futilely
raging for years, but radically altering personal tone and manner of
Mother of Parliaments.</p>
                <p>That is another story, too lengthy to be told here. Glad to know I
was intimately acquainted with the House and, with rare exceptions, with
the principal personages in either political camp through a long stretch
of older, more picturesque time.</p>
                <p>I close the Diary here, not because I am tired of writing it, nor, as
continuous testimony indicates, because a generous public is tired of
reading. But I am not disposed to linger superfluous on the stage. So I
withdraw, carrying with me my little bag of tricks, the sententious Dog,
the cynical <hi rend="sc">Sark</hi> and the rest of the
contents.</p>
                <p>Henceforward some new form will be given to the "Essence of
Parliament" which was created by <hi rend="sc">Shirley
Brooks</hi>, and enlivened by the hand of <hi rend="sc">Tom
Taylor</hi>.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Business done.</title>—<hi rend="sc">Toby,
M.P.'s</hi>.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1006" type="div2">
                <head>A DIRTY NIGHT.</head>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="sc">The</hi> night is starless, with a darkness so
enveloping that it seems to possess palpability. As we reel westward in
a smother of water the miracle of how any human being equipped with but
five senses can find and keep his course in the chartless void that
envelops us smites me afresh.</p>
                <p>A longing for an atmosphere unimpregnated with petrol eventually
sends me stumbling up the companion-way to the deck. Gripping the rail,
I make my way forward, and, peering through the mirk, distinguish a
huddled figure in a sou'wester. Aloof, detached, he steers the
shrewdest, swiftest path ever carved through a wall of blackness on
behalf of dependent fellow-creatures.</p>
                <p>"A wild night," I shout.</p>
                <p>He turns slightly and answers in a hoarse bellow, "The better for us,
mister. Keeps the track clear. Ought to get in ahead o' time."</p>
                <p>The yellow glare from our lights glances in broken splashes of colour
over the waters, as the squat craft heaves and rolls with rhythmic
regularity. From somewhere below comes the monotonous throb of the
protesting engines. A red light gleams suddenly on our starboard, and I
catch my breath. Æons pass, it seems, before a panther-like clutch at
the wheel carries us aside in time to let the offender plunge drunkenly
past. We were near enough to throw a biscuit on her deck. A swift
exchange of badinage follows.</p>
                <p>"Lost yer job o' puntin' coal-barges?"</p>
                <p>"Yuss—they're usin' donkey-power instead. I give in your name
'fore I left, but they 'adn't a spare stable." After which, the
immediate danger past, we plough our way down a blurred track on either
side of which lurks Peril in a hundred grim and invisible shapes.</p>
                <p>The temperature, already low, has begun to drop steadily, and a fine
drizzle yields to a penetrating chilliness which finds its way to one's
very marrow. I am glad of my heavy wraps, and inclined, indeed, to envy
the huddled figure, whose coverings are still heavier. Inwardly I wonder
what this clashing of the Nations has meant to him: whether he has wife
and children; whether he keeps their portraits in some deep-buried
pocket beneath that accumulation of clothing which engulfs him to the
ear-tips.</p>
                <p>I am still speculating when a second figure, moving with the easy
gait of one whose feet have trodden many decks, climbs the companion-way
and comes forward in leisurely fashion. The fellow is no stranger;
already, as I came on board, I had a glimpse of that grizzled, masterful
jaw and keen eyes. He peers past me towards his mate.</p>
                <p>"Elf!"</p>
                <p>"Yuss?"</p>
                <p>"Seed anyfink o' young 'Arry lately?'</p>
                <p>"Not me!"</p>
                <p>"Well, I 'ear 'e done a bit in the lead-slingin' line at a place
called Wipers, an' they've been an' stuck some sort o' French medal on
'is chest."</p>
                <p>"Blighter owes me fourpence, anyway," roars Elf; and I infer that
neither of them has a high opinion of 'Arry's character from the
civilian point of view.</p>
                <p>Follows an interval filled with small confused sounds—the
staccato note of a bell, the soft thud of a passenger's body as he is
jerked unexpectedly against the rail, the picturesque ripple of his
expostulations with Providence.</p>
                <p>A lamp, burning with unusual and illegal garishness, gives me light
enough to examine my watch. It indicates the proximity of midnight. I
realize that I am incredibly stiff and cold, and am tormented by visions
of unattainable comforts.</p>
                <p>At last I am conscious of a line of dimmed lights, of a distant roar
of escaping steam, of a violent quivering motion that indicates the
slackening of speed. We come to a sudden halt. The voice of Elf rises
triumphant.</p>
                <p>"Bill!"</p>
                <p>"Yuss?"</p>
                <p>"Two minutes arter!"</p>
                <p>"Knowed we'd do it!"</p>
                <p>And as I stumble blindly forth it is borne upon me that the last
Ealing motor-bus has ended her journey with five minutes to spare.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>"Egypt is placidly awaiting the event, with the absolute conviction
    that the Turks and Germans will get the boating of their lives in
    the Sinai Desert."—<title>Civil and Military Gazette.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>They certainly won't get it on the Suez Canal.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb n=" 123"/>
                <p>
                    <graphic url="images/i-123.png"/>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <title>Nervous Young Officer</title> (<title>to 'bus conductor</title>).
"<hi rend="sc">First Single to Oxford Circus</hi>."</p>
                <p>[The authorities have recommended that officers should travel
first-class.]</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1126" type="div2">
                <head>A MODEST SUGGESTION FOR A
NEW HUNNISH CANTICLE.</head>
                <p rend="center">
                    <hi rend="sc">"Kaiser Wants New National Hymn."</hi>
                    <lb/>
"<title>Westminster Gazette</title>" <title>Heading.</title>
                </p>
                <p>"He shall have it."—<title>Mr. Punch.</title>
                </p>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>
                            <hi rend="sc">God</hi> of our Fathers, God of old,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">  Who hast for us such sympathy,</l>
                        <l>Cast as Thou art in German mould,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">  Again we raise our voice to Thee:</l>
                        <l>Omnipotence, we need Thy hand</l>
                        <l>In air, on sea, canal and land!</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>The English (who, Thou knowest, hide</l>
                        <l rend="i2">  Contemptibly upon an isle)</l>
                        <l>No doubt on Thee have also cried,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">  According to their native guile;</l>
                        <l>Presumption could no further go</l>
                        <l>In those who plunged the world in woe.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Thou wouldst not hearken to a race</l>
                        <l rend="i2">  Possessed of that inhuman Fleet,</l>
                        <l>So cruel, arrogant and base,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">  So steeped in rancour and deceit.</l>
                        <l>'Twas they, remember, they alone,</l>
                        <l>Who forced this Burden on Thine own!</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Bless, rather, us! our arms! our cause!</l>
                        <l rend="i2">  Pour on us Thy protecting love!</l>
                        <l>Sanction our fractures of Thy laws,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">  By U,s beneath, by Zeps above!</l>
                        <l>Relieve us in this dark impasse;</l>
                        <l>Bless all our efforts; bless our gas!</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Deal gently with us should we tend—</l>
                        <l rend="i2">  Presuming as Thy favoured Race,</l>
                        <l>All flushed to own so great a Friend—</l>
                        <l rend="i2">  To dereliction into grace!</l>
                        <l>Deal gently with us, Lord, should we</l>
                        <l>Once deviate to decency!</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>And Him, from Whom such blessings flow,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">  Our <hi rend="sc">Wilhelm</hi>, first of Sons of Light,</l>
                        <l>Whose one ambition is to show</l>
                        <l rend="i2">  Mankind the rightfulness of Might;</l>
                        <l>Bless Him, and forward His device</l>
                        <l>To make an Earthly Paradise!</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>And should some other star up there</l>
                        <l rend="i2">  (For all the stellar space is Thine)</l>
                        <l>Demand Thy more immediate care,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">  And thus divert Thee from the Rhine,</l>
                        <l>Thou need'st but mention it, and He</l>
                        <l>Thy Viceroy hero will gladly be!</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e1315" type="div3">
                    <head>"WANT OF FOOD.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p rend="right">Salonika.</p>
                        <p>On returning to Salonika after an absence of a month, I find the
    situation much relieved as a result of the deportation of the enemy
    Consuls and the energetic measures adopted to clear the town of the
    numerous pies previously infesting it."—<title>Provincial
    Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>The headline seems justified.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>"I bought a brochure, which explained that the Emperor was not
    physically ill, but his metal condition was upset owing to the war."
  </p>
                        <p rend="right">
                            <title>Evening Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Another allusion, we suppose, to the depreciation of the Mark.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>"Lord Crewe and Lord Lansdowne have addressed the following Whip to
    the members of the House of Lords: On February 15 an address will be
    moved in the House of Lords in answer to His Majesty's Speech. We
    venture to express the hope that Your Majesty will find it possible
    to attend in your place on that day."—<title>Yorkshire Evening
    Post.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>We have heard of the Sovereign People, but the Sovereign Peers are
new to us.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>"In the course of the match, Brelsford, the United half-back, and
    Glennon, the Wednesday forward, were ordered off the field for
    fighting. Upwards of 16,000 spectators witnessed the
    match."—<title>Birmingham Post.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Mr. Punch will gladly furnish any of the players, or eligibles
amongst the 16,000 spectators, with the address of a field where
fighters will certainly not be "ordered off."</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1382" type="div3">
                    <head>"ANIMALS AND ZEPPELIN NOISES.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
                            <hi rend="sc">Sir</hi>,—The dat is affected by all
    sounds, according to its weakness or its strength."
  </p>
                        <p rend="right">
                            <title>Morning Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>We have often noticed the same thing about the cog.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>"<hi rend="sc">Typist</hi> and Shorthand
    Clerk.—Required at once for invoicing a young lady, accustomed
    to the drapery trade preferred."
  </p>
                        <p rend="right">
                            <title>Daily Chronicle.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Not an easy post. Some young ladies are so unaccountable.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>"Washington, Jany. 17.—Mrs. Emmeline Pankhurst the
    suffragette leader now under parole in New York will be formally
    admitted to the United States soon after her papers reach
    Washington. President Wilson is opposed to her
    execution."—<title>Bermuda Colonist.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>A merciful man, this <hi rend="sc">Wilson.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb n=" 124"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1446" type="div2">
                <head>A CONTROVERSY.</head>
                <p rend="center">(<title>From Our Own Correspondent in America.</title>)</p>
                <p rend="center">I.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="sc">Yesterday</hi>
President <hi rend="sc">Wilson</hi> addressed a monster
gathering of business men at Ponkapog. He said that it was a cruel
misconception to hold that Americans were without ideals. As a matter of
fact they cherished their ideals far beyond any question of making money
and would die rather than submit to acts which were an outrage on our
common humanity. In declaring that there was such a thing as being too
proud to fight he had, of course, meant that there was such a thing as
being only too proud to fight for what was just and right. This was the
American attitude, and he therefore advocated national preparedness
which might possibly imply such an increase in America's naval and
military forces as few people except himself had yet dreamt of. At this
point the audience rose <title>en masse</title> and cheered for ten minutes.
Nothing could show more clearly than this speech how intensely critical
are the relations between America and Germany over the <title>Lusitania</title>
case. There has been a wild panic on the New York Stock Exchange. A
prominent banker has expressed the opinion that
Count <hi rend="sc">Bernstorff</hi> will receive his passports
to-morrow</p>
                <p rend="center">II.</p>
                <p>Count <hi rend="sc">Bernstorff</hi> has not called on
Mr. <hi rend="sc">Lansing</hi> to-day. This is considered a
symptom of the utmost gravity, and the exchange value of the German mark
has receded ten points.</p>
                <p rend="center">III.</p>
                <p>Count <hi rend="sc">Bernstorff</hi> was closeted with
Mr. <hi rend="sc">Lansing</hi> for two hours this afternoon.
Relations are evidently strained to a very dangerous point, and the
worst is feared.</p>
                <p rend="center">IV.</p>
                <p>The situation has appreciably improved, and the controversy has been
narrowed down to the use or omission of the word "illegality." The
American Government insist that Germany should admit the illegality of
the torpedoing of the <title>Lusitania</title>, but for this Germany is not yet
prepared, though she is willing to make a formal expression of regret at
the death of American citizens, whom, she is ready to declare, she did
not intend to destroy. Colonel <hi rend="sc">Roosevelt</hi>
spoke last night at the dinner of the Associated Progressive
Manufacturers. He said no touch of infancy or feebleness had been
omitted by the present Administration in their conduct of negotiations
with Germany. They had performed the miracle of causing every true
American to blush for his country. When you met a rattlesnake you didn't
waste time in arguing with it or flattering it. Your duty was to shoot
it or knock it on the head, or, preferably, to employ both methods in
order to rid the world of a danger. At this vigorous denunciation the
whole audience rose and cheered for a quarter of an hour.</p>
                <p rend="center">V.</p>
                <p>The situation is easier. Count <hi rend="sc">Bernstorff</hi>
has declared in an interview that the German Government is prepared to
accept the American formula if the word "legality" be substituted for
the word "illegality." Germany would thus admit the legality of the
torpedoing of the <title>Lusitania</title> and express regret at the death of
American citizens. Count <hi rend="sc">Bernstorff</hi> points
out that Germany has thus gone very far towards meeting the American
demand. He hopes and believes that two great civilized nations will not
fall out over so small a matter as the use or omission of the two
letters <hi rend="it">i</hi>,<hi rend="it">l</hi>, at the beginning of a long word.</p>
                <p rend="center">VI.</p>
                <p>Mr. <hi rend="sc">Lansing</hi> has in a polite note expressed
himself unable to accept Count <hi rend="sc">Bernstorff's</hi>
offer as a full satisfaction of America's demands. The sands are
evidently running out, and there is serious danger of the negotiations
proving abortive. In the meantime a sharp Note has been addressed to
England in regard to her interference with American commerce. Six
munition works were yesterday blown up. The outrage is attributed to
Germans. President <hi rend="sc">Wilson</hi> is carefully
considering his action.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>
                    <graphic url="images/i-124.png"/>
                </p>
                <div xml:id="d1e1558" type="div3">
                    <head>THE ARMLET IN BORRIBODABOO.</head>
                    <p>
                        <title>The Old Man.</title> "<hi rend="sc">This hot spell makes me glad that I'm
too old to attest</hi>."</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <div xml:id="d1e1572" type="div3">
                        <head>The "Lusitania" Crisis.</head>
                        <quote>
                            <p>"The Vienna Correspondence Bureau emphasises the gravity of the
    situation, and says that the negotiations are interrupted. This
    interruption, it is added, is as it came from the cow."
  </p>
                            <p rend="right">
                                <title>Yorkshire Post.</title>
                            </p>
                        </quote>
                        <p>Not, as you might have expected, from
the <hi rend="sc">Wolff</hi>.</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <quote>
                            <p>"To prevent the eyes watering when peeling onions, let the tap drip
    on them. This keeps the fumes from rising, and if wanted for frying
    they can easily be dried in a cloth afterwards." —<title>The
    Matron.</title>
                            </p>
                        </quote>
                        <p>Thanks, but we hardly ever want to fry our eyes.</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <quote>
                            <p>"The Primate had the novel and undesirable experience of being
    shelled by the enemy, one shell in fact bursting within twenty-five
    yards of him. The arrangements for this part of his visit were
    mostly made by the Rev. ——, C.F."—<title>Northern
    Whig.</title>
                            </p>
                        </quote>
                        <p>Humorous fellows, these Army chaplains.</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <quote>
                            <p>"<hi rend="sc">For Sale.</hi>—Imported, fresh arrival
    of Japanese Poodles, very handsome, with a long silken hair, smart,
    and pick up anything taught. Rs. 200 per pair."—<title>Times of
    India.</title>
                            </p>
                        </quote>
                        <p>"And beauty draws us with a single hair."</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <quote>
                            <p>"What would he say to a chemist who could not translate a common
    tag—for example, rem tetigisti acer?"—<title>Morning
    Paper.</title>
                            </p>
                        </quote>
                        <p>We give it up, like the chemist.</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <quote>
                            <p>"<hi rend="sc">General</hi> (good, refined) for modern
    non-basement clergyman's house."—<title>Daily Chronicle.</title>
                            </p>
                        </quote>
                        <p>The reverend gentleman does not mention his ecclesiastical views; but
we gather that he is not an Arian.</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <pb n=" 125"/>
                        <p>
                            <graphic url="images/i-125.png"/>
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div xml:id="d1e1683" type="div3">
                        <head>OUR VILLAGE ENTERTAINMENT.</head>
                        <p>
                            <title>Boy</title> (<hi rend="it">explaining</hi>). "<hi rend="sc">You see, Auntie, the feller that's
going out has got a grudge against the other chap</hi>."</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1699" type="div2">
                    <head>RAILWAY RHYMES.</head>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>
                                <hi rend="sc">When</hi> books are pow'rless to beguile</l>
                            <l>And papers only stir my bile,</l>
                            <l>For solace and relief I flee</l>
                            <l>To <title>Bradshaw</title> or the <title>A. B. C.</title>,</l>
                            <l>And find the best of recreations</l>
                            <l>In studying the names of stations.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>There is not much among the <title>A</title>'s</l>
                            <l>To prompt enthusiastic praise,</l>
                            <l>But <title>B</title> is infinitely better,</l>
                            <l>And there are gems in ev'ry letter.</l>
                            <l>The only fault I have with Barnack</l>
                            <l>Is that it rhymes with Dr. <hi rend="sc">Harnack</hi>;</l>
                            <l>Barbon, Beluncle Halt, Bodorgan</l>
                            <l>Resound like chords upon the organ,</l>
                            <l>And there's a spirit blithe and merry</l>
                            <l>In Evercreech and Egloskerry.</l>
                            <l>Park Drain and Counter Drain, I'm sure,</l>
                            <l>Are hygienically pure,</l>
                            <l>But when æsthetically viewed</l>
                            <l>They seem to me a little crude.</l>
                            <l>I often long to visit Frant,</l>
                            <l>Hose, Little Kimble and Lelant;</l>
                            <l>And, if I had sufficient dollars,</l>
                            <l>Sibley's (for Chickney) and Neen Sollars;</l>
                            <l>Shustoke and Smeeth my soul arride</l>
                            <l>And likewise Sholing, Sole Street, Shide,</l>
                            <l>But I'm afraid my speech might go</l>
                            <l>Awry on reaching Spooner Row.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>In serious mood I often bend</l>
                            <l>My thoughts to Ponder and his End,</l>
                            <l>And when I'm feeling dull and down</l>
                            <l>The very name of Tibshelf Town</l>
                            <l>Rejoices me, while Par and Praze</l>
                            <l>And Pylle and Quy promote amaze.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>Of all the Straths, a numerous host,</l>
                            <l>Strathbungo pleases me the most,</l>
                            <l>While I can court reluctant slumber</l>
                            <l>By murmuring thy name, Stogumber.</l>
                            <l>Were I beginning life anew</l>
                            <l>From Swadlincote I'd take my cue,</l>
                            <l>But shun as I would shun the scurvy</l>
                            <l>The perilous atmosphere of Turvey.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>But though the tuneful name of Horbling</l>
                            <l>Incites to further doggerel warbling,</l>
                            <l>And Gallions, Goonbell, Gamlingay</l>
                            <l>Are each deserving of a lay,</l>
                            <l>No railway bard is worth his salt</l>
                            <l>Who cannot bear to call a "Halt."</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <div xml:id="d1e1890" type="div3">
                        <head>Encouraging.</head>
                        <quote>
                            <p>"<hi rend="sc">Wanted, Girl</hi>; farmhouse; last lived two
    years."—<title>Devon and Exeter Gazette.</title>
                            </p>
                        </quote>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    </div>
                    <div xml:id="d1e1907" type="div3">
                        <head>The Pinch of War.</head>
                        <quote>
                            <p>"Mr. —— is having his first show of well-known English
    Corsets, made specially for him."—<title>Provincial Paper.</title>
                            </p>
                        </quote>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    </div>
                    <div xml:id="d1e1921" type="div3">
                        <head>Getting Off Cheaply.</head>
                        <quote>
                            <p>"Mark then explained to the police that they had been 'had.' He was
    promptly arrested for falsely representing himself as a deserter and
    to-day was fined 0s."
  </p>
                            <p rend="right">
                                <title>Evening Paper.</title>
                            </p>
                        </quote>
                        <p>Judging by the small value attached to him he might have been the
German mark.</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <quote>
                            <p>"<hi rend="sc">Lost</hi>, in Annfield, Newhaven, boy's
    bicycle (three-wheeled); if found in any person's possession after
    this date will be prosecuted."
  </p>
                            <p rend="right">
                                <title>Edinburgh Evening News.</title>
                            </p>
                        </quote>
                        <p>For unlawful acquisition of the extra wheel, we presume.</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <p>From a shop-girl's account of the great War:—</p>
                        <quote>
                            <p>"I shall never forget the Saturday before that Bank Holiday if I
    live till I draw my last breath."—<title>Daily Mirror.</title>
                            </p>
                        </quote>
                        <p>She ought to have a fair chance of this.</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <quote>
                            <p>"Sir Edward Grey has all manner of fine and beautiful ideals to
    which we lay no claim. But the fairy step-mother who was so prodigal
    over his cradle yet denied him one gift."</p>
                        </quote>
                        <p rend="right">
                            <title>Morning Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                        <p>Still, it takes an exceptional man to have a step-mother at birth,
fairy or other.</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <pb n=" 126"/>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e2000" type="div2">
                    <head>AT THE PLAY.</head>
                    <p rend="sc">"Caroline."</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="sc">A baby</hi>, did he but know it, is only happy
reaching out from the bath for the soap. When he gets it, lo! it is mere
froth and bitterness. That, roughly, is
Mr. <hi rend="sc">Maugham's</hi> idea in <title>Caroline</title>.</p>
                    <p>If you are to love a woman, for heaven's sake, says he, take care
that she be safe bound beyond your reach. All attainment is dead-sea
fruit. But how is anyone to believe this depressing sort of doctrine
when the woman in question is such an engaging divinity as
his <title>Caroline Ashley</title>, interpreted by
Miss <hi rend="sc">Irene Vanbrugh</hi> at the very top of her
form? The doctrine, indeed, may be hanged for the nefarious half-truth
it is; but this would still leave you free to appreciate one of the most
brilliant and finished pieces of work which
Mr. <hi rend="sc">Maugham</hi> has yet done for the stage. True,
it is merely an airy trifle; but it is almost perfect of its kind.</p>
                    <p>The action opens on the morning of the announcement in <title>The
Times</title> of the death of <title>Caroline's</title> extremely difficult husband,
who has long been a wanderer seeking spirituous consolations in
out-of-the-way places of the earth. <title>Robert Oldham</title>, a quite
delightful barrister (Mr. <hi rend="sc">Leonard Boyne</hi>; so
you will understand the "delightful"), has worshipped <title>Caroline</title>
with an honourable fidelity for ten years, waiting patiently for the day
on which she shall be free. Well, here is the long-desired day.
Affectionate, officious friends come to congratulate each of the pair
before they meet, and each confesses to a curious chilling sense of
dread. When the embarrassing moment of the <title>téte-à-téte</title>
arrives, <title>Robert</title>, obviously ill-at-ease and apparently more as a
matter of duty than of eager conviction, suggests that <title>Caroline</title>
shall name the day. She gives him a blank refusal. Both affect dismay at
this queer ending of their long-deferred hopes, but eventually confess,
mid peals of their own happy laughter, their actual relief. So ends the
first chapter.</p>
                    <p>
                        <graphic url="images/i-126.png"/>
                    </p>
                    <div xml:id="d1e2065" type="div3">
                        <head>BLIGHTED TROTH.</head>
                        <p>
                            <title>Caroline Ashley</title> …… Miss <hi rend="sc">Irene Vanbrugh</hi>.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Robert Oldham</title> ……  Mr. <hi rend="sc">Leonard Boyne</hi>.</p>
                        <p>A later hour of the same day finds our heroine on her sofa, languid
from the morning's emotions, and indulging in the luxury of not feeling
at all well. Her world is crumbling. She cannot do without a slave,
and <title>Robert</title> can no longer fill quite the old <title>rôle</title>. Clearly
a matter for counsel with her physician and friend, <title>Dr. Cornish</title>
(Mr. <hi rend="sc">Dion Boucicault</hi>), who pleasantly
diagnoses middle-age and prescribes a young adorer, than which no advice
could be more nicely calculated to restore her lost feeling of queenly
complacency. She sends for young <title>Rex Cunningham</title>
(Mr. <hi rend="sc">Martin Lewis</hi>), a morbid egoist, who
nourishes a hopeless passion for her (and others), being well aware of
the paramount claims of <title>Robert</title>. She contrives to let him know
that she is free, and the youth, whose pet hobby is hopeless passion, at
once sheers off in alarm. <title>Caroline</title> is learning—is beginning
to understand the dark philosophy of Mr. <hi rend="sc">Somerset
Maugham</hi>. In despair she again turns to <title>Robert</title>. They become
engaged and promptly begin quarrelling about their houses. He objects to
her Futurist bathroom; she to his, which is so like a tube station that
she would bathe in constant apprehension of the sudden appearance of a
young man demanding tickets. <title>Robert</title> begins to assert his
masculine rights to control these and sundry matters. She realises (oh,
venerable gag of the cynics!) that the fetters which would unite their
bodies would put a barrier between their souls. The engagement is by
mutual consent declared off.</p>
                        <p>Realising, however, in Chapter III., that she needs <title>Robert's</title>
devotion more than anything else, she conceives a plot. <title>Dr.
Cornish</title> makes an opportune call, not this time as a doctor, but as a
whole-hearted admirer. With just such an one for my husband, thinks
<title>Caroline</title>, <title>Robert</title> could again assume his accustomed part of
loyal friend and incense-bearer. She accordingly proposes. Appreciating
the difficulty of directly refusing without discourtesy, he temporises
and appears to fall in with her suggestion that he shall announce their
engagement to <title>Robert</title> and her interfering friends, who are
promptly telephoned for to hear an interesting statement.
But <title>Cornish</title> proves himself a <hi rend="sc">Wolff</hi> in sheep's clothing.
Instead of announcing the engagement he asserts that he has just
seen <title>Stephen Ashley</title>, the husband: a lie which obtains credence
with the others because of the dead man's amiable habit of occasionally
putting about a rumour of his decease. <title>Caroline</title>, with superb
presence of mind, seeing a glorious way out of a dilemma, adopts the
lie, contrives a more or less plausible explanation, and thus
establishes the <title>status quo ante</title>—the grass widow with the
faithful and contented adorer.</p>
                        <p>The play, whose only flaw was a certain rather upsetting ambiguity
(whether accidental or designed I could not quite gather) in the last
few sentences before the curtain fell, was interpreted with a very fine
intelligence. Miss <hi rend="sc">Irene Vanbrugh's</hi> superbly
trained talent showed itself in an astonishing range of moods tethered
in a plausible unity of conception.
Mr. <hi rend="sc">Boyne</hi>, who is just coming into his own,
scored bull after bull. Perhaps he didn't make <title>Oldham</title> quite the
Englishman that the author (I should say) designed, but rather an
Irishman of that delightfully faint flavour which is so entirely
attractive. Miss <hi rend="sc">Lillah Macarthy</hi>, as <title>Maude
Fulton</title>, a well-preserved bachelor in the most bizarre modern mode,
also a dexterous liar and officious matchmaker, played with her head in
her most accomplished manner and gave full value in the general scheme
to a character which the author made a person when he might have been
content with a peg. Mr. <hi rend="sc">Dion Boucicault's</hi>
physician was as bland a humbug as ever coined guineas in Mayfair. Mr.
<hi rend="sc">Martin Lewis</hi>, as a profoundly silly ass, played a difficult
hand without fault. Miss <hi rend="sc">Nina Sevening</hi>, as a consoler of
handsome men in trouble, and Miss <hi rend="sc">Florence Lloyd</hi>,
as <title>Caroline's</title> maid, competently rounded off in subsidiary
<title>rôles</title> the work of the principals.</p>
                        <p>Yes, undoubtedly a brilliant performance.</p>
                        <p rend="right">T.</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <pb n=" 127"/>
                        <p>
                            <graphic url="images/i-127.png"/>
                        </p>
                        <p rend="sc">
                            <title>Huntsman.</title> "Give us a bit o' room! You was nearly in my pocket that time."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Flat-race Jockey.</title> "Room? Why, I was nearly half a length behind you."</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    </div>
                    <div xml:id="d1e2226" type="div2">
                        <head>OUR BOOKING-OFFICE.</head>
                        <p rend="center">(<title>By Mr. Punch's Staff of Learned Clerics.</title>)</p>
                        <p>
                            <hi rend="sc">The</hi> evolution of the long novel appears to
be following that of the human race. Instead of the individual, the
family now threatens to become the central unit. I confess that this
prospect, as evidenced by <title>Three Pretty Men</title>
(<hi rend="sc">Methuen</hi>), fills me with some just
apprehension. Mr.
<hi rend="sc">Gilbert Cannan</hi> has set out to tell how a Scotch family,
three brothers, a mother, and some sisters in the background,
determines to make its fortune in a South Lancashire
city (very recognisable under the name of <title>Thrigsby</title>),
and how eventually all but one of them succeed. It is a
long book and a close; and the dialogue (which of its
kind is good dialogue, crisp and illuminating), being printed
without the usual spacing, produces an indigestible-looking
page that might well alarm a reader out for enjoyment.
The book, in its record of the progress of the three,
<title>Jamie</title> and <title>Tom</title> and <title>John</title>, is really more a study of social
conditions in mid-Victorian Manchester than a work of
imagination. But there is clever character-drawing in
it, especially in <title>Jamie</title>, who from a worldly point of view
is the failure of the group, making no money, and drifting
through journalism to emigration; and in the finely
suggested figure of <title>Tibby</title>, the ill-favoured kitchen drudge,
who is his real centre of inspiration. But first and last
it remains a dull business, partly from an entire lack of
humour, partly from the absence of any settled plan that
might help one to endure the dreariness of the setting. Mr.
<hi rend="sc">Cannan</hi> certainly knows his subject, and few novels indeed
have given me, rightly or wrongly, a greater suggestion of
autobiography. But for once the art of being exhaustive
without being exhausting seems to have eluded him.</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <p>If you want really to get a picture of war as she is waged by an
obscure unit in the thick of the dirtiest, dampest and most depressing
part, read <hi rend="sc">Patrick MacGill's</hi>
                            <title>The Red Horizon</title> (<hi rend="sc">Jenkins</hi>). Here we meet the author of
<title>The Children of the Dead End</title> and <title>The Rat Pit</title> as Rifleman
3008 of the London Irish, involved in the grim routine of
the firing line—reliefs, diggings and repairs, sentry-go's,
stand-to's, reserves, working and covering parties, billets;
and so <title>da capo</title>. With a rare artistic intuition, instead of
diffusing his effects in a riot of general impressions, he has
confined himself to a record of the doings of his section,
and I have read nothing that gives anything near so
convincing an impression of the truth, at once splendid and
bitter. It is a privilege to be shown, through the medium
of an imaginative temperament, the fine comradeship of
the trenches, the heroism that shines through the haunting
fear of death, mostly conquered with a laugh, but sometimes
frankly expressed in the pathetic desire for a
"blighty" wound—a wound just serious enough to send the
envied hero home. You won't get much of the Romance
of War out of this strong piece of work, except the jolly
sort of romance of the little Cockney, <title>Bill</title>, who, when the
regiment in reserve was crouching in the trench under
heavy shelling, cheered it by delivering himself characteristically
as follows: "If I kick the bucket don't put a
cross with ''E died for 'is King and Country' over me. A
bully beef tin at my 'ead will do, and—' 'E died doin'
fatigues on an empty stomach.'"</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <pb n=" 128"/>
                        <p>If you were the hero of a novel, the only possible mate for the
heroine, and, in short, taking you all round, an important sort of
person, would you not consider yourself hardly treated if you were not
allowed to make the girl's acquaintance till page 311, when you knew
there were to be only three hundred and thirty-two pages in the book? I
disagree entirely with <title>Roger Quinn</title>, in
Miss <hi rend="sc">Beatrice Kelston's</hi>
                            <title>The Blows of
Circumstance</title> (<hi rend="sc">Long</hi>), when, reviewing the
affair, he writes to a friend: "It's amazing that we fell short of
perfect understanding." My opinion is that <title>Roger</title> did extremely
well in the little time he was given. Of course he had conducted the
case for the Crown when she was in the dock, charged with murder, and
that formed a sort of bond between them; but even so I don't see how he
could have got much nearer to a complete understanding, considering that
the girl dashed off and committed suicide almost before he could get a
word in. If my enjoyment of <title>The Blows of Circumstance</title> waned
towards the end and the book seemed to me to lose grip, it was because
the sudden discovery on the part of <title>Quinn</title> and <title>Amalie Gayne</title>
that they were soul-mates was too sudden to convince me. Up to the
beginning of the trial the story has vigour and an air of probability,
with its careful building-up of <title>Amalie's</title> curious character and
the vivid description of her life on the stage and off it in the society
of a drug-taking husband; but from that point on it seemed to me to
fail. In real life all might have happened just as it is set down, but
real life is sloppily constructed. A novel must obey more rigid rules.
Miss <hi rend="sc">Kelston</hi> writes extremely well, if a
trifle too gloomily for my personal taste, but she cannot afford to
ignore the laws of construction and hurl her big situation at the reader
with an abrupt "Take it or leave it!"</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <lg>
                            <lg>
                                <l>For <title>Thirteen Stories</title> I've nought but praise,</l>
                                <l rend="i2">  Although you'll find when you overhaul them</l>
                                <l>They're best described, in the author's phrase,</l>
                                <l rend="i2">  As "sketches, studies or what do you call them?"</l>
                            </lg>
                            <lg>
                                <l>Per <hi rend="sc">Duckworth</hi> forward and back you trek;</l>
                                <l rend="i2">  You may book right through or choose between a</l>
                                <l>Peep at Perim or Chapultepec,</l>
                                <l rend="i2">  Sahara, Hampstead or Argentina.</l>
                            </lg>
                            <lg>
                                <l>You may halt, if you will, at phalansteries,</l>
                                <l rend="i2">  Where Mescaleros on maturangos</l>
                                <l>Eat or drink (whichever it is)</l>
                                <l rend="i2">  Baked tortillas and twang changangos.</l>
                            </lg>
                            <lg>
                                <l>Suchlike things come easy as pie</l>
                                <l rend="i2">  To the author, Mr. <hi rend="sc">Cunninghame Graham</hi>,</l>
                                <l>And I quite like 'em so long as I</l>
                                <l rend="i2">  Have only to read and not to say 'em.</l>
                            </lg>
                        </lg>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <p>If 'tis love that makes the world go round, it is certainly the same
force that maintains the circulation of the libraries. So it is safe to
assume that such a title as <title>The Little Blind God</title>
(<hi rend="sc">Melrose</hi>) is itself enough to preserve the
volume that bears it from any wallflower existence on the less
frequented shelves. But as for the story to which
Miss <hi rend="sc">Anne Weaver</hi> has given this attractive
name I find it very difficult to say anything, good or bad. Only once
did its placid unfolding cause me any emotion, even the mildest.
Old <title>Lady Conyers</title> had adopted as companion one <title>Mistress Barbara
Cardeen</title> (need I interpolate that the time is the eighteenth century?
O brocade and lavender! O swords and candle-light and general tushery!),
whom she found playing a violin in the streets of Bath—I should
say <hi rend="it">the</hi> Bath; let us above all things be atmospheric! As her
ladyship had a most eligible son, and as <title>Barbara</title>—the
chit!—naturally hadn't a guinea, I own I was slightly astonished
to find the dowager positively hurling the young couple at each other's
heads. However, doubtless <title>Lady Conyers</title>, as herself a
novel-reader, knew that the thing was inevitable anyway. But before this
there were of course the misunderstandings. <title>Mistress Barbara</title> had,
in the violin days, a half-brother and this gentleman very obligingly
turns up <hi rend="it">incognito</hi> at Conyers End, and even goes to the expense
of hiring rooms in a cottage on the estate, for no other purpose in life
than that his conspicuously clandestine meetings with the
fair <title>Barbara</title> should be misconstrued as an assignation. Ha! out,
rapiers! and let us be ready for the moment when <title>Barbara</title>, rushing
between the combatants, receives in her own bosom the blade intended
for——, etc. But of course not enough blade to endanger the
happy ending. So there you are. A placid, undistinguished tale, that may
be commended as nourishment or soporific according to the taste and
fancy of the reader.</p>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <p>
                            <graphic url="images/i-128.png"/>
                        </p>
                        <div xml:id="d1e2465" type="div3">
                            <head>ANOTHER EXAMPLE OF PRUSSIAN EFFRONTERY.</head>
                            <p>
                                <title>Officer of Zeppelin</title> (<title>in perfect English.</title>)
"<hi rend="sc">Would you kindly direct me to the War
Office</hi>?"
</p>
                            <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                            <div xml:id="d1e2482" type="div3">
                                <head>An Optimist.</head>
                                <quote>
                                    <p>"Gentlewoman, bright, owing to War, offers Companionship in Return
    for hospitality, laundry, and travelling expenses."
  </p>
                                    <p rend="right">
                                        <title>Morning Paper.</title>
                                    </p>
                                </quote>
                                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                                <quote>
                                    <p>"An attack on the compulsory vice bill now before the House of
    Lords was made by the president of the conference, William C.
    Anderson."—<title>New York Globe.</title>
                                    </p>
                                </quote>
                                <p>Our American contemporary is misinformed. The measure in question
seeks to make virtue compulsory—the virtue of patriotism.</p>
                                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                                <quote>
                                    <p>"The following French official communiqué was issued this
    afternoon:—3.25.—Bouton Rouge 1, Dordogne 2, Kitch 3.
    Eight ran."— <title>Evening Times and Echo.</title>
                                    </p>
                                </quote>
                                <p>We are sorry that <hi rend="sc">K. of K.</hi> didn't do
better.</p>
                            </div>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>