<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Punch, or the London Charivari, Vol. 150, May 3, 1916</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <idno type="gutenberg">22941</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>This text is freely available for re-use under US and UK law, consult
                            your local legal restrictions if elsewhere.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This text is a TEI version of a Project Gutenberg text originally located at
                            <ptr target="http://www.gutenberg.org/dirs//////"/>. As per their license agreement we have removed
                        all references to the project's trademark, however have included this
                        pointer to the original in case you want the plain text, or their XHTML
                        version. </p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2008-06-27T16:13:37.786+01:00"/>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:id="d1e44" type="div2">
                <head>May 3, 1916.</head>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page289" n="pg 289"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e52" type="div2">
                <head>CHARIVARIA.</head>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">Sir Roger Casement</name>, it appears,
landed in Ireland from a collapsible
boat. And by a strange coincidence
his arrival synchronised with the outbreak
of a collapsible rebellion.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Hard soap can now be obtained in
Germany only by those who purchase
bread tickets. The soft variety cannot
be obtained at all, the whole supply, it
seems, having been commandeered by
the Imperial Government for export to
the United States.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>£175 worth of radium was lost last
week in Dundee.  The ease with
which bar radium can be melted
down and remoulded in the form of
cheap jewellery affords, according to
the local police, a clear indication
that this was the work of thieves.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A conscientious objector has stated
that he had even given up fishing
on humanitarian grounds. We fear
that his fish stories may have caused
some fatal attacks of apoplexy among
his audiences.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>According to Sir <name rend="sc">Thomas Barlow</name>
"the importation of bananas has
had a far-reaching effect on the
digestion of our children." Only
last Monday week the importation
of six bananas had just that kind of
effect on the digestion of our own
dear little Percy.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Portugal has decided to expel
German sympathisers of whatever
nationality. Other clubs please copy.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>From the Eastern Counties comes
news that in last week's Zeppelin
raid twenty turnips were "completely
destroyed." And so the grim
work of starving England into submission
goes relentlessly on.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"That boy there," said the <name rend="sc">Lord
Mayor</name> at the Mansion House, in addressing
some children from an orphanage,
"can easily become a Lord Mayor."
Cases of this sort are really not hard
to diagnose when you are familiar with
the symptoms, and the <name rend="sc">Lord Mayor</name>
had, of course, noticed the hearty
manner in which the lad was attacking
his food.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The latest Shakspearean discovery
announced by Sir <name rend="sc">Sidney Lee</name> is that
the Bard was a successful man of
business; but the really nice people
who have lately taken him up have
resolved not to let the fact prejudice
them against him after all these years.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"Absence of the Polecat from Ireland"
is the title of a vigorous article
in the current number of <title>The Field</title>.
While agreeing in substance with the
writer, we cannot refrain from commenting
on this unexpected departure
of a peculiarly moderate organ from
its customary restraint in dealing with
the political questions of the day.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The Editor of <title>The Angler's News</title>
makes public the request that fishermen
will provide him with the particulars
of any exceptionally big fish
which they may catch. Strangely
enough he does not suggest that the
data should be accompanied, for purposes
of verification, by the fish themselves.
It is refreshing to know that
there is a man left here and there who
is not trying to make something out
of the War.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>One of the Zeppelins that recently
visited England dropped one hundred
bombs without causing a single casualty,
and a movement is on foot to present
the Commander with a pair of white
gloves.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"What I wish to show Mr. Norman,"
says Mr. G. K. <name rend="sc">Chesterton</name> in <title>The
New Witness</title>, "is that the fantastic
pursuit of the <foreign xml:lang="fr">idée fixe</foreign>... leads to a
<foreign xml:lang="lat">reductio ad absurdum</foreign>." One has often
had occasion to notice the rapidity with
which a young <foreign xml:lang="fr">idée fixe</foreign> will dart down
a convenient <foreign xml:lang="la">reductio ad absurdum</foreign>
when closely pursued.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A writer in the current number of
<title>The Fortnightly Review</title> has elaborated
the theory that the War can be won
without difficulty by breaking through
the German line in the West. It is
the ability to grasp these simple but
fundamental truths that distinguishes
the military genius from the War
Office hack.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The majority of the larger railways
have now announced their intention
of serving no more meals on trains.
While the reason has not been officially
stated the authorities are said to be of
the opinion that Zeppelins have on
several occasions been able to reach
important termini by following the
smell of cookery.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e179" type="div3">
                    <head>The Perils of the Tyne.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"A ship's apprentice who attempted the
rescue of a man in shark-infested waters
to-day, at Newcastle, received the Shipping
Federation's diploma and medal."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Morning Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e197" type="div3">
                    <head>The Infallible Experts.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"In general (continued Count Andrassy),
the battle has ceased to be of the nature
of a siege, as it was intended to be at the
beginning. It is a long-drawn-out and
deadly combat between the French and
German armies, and the victory of one
will undoubtedly be the defeat of the
other."—<title>Yorkshire Post.</title>
                        </p>
                        <p>"It is a reasonable conclusion from
these facts that ... the principal attack,
supposing that it should actually have
taken place, has already been made."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Col. <name rend="sc">Feyler</name> in "The Sunday Times."</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e224" type="div3">
                    <head>Delphinium Hybrids.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"What looks much handsomer than a
sow of Delphiniums in the borders of your
garden, and once planted they are always
there."—<title>Garden Work for Amateurs.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>The only drawback is that it is apt
to make such a litter.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Before we are through with it, we may be
obliged to have a war outright with Mexico,
because the Defacto Government is none too
friendly to us."—<title>Bournemouth Guardian.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>It is not perhaps generally known
that President Defacto is a direct
descendant of that well-known ruler,
Señor A. Priori.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Outside Dublin the county is tranquil.
Mr. Asquith, and three minor cases of disturbance
are reported."—<title>Evening News.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>We deprecate this attempt to import
political prejudice into the situation.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Two ladies obliged to remain in furnished
house, Bournemouth, till let, offer free weekly
accommodation to middle-aged healthy lady
and dog in difficulties through war."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>The Common Cause.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Even the pets are feeling the pinch of
the Common Cause.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e289" type="div3">
                    <head>THE DIVINER.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/289.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page290" n="pg 290"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e302" type="div2">
                <head>DRESS ECONOMY AND THE CLAIMS OF ART.</head>
                <quote type="note">To Lord <name rend="sc">Spencer</name> on seeing his portrait by Mr. <name rend="sc">Orpen</name> at the
Royal Academy.</quote>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Here, at the Press View, ere the opening day</l>
                        <l>Admits the public on receipt of pay</l>
                        <l rend="i2">And all the gallery like a murmurous shell hums,</l>
                        <l>I stand before your picture, awed and mute,</l>
                        <l>In reverent worship and an old, old suit</l>
                        <l rend="i4">Of baggy ante-bellums.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>For, when Britannia first in wrath arose,</l>
                        <l>I took a vow:—So long as these poor clo's</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Together, though reduced to just a mesh, hold,</l>
                        <l>Never will I, till Victory's trump rings clear</l>
                        <l>(Save when I purchase military gear),</l>
                        <l rend="i4">Cross any tailor's threshold.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Yet, gazing on the garb you figure in,</l>
                        <l>Shining and perfect as a new-born pin—</l>
                        <l rend="i2">The frock-coat built to dazzle gods and men, Sir,</l>
                        <l>The virgin tie, the collar passing tall,</l>
                        <l>The flawless crease of trousers which recall</l>
                        <l rend="i4">The prime of <name rend="sc">Bobby Spencer</name>—</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>I hesitate to blame your lack of thrift;</l>
                        <l>I would not have your sacred feelings biffed</l>
                        <l rend="i2">By harsh reflections from a patriot's war-pen;</l>
                        <l>Those rich externals which arrest the view</l>
                        <l>Were but adopted as essential to</l>
                        <l rend="i4">The scheme of Mr. <name rend="sc">Orpen</name>.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Such was the sacrifice you made to Art!</l>
                        <l>And there are other portraits, very smart—</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Sitters who must have borne the same hard trial;</l>
                        <l>Who waived their loyal taste for cheap attire</l>
                        <l>And went, superbly tailored, through the fire</l>
                        <l rend="i4">Of noble self-denial.</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <p>O. S.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e439" type="div2">
                <head>UNWRITTEN LETTERS TO THE KAISER.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e443" type="div3">
                    <head>No. XXXVIII.</head>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e447" type="div3">
                    <head>(<title>From General <name rend="sc">von Falkenhayn</name>.</title>)</head>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Almightiest War-Lord</name>,—See how the Fates make sport
with us! We began in February to make our great attack
upon the fortified position at Verdun. In ten days, so we
thought, our massed artillery, firing a ceaseless torrent of
projectiles, would have shattered beyond recovery the lines
of the enemy, and our irresistible infantry, breaking through
like a flood, would have swept away all opposition, and
would without doubt have taken the fortress and cleared
our way to Paris and to decisive victory. So we believed,
having, as it appeared, every reason for our belief, and
having taken into account in our careful planning all the
chances and vicissitudes to which men and battles are
exposed. And now May is come with her buds and blooms,
May, when, as your Majesty knows, the heart of every
good honest German turns to thoughts of beer-gardens and
draughts of foaming liquid, and so far as the capture of
Verdun and the opening of the road to Paris are concerned
we have done nothing that has any value except for our
foes, who have had the satisfaction of seeing us beat ourselves
to fragments against the steel wall of their defence.
It must be confessed that German blood and German
courage have been miserably wasted, and not even our
resources, great as they are, can much longer stand the
strain which has been imposed upon them.</p>
                    <p>Your Majesty asks me what under these circumstances
it is best to do. Shall we break off our attacks at Verdun
and direct our hammer-blows at some other part of the
front? Theoretically there is much to be said from the
purely military standpoint for such a course; but can your
Majesty foresee what the moral effect would be upon our
troops in the field and upon the Germans still left behind
us in Germany? We might, of course, announce that we
had now gained everything we had set out to gain, that
the French had lost immense numbers of killed and
wounded, that we had taken in unwounded prisoners the
equivalent of an army corps, that our booty was incalculable,
and that, in fact, the victory was definitely ours. But
would Germany believe this statement—<name rend="sc">Reventlow</name>, of
course, would believe it, but then he would believe anything—and
above all would the French believe it? I can
promise your Majesty that they would believe nothing of
the sort, and that they would give some excellent reasons
for their disbelief. And the result would be that we should
be held not only to have acknowledged our failure, but
also to have made ourselves ridiculous in the sight of the
whole world. That, I am certain, would be intolerable
for your Majesty and for the German people, who have
been fed upon a diet of victory, and would be beyond
measure disquieted by such an admission of failure as I
have mentioned. No, the only thing to do, now that we
have been so deeply involved, is to persist in the struggle
and hope that we may in the end wear out enemies who
have hitherto shown no signs of fatigue.</p>
                    <p>Fortunately it cannot be said that your Majesty is involved
in this lack of the success we all hoped for. Though
you are nominally the chief Commander of our Armies
it is known that in the actual operations your Majesty
has played the modest part of an onlooker rather than a
director. Formerly, that is before the breaking out of the
War, you were a great planner of plans, and it was understood
that, in case of war, you would lead your armies in
the field and prove that a Hohenzollern can do anything.
But now you have recognised your limitations, and no
Emperor can well do more than that. You do not now
thrust your advice upon your generals, whatever you may
have done at the outset of the War, and, though you may
once have dreamed of leading your hosts in a thundering
charge upon the foe, you have long since abandoned such
visions and have begun to realise that an Emperor is
but a man and cannot know everything. This, at least, is
my conviction, and I testify it to your Majesty with all the
bluntness that befits a soldier who has been honoured by
his Sovereign with a high command.</p>
                    <p>Most dutifully yours,   <name rend="sc">Von Falkenhayn</name>.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e480" type="div3">
                    <head>Good Hunting.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"The jungle sale held in Warrenpoint in aid of the Warrenpoint
District Nursing Association realised the sum of £40. 3s."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Northern Whig.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Young couple furnishing wishes to buy contents of 3 rooms,
including piano, or part of same."—<title>Edinburgh Evening News.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Their future neighbours are hoping that they will get one
without a keyboard.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"There is scarcely a family who have not someone near and dear to
them in the fighting line, and by substituting the task of knitting
for that of sewing, the well-known lines of Ibid are particularly
appropriate:—</p>
                        <lg>
                            <lg>
                                <l>'My tears must stop, for every drop</l>
                                <l>Hinders needle and thread.'"</l>
                            </lg>
                        </lg>
                        <p>
                            <title>York Herald.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>
                        <title>Ibid</title>, who is a close connection of that other voluminous
author, <title>Anon</title>, seems on this occasion to have plagiarized
from <name rend="sc">Hood</name>.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page291" n="pg 291"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/291.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page292" n="pg 292"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/292.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e570" type="div2">
                <head>ON THE SPY TRAIL.</head>
                <p>Jimmy's bloodhound, Faithful, had
his fortune told the other day—really,
I mean; not what the man next door
says when Faithful keeps on singing
to his cat at night from the bottom
of an apple-tree.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says the man next door often
has gloomy thoughts as to what will
happen to Faithful, and he gets up
from his warm bed to tell them to
him.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says Faithful was not expecting
to have his fortune told; he was
just sitting quietly on the wall
near the road, watching the day
go by.</p>
                <p>Everything was very nice and
quiet and peaceful; there was a
cat up each of three trees close by,
and a hen up another, all being
comfortable and quite all right
where they were, thank you, because
Faithful had inquired.</p>
                <p>The man next door was being
busy amongst his flowers; he was
replanting some that had been
planted right on the top of a place
where Faithful had laid down some
bones to mature.</p>
                <p>Things were so quiet that Jimmy
was just thinking about taking
his bloodhound on the spy trail,
when a woman came along with a
little hand-organ slung round her
neck and a cage containing two
small green parrots for telling your
fortune.</p>
                <p>Bloodhounds are very fond of
music, Jimmy says; they sing to
it, at least Faithful does. Jimmy
says Faithful lifted up his stomach
and threw back his head; but he
found it a little difficult to keep
time at first, because, you see, the
notes that were missing in the
organ were not the same ones that
were missing in Faithful's voice.
Jimmy says it is just the same
when two people singing a duet both
have hiccoughs; unless they hiccough
together you always notice something
wrong.</p>
                <p>The parrots were very clever; they
would come out of the cage and perch
on the end of a stick the woman held,
and then pick a small blue envelope
out of a box. Jimmy says that he
doesn't think the parrots had ever seen
a prize bloodhound like Faithful before,
not even in their native haunts, for
when Faithful tried to make a fuss of
them and love them they kept flying
about the cage and moulting their
feathers at him.</p>
                <p>Faithful picked up one of the feathers,
and when one of the parrots came out
of the cage to tell fortunes he tried to
put the feather back again. But the
parrot avoided him and went away.</p>
                <p>Faithful did his best to catch it again;
he has a very good nose for game,
Jimmy says, and he soon tracked the
parrot to its lair: it had joined the hen,
and the hen was being surprised—you
could hear it doing it, Jimmy says.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says Faithful sat at the
bottom of the tree and tried to look
like a birdcage; but his presence seemed
to disturb the woman so much that
Jimmy had to put the chain on him
and lead him away.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says Faithful kept yearning
to go back and help; he is a good
yearner, Jimmy says, and he does it
by pushing his head through the collar
as far as he can stretch it, and then
choking. Jimmy says the butcher is
a good yearner too, but he does it by
going red in the face and trying to burst
his collar with his neck. He did it at
Faithful this time. You see Faithful
was quietly passing his shop and doing
nothing at all to anyone—Jimmy had
only just let him loose on the trail—when
he caught sight of the butcher's
sandy cat lying curled up in the window
and going up and down at him with
her side. Jimmy says cats are always
doing something like that at his bloodhound,
and then what can you expect
if you will do it?</p>
                <p>There was a fly-paper on the counter,
and after old Faithful had driven the
cat into a corner Jimmy saw him suddenly
swing his tail at the fly-paper
and get firm hold of it; then he squatted
down on the counter and wagged the
fly-paper at the cat like anything to try
and mesmerise it. Jimmy says that
when the butcher came into the shop,
and Faithful stopped to turn round and
see where things were, the butcher
yearned at him like anything, and it
only made him worse when old Faithful
semaphored at him with the fly-paper.</p>
                <p>There was only a bluebottle on the
fly-paper besides Faithful, Jimmy
says, so that it wasn't very
crowded; but by the buzz the bluebottle
kept on making you would
think it owned the fly-paper. Jimmy
says his bloodhound had never
shared a fly-paper with a bluebottle
before, and he kept stopping
to answer the bluebottle back instead
of keeping to the spy trail.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says Faithful had just
sent an ultimatum to the bluebottle
when there came the sounds
of the hand-organ from a house
close by.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says as soon as Faithful
heard the music he seemed to
stiffen all at once and become
rigid.  He looked splendid like
that, Jimmy says. One paw up,
his tail as straight as he could get
it, and the fly-paper at half-mast—everything
pointing to sudden
death.</p>
                <p>Jimmy followed Faithful as hard
as he could, and was in time to
see him stalking quietly hand over
fist across a lawn while the woman
was getting one of the green
parrots on the end of the stick.</p>
                <p>Jimmy knew the man who lived
at the house, and who was having
his fortune told. He had come
there to live a tired life, Jimmy
says, and when the War broke out
he had put up a big flag-pole with a
Union Jack on it as his share.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says the parrot had just got
the man's fortune in its beak, when
Faithful took a standing jump from
behind the woman at it. It was awful,
Jimmy says. The woman gave a
scream and grabbed at the parrot, the
man grabbed at Faithful, and Faithful—well,
Jimmy says he never knew
quite what Faithful did or how he did
it, but he emerged with the man's
fortune sticking to the fly-paper.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says bloodhounds are very
sensitive and avoid a commotion; but
the man and the woman were not used
to his side action in running and they
fell over one another.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says it was a very funny
<pb xml:id="page293" n="pg 293"/>
fortune; it was in a special red envelope
and he couldn't understand it at first.
You see it only contained the names of
some towns and villages, and Jimmy
was just wishing that Faithful would
leave music and parrots and fly-papers
and fortunes alone, and catch German
spies instead, when it all came to him
because a friend of his mother's lived at
one of the villages and some Zeppelin
bombs had been dropped there.</p>
                <p>The woman had given the man the
names of the places where Zeppelin
bombs had fallen, and old Faithful had
been tracking them down all the time.</p>
                <p>Jimmy's head just buzzed with
thoughts as he ran to the police-station.
They caught the man and the woman,
and one of the policemen discovered the
flag-pole on the man's lawn, and it
turned out to be part of a wireless apparatus
to send messages to Germany.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says that, when the spies
were nicely locked up and settled for
the night, one of the policemen got the
parrot to tell Faithful's fortune, and
when they opened the envelope it said,</p>
                <p>"Your face is your fortune."</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/293.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e664" type="div2">
                <head>A VERDICT REVISED.</head>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Randolph the rash in cruel phrase defames</l>
                        <l>The "mediocrities with double names;"</l>
                        <l>But nowadays we find whole-hearted pleaders</l>
                        <l>Urging the claims of hyphenated leaders.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>For what were Pemberton without the thrilling</l>
                        <l>Corollary and supplement of Billing?</l>
                        <l>While Billing by itself, pronounced <title>tout court</title>
                        </l>
                        <l>And shorn of Pemberton, sounds bald and poor.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Without emotion you and I may any day</l>
                        <l>Light on a Jones unwedded to a Kennedy;</l>
                        <l>Likewise a Kennedy unlinked with Jones</l>
                        <l>Will fail to stir the marrow in our bones.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Mark you, moreover, how the order tends</l>
                        <l>To foster and promote euphonic ends;</l>
                        <l>For Billing Pemberton sounds flat and dull,</l>
                        <l>And Jones prefixed to Kennedy is null.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>But Pemberton by Billing followed up,</l>
                        <l>And Kennedy with Jones to fill the cup,</l>
                        <l>Electrify the nation's tympanum</l>
                        <l>And strike the voice of sober Season dumb.</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A quotation from <name rend="sc">Browning</name> as rendered
by <title>The Daily Chronicle</title>:—</p>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>"No! let me taste the whole of it, fare like my peers,</l>
                        <l>The horrors of old."</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <p>We regret to see our respected contemporary
has not yet abandoned its prejudice
against the Upper House.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"A report was read from the Sanitary Inspector
who has now joined the 3rd/4th Wilts
Regt. This showed that 18 parishes had been
infected under the Housing and Town Planning
Act, leaving eight parishes still to be
dealt with."—<title>Wiltshire Advertiser.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>In the interests of the uninfected
parishes we trust that the Sanitary
Inspector will deal faithfully with the
Germs.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page294" n="pg 294"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e794" type="div2">
                <head>LUNCHEON CAUSERIES.</head>
                <p>A young lady typist was overheard
remarking in a City teashop the other
day that she liked <name rend="sc">Silas Hocking</name> better
than <name rend="sc">Joseph</name>, because the latter was
"rather deep." The remark was significant
of the new atmosphere of
literary enthusiasm which the feminine
invaders of business London have
brought with them into the luncheon-hour.
We are instituting a causerie
for the special benefit of this large class
of readers, <title>i.e.</title> those who get out of
their depth in the transition from <name rend="sc">Silas</name>
to <name rend="sc">Joseph</name>.</p>
                <p>I want to introduce you to-day to
a writer whose subtle genius defies
analysis but demands reverent appreciation.
Ruby L. Binns came into my
own intellectual life at a rather critical
stage in my reading. Like most young
men of the early nineteen-noughts, I
had fallen under the spell of Guy
Beverley, whose <title>Only a Mill Hand</title> and
<title>Squire Darrell's Heir</title> appeared to us
the consummation of the novelettist's
art. In those days every other young
man you met was mouthing the great
renunciation scene from the <title>Mill Hand</title>.
Small marvel too! As I recall it even
now something of the old glamour
revives.</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"Go!" cried Mary Ellen. "Though you
are the Export Manager and I but a poor
humble mill-girl, I would sooner beg my
bread from door to door than seek it at <hi rend="it">your</hi>
hand." She eyed him with pitiless scorn.
Jasper Dare went out into the night.
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>Fine? Ay, and more than fine. But
we young men of the nineteen-noughts
made one big mistake. We thought
Guy Beverley had scaled the summit
of art; but art has no summit. We
thought he had plumbed the depths
of psychology; but psychology defies
the plumber. I date a new epoch in
my life from that day in 19— when I
picked up my <title>Daily Reflector</title> and read
the opening chapter of a new serial,
<title>Her Soldier Sweetheart</title>, by Ruby L.
Binns. That was on a Monday. By
Wednesday of that week this unknown
writer had revealed to me a New Idea
and a New Style. The idea is familiar
to most of you now, but in those days
the daring conception that a common
soldier might turn out to be the
missing heir of a baronet rang like a
challenge in the ears of the older romanticism.
It is her style, however,
that is Ruby Binns's most enduring
gift to English prose literature. Lean,
restrained, economical, it holds (for me)
the very spirit of the English race and
tongue. Listen:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
She went to the door, thinking she heard
something. There was nobody there, so she
went back to her work, thinking sadly of her
soldier boy. "Cheer up," said Clarice;
"perhaps he'll come back soon." "Perhaps,"
answered Yvonne wanly, "but it does
not seem very likely, does it, dear?" The
next moment the door opened and a tall
soldierly figure entered the room.
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>English? It is like a May morning
on Tooting Common. Beverley
would have handled that situation well,
no doubt. But could he—could anyone—have
achieved the poignancy of
that unaffected phrase, "It does not
seem very likely"? I said that the
depths of Art were unplumbable. True,
but Ruby Binns has at least got lower
than most.</p>
                <p>Next week I want to speak of a new
man and a new book, Stott Mackenzie
and his <title>Only a Trailer-Car Conductress</title>.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e864" type="div2">
                <head>THE BEAUTIFUL THING.</head>
                <p>You see ugly things in London now-a-days.
Oh, yes, but you see beautiful
things as well. I saw one yesterday—one
of the beautiful things.</p>
                <p>It was a cold wet evening, not
actually raining but very, very nearly.
I stood at the place in Piccadilly where
the 'buses stop. There was quite a little
crowd waiting, as there always is at this
time of day—women with parcels, work-girls
going home, a few men. All of
them looked tired, and many of them
looked cross.</p>
                <p>When a 'bus drew up at the curb
all those people made a simultaneous
plunge for it. Before it had finally
stopped they were clinging like a swarm
of bees to the steps and rails. It is an
arduous game this 'bus-catching, though
for those who are young and strong it
should perhaps have a certain attraction,
combining as it does the allurement of
a lottery gamble with the charm of a
football scrimmage.</p>
                <p>There were only three vacant places,
and these, after a desperate struggle,
were secured by two athletic-looking
girls and a red-haired schoolboy. The
conductor waved back the disappointed
boarders and they dropped off sulkily.
I watched them a moment and then
my eyes toward two soldiers,
who were crossing the street. Fine,
well-set-up men they were, and they
carried themselves with the indescribable
air of those who have crossed
swords with Death and left their
opponent, for the time at least, defeated.
One of them had a green
shade over his left eye. The other
carried a stick and walked with a slight
limp.</p>
                <p>They took up their position a little
to the side of the expectant crowd that
was already beginning to sway and
jostle at the sight of a fresh 'bus, which
had just rounded the corner. Small
chance for the new-comers, however
slightly wounded, in such a <title>mêlée</title>,
thought I.</p>
                <p>The 'bus came rocking along, reeled
to the left, staggered to the right, and
came uncertainly to a shuddering rest
beside the pavement.</p>
                <p>And then it was that I saw the
Beautiful Thing.</p>
                <p>For of that little crowd, some twenty
people in all, not a soul moved. Not
a man, woman or child took so much
as a step forward. They looked at the
half-filled 'bus, they looked at the two
soldiers, and waited, motionless.</p>
                <p>Those two had pressed forward briskly
enough, but as they mounted the steps,
the man with the green shade giving
a helping hand to his companion, the
attitude of the crowd seemed suddenly
to strike them. The lame man glanced
over his shoulder, smiled and murmured
something to his friend. His friend
turned likewise and stared. He pushed
his comrade through the doorway,
turned again, and very solemnly raised
his hand to his cap in salute. A second
later he too vanished within the interior
of the 'bus.</p>
                <p>And then the rush began.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e904" type="div2">
                <head>THE TRUMP CARD.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e908" type="div3">
                    <head>
                        <title>"Gold lace has a charm for the fair."</title>
                    </head>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>When William first became a Lieut.</l>
                            <l rend="i2">R.N.V.R., in blue and gold,</l>
                            <l>Belinda smiled upon his suit</l>
                            <l rend="i2">(Which formerly had found her cold);</l>
                            <l>His manly form and honest face,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">She really liked them, I believe;</l>
                            <l>But, most of all, she loved the lace</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Upon his sleeve.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>Yet soon a rival courtier came—</l>
                            <l rend="i2">A dashing dapper Lieut. R.N.;</l>
                            <l>And, as this paragon pressed his claim,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Oh, what could William hope for then?</l>
                            <l>How could a wobbly-braided swain</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Vie with the actual Royal Navy,</l>
                            <l>Whose stripes were half as broad again</l>
                            <l rend="i2">And straight, not wavy?</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>Then William swore (ah, Envy, ah!)</l>
                            <l rend="i2">"Belinda <hi rend="it">shall</hi> be mine, she <name rend="sc">SHALL</name>!"</l>
                            <l>And wrote a note to his papa,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Who'd just been made an Admiral:—</l>
                            <l>"Father, now that you'll fly at sea</l>
                            <l rend="i2">A two-balled flag in place of pennant,</l>
                            <l>What do you say to taking me</l>
                            <l rend="i2">As flag-lieutenant?"</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>When William next waylaid his fair,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">He had his glittering "aiglets" on;</l>
                            <l>Rope upon rope of gold was there,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">And now his rival's look was wan;</l>
                            <l>He tried a bitter sneer, to greet</l>
                            <l rend="i2">This "peacock preening in the sun";</l>
                            <l>But Miss Belinda thought them "sweet"....</l>
                            <l rend="i2">And William won.</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page295" n="pg 295"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1040" type="div2">
                <head>MR. PUNCH'S POTTED FILMS.  THE AMERICAN THRILLER.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e1044" type="div3">
                    <head>THE EXPLOITS OF JEMIMA ANN.  <name rend="sc">159th</name> EPISODE.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/295a.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/295b.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/295c.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/295d.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/295e.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/295f.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page296" n="pg 296"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/296.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1094" type="div2">
                <head>THE LATEST SOLAR MYTH.</head>
                <quote type="note">Mr. J. H. <name rend="sc">Willis</name>, a Norwich scientist, writing in <title>The Morning
Post</title>, condemns the daylight-saving movement on the ground that
too much sunshine is enervating and that life is more virile in
Northern latitudes.</quote>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Though the daylight-saving measure, which ingenious <name rend="sc">Willett</name> planned</l>
                        <l>To illume the work and leisure of the toilers of the land,</l>
                        <l>Has not yet convinced the nation, or unto the mass appealed,</l>
                        <l>Still without exaggeration it can claim to hold the field.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>But of late a man of science—Mr. <name rend="sc">Willis</name> is his name—</l>
                        <l>In a mood of flat defiance bans the daylight-saving game;</l>
                        <l>And, relentlessly pooh-poohing the delights of sunny days,</l>
                        <l>Recommends the prompt tabooing of the cult of solar rays.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>All the hardy Northern races are efficient, in his view,</l>
                        <l>Just because they live in places where the sunlit hours are few,</l>
                        <l>And, conversely, peoples broiling in the horrid torrid zones</l>
                        <l>Have no grit or zest for toiling and no marrow in their bones.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>There was once a commentator, if I rightly recollect,</l>
                        <l>Who, discussing the Equator, treated it with disrespect;</l>
                        <l>But his temperate impeachment, though it showed a mental twist,</l>
                        <l>Pales before the drastic preachment of the Norwich scientist.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Metaphorically speaking, it's a symptom of the Hun</l>
                        <l>To be always bent on seeking after places in the sun;</l>
                        <l>But I'd rather choose to follow what my deadliest foes applaud</l>
                        <l>Than to ostracise Apollo as an enervating fraud.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>No, you don't convince me, <name rend="sc">Willis</name>, with your scientific chat,</l>
                        <l>And my slangy daughter, Phyllis, says you're talking through your hat;</l>
                        <l>For, while many drug-concoctors merit death <title>by sus. per coll.</title>,</l>
                        <l>I believe the best of doctors is our old friend Doctor Sol.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Hours recorded on the dial, "hours serene," assuage more ills</l>
                        <l>Than the lancet or the phial or a wilderness of pills;</l>
                        <l>And if cranks of anti-solar leanings long for gloom, they should</l>
                        <l>Emigrate to circumpolar regions and remain for good.</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e1230" type="div3">
                    <head>Punch's Roll of Honour.</head>
                    <p>We record with sincere grief the death of Lieutenant
<name rend="sc">Alec Leith Johnston</name>, who was killed in action on
April 22nd during the fight in which the gallant Shropshires
recaptured a trench on the Ypres-Langemarck Road.
Early in the War Mr. <name rend="sc">Johnston</name> joined the Artists' Corps
and saw service at the Front. Later he received a commission
in the K.S.L.I., and a few months ago was in the
list of wounded. He has for a long time been associated
with <title>Punch</title>, and during the War has contributed many
articles under the titles "At the Back of the Front" and
"At the Front." His loss will be very keenly felt.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page297" n="pg 297"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1250" type="div3">
                    <head>WANTED—A ST. PATRICK.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/297.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page298" n="pg 298"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1263" type="div2">
                <head>ESSENCE OF PARLIAMENT.</head>
                <p>
                    <title>Tuesday, April 25th.</title>—The Government,
which has sometimes been
accused of not having sufficient confidence
in the House of Commons, has
made ample amends. Information
about the Army, too grave to be imparted
to the people who provide the
men and the means for maintaining it,
is to be freely given to four
or five hundred Members of
Parliament (not to mention a
similar number of Peers).</p>
                <p>The <name rend="sc">Prime Minister</name> opened
the Secret Session in one of
his briefest speeches. "Mr.
Speaker," he said, "I beg,
Sir, to call your attention to
the fact that strangers are
present." The historic form
of this advertisement, "I spy
strangers;" is briefer still, but
inadmissible in these ticklish
times. One does not want
to see, in the enemy Press,
"British Prime Minister confesses
to spying."</p>
                <p>Then the Press Gallery
was cleared, and the Great
Inquest of the Nation became
a Vehmgericht. The wretched
scribe who should attempt to
peer behind the veil that
shrouds its proceedings has
been warned in advance of
the unnamed pains and penalties
that await him if he should
venture to describe or even
"refer to" the proceedings of
the Secret Session. I am unable
to say, therefore, whether
it is true that the occupants
of the Treasury Bench forthwith
donned helmets and gas-masks
to protect themselves
from the fiery darts and mephitic
vapours launched at
them from above and below
the Gangway.</p>
                <p>On these picturesque details
the official report, compiled
by Mr. <name rend="sc">Speaker</name>, who is understood
to have seized the
opportunity offered by his recent stay
at Bath to learn Pitman's shorthand,
is unfortunately silent.</p>
                <p>All we learn from its severely restrained
pages is that the <name rend="sc">Prime
Minister</name> made a long statement about
recruiting. From this we gather that
if fifty thousand of the unattested
married men do not enlist before the
end of May they will be compelled
to do so; and that altogether the
Government will insist on getting
200,000 men from this source. The
German General Staff will be surprised
to learn that our requirements are so
modest, and will wonder, as we do,
what all the pother is about.</p>
                <p>Perhaps Mr. <name rend="sc">Lowther</name> did not take
notes of the other speeches that were
delivered. At any rate he gives us no
indication of their drift. All we know
is that in the course of some seven
hours no fewer than sixteen Members
addressed the House. From this it
may be inferred that the absence of
reporters has at least the negative advantage
of conducing to brevity of
utterance. May we also infer that the
speaking was as plain as it was brief,
and that for the time being the Palace
of Westminster has become the Palace
of Truth?</p>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/298.png"/>
                </figure>
                <p>
                    <title>Wednesday, April 26th.</title>—So far as
we are permitted to know what took
place—for the House of Commons had
another Secret Session—in both Houses
it was Ireland, Ireland all the way.
The Commons began by granting a
return relating to Irish Lunacy accounts,
and then by an easy transition
passed to the report of the Sinn Fein
rebellion in Dublin.</p>
                <p>Colonel <name rend="sc">Sharman-Crawford</name>, who
bears a name that all Ireland has solid
reason to respect, desiring to return to
his native country, asked Mr. <name rend="sc">Birrell</name>
what routes, if any, were open. Mr.
<name rend="sc">Birrell</name> did not know, but intimated
genially that he might be able to take
absence of over the gallant Colonel under his own
protecting wing. The House
appeared to find humour in
the idea of the <name rend="sc">Chief Secretary</name>
returning to his post,
and an Hon. Member inquired
why he had ever left it.</p>
                <p>The <name rend="sc">Prime Minister</name> gave
a brief and, so far as it went,
rosy-coloured report of the
situation in Dublin. Some
Nationalist Volunteers were
helping the Government. The
forces of the Crown were to
be further strengthened by a
party of American journalists,
armed to the teeth with quick-firing
pencils, who were going
over to deal with "this most
recent German campaign."</p>
                <p>This may have reminded
Mr. <name rend="sc">Asquith</name> that there were
British journalists in the
Press Gallery. The <name rend="sc">Deputy
Speaker's</name> attention having
been called to this fact, the
House voted for their expulsion,
and again passed into
Secret Session.</p>
                <p>The Lords were again in
Open Session, to the regret,
perhaps, of the Government
representatives, who heard
some very plain speaking
from Lord <name rend="sc">Middleton</name>. According
to his information the
rebels were still in possession
of important parts of Dublin.
The Government had been
warned on Sunday last that an
outbreak was imminent, but
had nevertheless allowed many
officers to go on leave, while
others were permitted to assist
at the races on Monday.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Thursday, April 21th.</title>—Mr. <name rend="sc">Ginnell</name>
does not believe in the supineness of
the Irish Executive. His information
is that quite a long time ago it had
resolved to place Dublin in a state of
siege, to imprison Archbishop <name rend="sc">Walsh</name>
and the <name rend="sc">Lord Mayor</name> in their respective
official residences, and to arrest the
leaders of sundry Nationalist associations.
Mr. T. W. <name rend="sc">Russell</name>, as spokesman
for the ruthless Mr. <name rend="sc">Birrell</name>,
denied emphatically that these drastic
steps had been contemplated.</p>
                <p>The <name rend="sc">Prime Minister</name> subsequently
announced that the situation still had
<pb xml:id="page299" n="pg 299"/>
"serious features." This mild phrase
covers the continued possession by the
rebels of important parts of Dublin,
the prevalence of street fighting, and
the spread of the insurrection to the
wild West. Martial law had been
proclaimed all over the country; Sir
<name rend="sc">John Maxwell</name> had been sent over in
supreme command, and the Irish Government
had been placed under his
orders—the last part of this announcement
being greeted with especially loud
cheers.</p>
                <p>Sir <name rend="sc">Edward Carson</name> and Mr. <name rend="sc">John
Redmond</name> joined in expressing horror
of this rebellion and hoped that the
Press would not make it an excuse for
reviving political dissension on Irish
matters—a sufficient rebuke to <title>The
Westminster Gazette</title> and <title>The Star</title>,
both of which by a curious coincidence
had found the moment auspicious for
preaching from the text of the old tag,
"There but for the grace of God," etc.</p>
                <p>Sir H. <name rend="sc">Dalziel</name> attempted to secure
an immediate debate upon the Irish
trouble. But the eminent Privy Councillor
found little support in the House,
and was first knocked down by the
<name rend="sc">Deputy-Speaker</name> and then trampled
upon by Mr. <name rend="sc">Asquith</name>.</p>
                <p>If the Secret Sessions were intended
to make smooth the way of the Military
Service Bill they failed miserably in
their object. Mr. <name rend="sc">Long</name>, to whom was
entrusted the task of introducing it,
felt his position acutely. Only when
explaining that one of the principal
objects of the Bill was to extend the
service of time-expired soldiers for the
duration of the War did he wax at all
eloquent, and then it was in lauding
the chivalry of these men and in expressing
his extreme distaste for the
task of coercing them.  The whole
speech justified the poet's remark that
"long petitions spoil the cause they
plead."</p>
                <p>Not a voice was heard in favour of
the measure.  Sir <name rend="sc">Edward Carson</name>
damned it for not going far enough,
and Mr. <name rend="sc">Leif Jones</name> because it went
too far; and Mr. <name rend="sc">Stephen Walsh</name>, as
representative of the miners, who have
given so much of their blood to the
country's cause, bluntly demanded that
the House should reject this Bill "and
insist on the straight thing."</p>
                <p>Mr. <name rend="sc">Asquith</name>, recalled to the House
by his agitated colleague, recognised
that his old Parliamentary hand had
got into a hornet's nest, and promptly
withdrew it. To the best of my recollection
this is the first time on record
that a Government measure has perished
before its first reading. Conceived in
secrecy and delivered in pain, its epitaph
will be that of another unhappy
infant:—</p>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>"If I was to be so soon done for</l>
                        <l>I wonder what I was began for."</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/299.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"The Austrians thrice attempted to rush
the Italian positions on the Upper Isonzo, but
were repulsed with heavy lasses."</p>
                    <p>
                        <title>Times of Ceylon.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>Stout girls, these <hi rend="it">contadine</hi>.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"Recently I have seen several German
planes so high as to be mere specks, and of
the many I have seen none has been lower, I
should say, than ,000 ft."—<title>Morning Paper.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>A cautious statement, and probably
true.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"We are glad to learn that the daughter of
our popular banker was married on the 10th
instant, over 1000 persons were invited and
sumpfedtuously."—<title>Indian Paper.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>We infer that the compositor was
among them.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"In his defence Mr. —— said he had endeavoured
to fake the point that the onus of
proving he was under the Military Service
Act was upon the prosecution."</p>
                    <p>
                        <title>Bayswater Chronicle.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>If not a conscientious he seems to have
been at least a candid objector.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page300" n="pg 300"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1525" type="div2">
                <head>"THE BIRTH OF A FLUENCE."</head>
                <p>In consequence of the new tax on
imported films the Cinema industry in
England has received a new fillip, and
a wave of enterprise is passing over
the studios. In place of the familiar—almost
too familiar—American dramas
we are to have English. No more
of those square-jawed stern American
business men at their desks, with the
telephone ever in their hands and
instantaneous replies to every call.
No more police officers, also at their
desks, giving orders like lightning and
having them understood and acted
upon as quickly. No more crooks
clambering over the roofs of an
express train. No more motor-car
pursuits. No more Indians, no
more cowboys, no more heroines
in top boots.</p>
                <p>And what is there to be instead?
Not—I hear you cry
appealingly—not panoramas of
Zurich or Cape Town? No, not
those devastating views of scenery,
but home-made films "featuring"
English performers, with an eye
not only to entertainment but instruction.
That is the new movie
note. And for a start a wonderful
picture has just been completed,
under the title "The Birth of a
Fluence," taking the Cinema-goers
(as they are called) behind the
scenes of a London daily paper.</p>
                <p>Not a real paper, of course, for
that would be telling too much,
but an absolutely imaginary paper,
yet like enough in many respects
to a real paper to afford to the
imaginative spectator an idea of
how such marvellous sheets are
put together.</p>
                <p>No expense has been spared to
get an air of verisimilitude into
these pictures, at a private view
of which we were permitted to
be present.</p>
                <p>Let us give a rough sketch of the
film, which is some mile and a half
long, or as far, say, as from the House
of Lords to Printing House Square.
But first we must remark that the
unseen force which agitates all the
documents and blinds of the various
rooms shown is not due, as it usually
is, to the circumstance that the pictures
were taken in the open air, during
a gale, but it symbolises the power of
the Proprietor of the paper, who can
by a breath make or unmake Governments.</p>
                <p>The first picture shows the arrival
of the Editor, a man of desperate mien,
dark as a thunder cloud, ready to be
affrighted by nothing, with instant
disapproval of whatever he disapproves
breaking through his alert, intellectual
features. To him, stern patriot as he
is, it is nothing that men do well.
He is there, vigilant and implacable,
to pounce swiftly and mercilessly on
derelictions of duty. No one knows so
well as he what is possible to a Minister
and his Department and what not.
They themselves, the Minister and his
Department, are totally uninstructed
in the matter. Truly a remarkable man.</p>
                <p>The Editor opens his letters; touches
bells, speaks through telephones, and
generally proves himself to be more
than a man, a Force. Imaginary as is
the whole affair, no one seeing this film
can ever open a morning paper again
without a thrill, a foreboding.</p>
                <p>Next we are shown the Proprietor
leaving his private house by aeroplane
to visit the office. We see him first
alighting on the roof and then entering
his private room by a secret door, from
a secret staircase. Having removed
his slouch hat and cloak and laid aside
his dark lantern, he is revealed as a
man of destiny indeed.</p>
                <p>We see the mottoes on the walls of
the room, such as "Always change
horses in midstream"; "Always wash
dirty linen in public"; "Any stick is
good enough to beat a dog with";
"If you throw enough mud some will
stick"; "Damn the consequences";
"Disunion is strength"; "After me
the Deluge," and so forth.</p>
                <p>Then the Proprietor begins to get
busy. He too touches bells, and various
assistants rush to his presence. The
first is the Editor, and we watch the
progress of a fateful interview, which
is made the more understandable by
legends shown on the screen. Thus,
after a long course of lip-moving and
chin-wagging on the part of the Proprietor,
we read the helpful words:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"The Twenty-three must go."
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>Then the Editor's lips move and his
chin rides up and down and we read
the words:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"But suppose the old man is too
clever?"
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>And so the epoch-making talk goes
on and others are summoned to
take part in it.</p>
                <p>Next, as a guide to the paper's
enterprise we are admitted to a
meeting of the Cabinet, and are
assisted, at last to unravel the
mystery as to which Minister it
is who gives away the secrets of
that assembly, for we watch him
in his various disguises on his way
to the dark cellar where he meets
the political representative of the
paper, makes his report and receives
the promise of his future
reward. It is, we feel confident,
this particular section of the film
which will secure for it an amazing
popularity, though all reference in
the Press to Cabinet proceedings
has now been made illegal for the
duration of the War.</p>
                <p>"The Birth of a Fluence," it will
be seen, does not confine its energies
to the office of the paper.
So thorough is the scheme that
various pictures have been taken—always,
of course, at the usual
enormous expense—at even distant
places, where its activities, or the
result of them, can be studied. For
example, we are shown a section of
the Front and the delight of the English
soldier as he unfolds the paper and discovers
that his country is still being
goaded towards that healthy disintegration
which must necessarily accelerate
our victory. And we are even
shown one of the paper's defeated candidates
seeking the railway-station
after the election; for it is notorious
that, vast as are the paper's other influences,
it is often unable to persuade an
electorate to follow it.</p>
                <p>The last picture, which also should
be of particular interest to the public
as proving how sacred the Fourth
Estate holds the duty of providing it
with accurate reports, shows the whole
of the building draped with the habiliments
of woe and the staff in deep
<pb xml:id="page301" n="pg 301"/>
mourning on learning that the secrecy
of the secret session is to be callously
and rigorously enforced by the Government.
And in this state of prostration
the <hi rend="it">personnel</hi> is left. So ends one of
the most enthralling films that this
country has yet invented.</p>
                <p>"The Birth of a Fluence" would, of
course, be more instructive still were
there any paper that at all corresponded
to the fantastic and incredible organ
here illustrated. But of course a sheet
that during the progress of an anxious
war so consistently belittled its country
and aspersed its rulers would be impossible.
Still, enough verisimilitude
remains to make an amusing half-hour.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/300.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1606" type="div2">
                <head>NURSERY RHYMES OF LONDON TOWN.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e1610" type="div3">
                    <head>IX.—<name rend="sc">The Poultry and the Borough.</name>
                    </head>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>The Fox ran to London</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Starving for his dinner;</l>
                            <l>There he met the Weasel</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Looking even thinner.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>The Weasel said to Reynard,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">"What shall be our pickin's?"</l>
                            <l>Said Reynard to the Weasel,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">"Rabbits and Spring Chickens."</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>Then they went a-hunting,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">And they did it very thorough,</l>
                            <l>The Fox in the Poultry</l>
                            <l rend="i2">And the Weasel in the Borough.</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1665" type="div3">
                    <head>
                        <name rend="sc">X.—Wormwood Scrubbs.</name>
                    </head>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>Wormwood scrubs, Wormwood scrubs</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Windows, walls, and floors,</l>
                            <l>Pots and pans and pickle-tubs,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Tables, chairs and doors;</l>
                            <l>Wormwood scrubs the public seats</l>
                            <l rend="i2">And the City Halls;</l>
                            <l>Wormwood scrubs the London streets,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Wormwood scrubs Saint Paul's;</l>
                            <l>Wormwood scrubs on her hands and knees,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">But oh, it's plainly seen,</l>
                            <l>Though she use a ton of elbow-grease</l>
                            <l rend="i2">She'll <hi rend="it">never</hi> get it clean!</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1721" type="div3">
                    <head>A TRUE PESSIMIST.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/301.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1732" type="div2">
                <head>THE LOAN.</head>
                <p>It was past ten o'clock and the maid
was, or should have been, asleep, so
when there came a knock at the front-door
Bertha got up to answer it herself.</p>
                <p>"Whoever can it be at this time of
night?" I said.</p>
                <p>"It's Evelyn come to borrow again,"
said Bertha. "I know her knock."</p>
                <p>"Don't always look on the dark side
of things," I counselled; "be an optimist
like me. Now I have a feeling
that she has come to pay back what
they borrowed last week."</p>
                <p>A minute later Bertha returned. "I
knew it," she said; "it is as I feared.
Jack has sent her over to borrow three
more."</p>
                <p>"Three more!" I gasped; "but it's
preposterous. They borrowed five only
last Monday and they'll never pay
them back, of course. What did you
say to her?"</p>
                <p>"I said I couldn't manage it myself,
but I would ask you."</p>
                <p>"I suppose we shall have to do it,"
I said, crossing over to the bureau and
unlocking it.</p>
                <p>"Haven't you got any on you?"
asked Bertha.</p>
                <p>"Only one; I never carry more than
that in case I might get my pockets
picked. It's a bit thick," I continued,
"we economise and deny ourselves in
all kinds of ways and then that spend-thrift
comes—or, rather, sends his wife—and
borrows all our hard-earned
savings."</p>
                <p>From a secret drawer in the bureau
I drew forth a small box that I
opened with fingers that trembled like
<title>Gaspard's</title>.</p>
                <p>Bertha joined me and, side by side,
we stood gazing at the contents in a
hush that was akin to worship.</p>
                <p>"Well," said I, at last breaking the
silence, "here you are, and for goodness'
sake tell her not to waste them!" and
into my wife's outstretched hand I
carefully counted out—three matches.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page302" n="pg 302"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1784" type="div2">
                <head>AT THE PLAY.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e1788" type="div3">
                    <head>
                        <name rend="sc">"The Mayor of Troy."</name>
                    </head>
                    <p>The admirable "Q" has shot his
arrow into the gold so often and carried
off so mountainous a load of trophies
that he can see with equanimity his
last shot signalled an outer—even a
miss. The signaller must needs be
more dismayed than he. "Q" is also
too honest and perceptive a critic not
to see the weak points of <title>The Mayor
of Troy</title> as a stage play, though he may
fairly plume himself on the pleasant
(and unpleasant) folk of his creation
who partly came to life on the opening
night at the Haymarket. He will
have found out and noted for an
appendix to those lively and instructive
discourses of his <title>On the
Art of Writing</title> that it is a jolly
difficult thing to write a play;
that an act is not a chapter of a
novel, still less a <title>compôte</title> of bits
of many chapters; that, while to
be charmingly discursive is a
paramount quality of the higher
type of novelist, the same attribute
in a play, whose very breath
of life is essential brevity, makes
it appear to go on crutches, like
his own discomfited hero. It
bemuses an audience and gravels
the players—as the queer uncertainty
of touch of so skilful, so
conscientious an actor as Mr.
<name rend="sc">Ainley</name> sufficiently betrayed. But
to the story.</p>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/302.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <p>Portly and pompous <title>Major
Solomon Hymen Toogood</title> (Mr.
<name rend="sc">Ainley</name>), wealthy citizen of Troy
Town, and, in the perilous year
of grace 1804, for the seventh
time its Mayor; Justice of the
Peace, in command of the battery
of <title>Diehards</title> which himself had
raised, spoilt by the worship of
the women and the tractability (with
reservations) of the men, has reason
to be mightily pleased with himself;
and very distinctly is. On this pleasant
day on which the play opens he
has written a proposal of marriage
to a lady whose heart, unhappily, is
already given to his Deputy in civic
office and Second in Command of the
battery, Dr. <title>Dillworthy</title> (Mr. <name rend="sc">Leon
Quartermaine</name>).  Meanwhile a little
smuggling expedition, which he had
planned under cover of his military
authority (Sir <name rend="sc">Arthur</name> does not quite
put it like that), turns into a genuine
fight, and our Mayor is carried off
prisoner to France.</p>
                    <p>At the peace of 1814 he returns thin
and lame to find that the lady of his
choice has long married the man of
hers (and why not?), and that the two,
with their children, are installed in his
house; <title>Dillworthy</title> no longer Deputy
but reigning Mayor. Nobody recognises
the famous <title>Toogood</title>, which is
entirely "Q's" fault, not theirs; and
nobody, except a pretty maid who is to
marry his nephew (his own money has
made the match possible), seems to
worry overmuch (<title>absit omen</title>!) about
returned prisoners of war. He reveals
himself to nobody but his villain
brother <title>William</title> (Mr. <name rend="sc">Ayrton</name>). That
fatuous revenue officer, <title>Lomax</title> (Mr.
<name rend="sc">Malleson</name>), has written a fulsomely
flattering life of him at which his gorge
rises. Everybody, apart from opening
a hospital in his memory (in a bed of
which he eventually finds himself),
seems to be going about his or her
business much as usual (yet what
else could they do?). He extracts a
character of himself from his faithful
old servant and finds it not so flattering
as he would have liked. Seems, in
fact, determined to have his grievance.
Well, then, he will buy a dog. And he
will take the road with his pal the
comic sailor and shake the dust of
fickle Troy from off his feet.</p>
                    <p>But I protest that this is all very
unfair to the Trojans. As soon as he
gave them their chance they took it
decently enough, so much so that all
ended happily in what must have been
a most uncomfortable dance on the
sharp fragments of the <title>Toogood</title> bust
which the disgruntled original had
smashed with his crutch.</p>
                    <p>Of course poor <title>William</title> very naturally
resented this extraordinarily inconsiderate
return from the dead of a long and
well-lost brother, several thousand of
whose pounds he had misappropriated.
As for <title>Lomax</title>, could he by any stretch
of the imagination within the frame
of this picture have tried to bribe the
Mayor to go away just to save his
infernal biography from being wasted?
You simply can't have a convincing
colloquy on these lines between the
tragic figure of the disillusioned and
embittered hero and this farcical jackanapes.</p>
                    <p>And I think it was just this sort of
lack of conviction that flattened the
actors. Mr. <name rend="sc">Henry Ainley</name> had his
moments, but he's not a man of moments.
He's about our best
<title>whole-hogger</title>. Mr. <name rend="sc">Leon
Quartermaine's</name> easy skill was,
as it always is, a very pleasant
thing to watch. Mr. <name rend="sc">De Lange</name>
gave an animated little sketch
of a droll French spy. Mr. <name rend="sc">Miles
Malleson</name> shouldn't let his sense
of character and his undoubted
talent for business lead him into
that capital sin of taking more
than his share of the stage. Mr.
<name rend="sc">Hendrie</name> as the sailor, <title>Ben Chope</title>,
gave us another of those amusing
grotesques of his; and Miss
<name rend="sc">Claire Greet</name> put in a clever
paragraph as <title>Mrs. Chope</title>. Mr.
<name rend="sc">Frederick Groves</name> was an excellent
gruff servant; Miss <name rend="sc">Peggy
Rush</name> a pretty bride; Mr. <name rend="sc">Gerald
McCarthy</name> a plausible lover; Miss
<name rend="sc">Bruce-Potter</name> a becomingly
subdued and adoring Georgian
doctor's wife. Mr. <name rend="sc">Lyall
Swete</name> played competently a
poisonous ass of a vicar, and was
responsible for the production,
which was admirable.</p>
                    <p>T.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1930" type="div3">
                    <head>A Ranker.</head>
                    <p>Extract from Battalion Orders:—</p>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"The horse and cab of the Headquarters
attached to the —— Regt., A. Coy.,
for forage and accommodation."
</p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"In the Ascot Double Handicap Hurdle
Race, after an objection to Early Berry for
jumping, the race was awarded to Marita."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Sporting Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Marita, presumably, crawled under the
hurdles like a little lady.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"In spite of all traditions about the British
love of a tub, we rarely are acquainted with
the proper use of soap and water.... And
thus we lay ourselves under Browning's reproach
of 'You very imperfect ablutionist!'"</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>British Weekly.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Browning may have written this; but
we prefer <name rend="sc">Gilbert's</name> version:—</p>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"You very imperfect ablutioner."
</p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page303" n="pg 303"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/303.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1999" type="div2">
                <head>OUR BOOKING-OFFICE.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e2003" type="div3">
                    <head>
                        <title>(By Mr. Punch's Staff of Learned Clerks.)</title>
                    </head>
                    <p>I would heartily commend to all good English women
and men <title>The Book of Italy</title> (<name rend="sc">Unwin</name>), first because it will
help the families of those Italians who have left England
to join their ships and regiments and will make possible
the works of mercy of the Italian Red Cross, and secondly
because it is in itself an admirable book—the most distinguished,
I think, of any of its kind published here during
the War. It tells us something of the great Italian creators
and liberators, <name rend="sc">Dante</name>, <name rend="sc">Leonardo</name>, <name rend="sc">Michelangelo</name>,
<name rend="sc">Mazzini</name>,
<name rend="sc">Garibaldi</name>, <name rend="sc">Cavour</name>—too little perhaps of <name rend="sc">Mazzini</name>,
than whom no movement for liberty ever had a nobler or
a saner prophet. Of the good things, besides the contributions
of distinguished Italians (a particularly interesting
note on the Italian Red Cross by Signor <name rend="sc">Galante</name> claims
a Neapolitan, <name rend="sc">Ferdinando Palasciano</name>, as the pioneer,
in 1848, of the Red Cross idea), let me specially commend
the spirited introduction of Lord <name rend="sc">Bryce</name>, the eloquent
letter of <name rend="sc">Sabatier</name>, the memories of <name rend="sc">Frederic Harrison</name>,
the quiet wisdom of <name rend="sc">Clutton-Brock</name>, the learning (decently
veiled for normal eyes) of <name rend="sc">Frazer</name>, of <title>The Golden Bough</title>;
the inspired prejudices, fringed with epigram, of G. K. C.
A mere catalogue of a few of the well-known writers
represented, of <name rend="sc">Symons</name>, <name rend="sc">Galsworthy</name>, <name rend="sc">Gilbert Murray</name>,
<name rend="sc">Bagot</name>, <name rend="sc">Hichiens</name>, <name rend="sc">Barry Bain</name>,
<name rend="sc">Phillpotts</name>; and of artists
such as <name rend="sc">Brangwyn</name>, <name rend="sc">Sargent</name>, <name rend="sc">Shannon</name>, <name rend="sc">John</name>,
<name rend="sc">Lavery</name>,
<name rend="sc">Richmond</name>, <name rend="sc">Poynter</name>, <name rend="sc">Frampton</name>, <name rend="sc">Ricketts</name>,
<name rend="sc">Anning Bell</name>,
<name rend="sc">Cayley Robinson</name>, makes its best testimonial. England
has never been other than the friend of modern Italy, for
the Triple Alliance was merely a freak of desperate diplomacy
and was broken by the popular will when Germany (be
it remembered) was giving fair promise of ultimate victory.
We don't need conversion to the cause of Italy, but everything
that helps to foster and develop the comradeship of
the now <title>Risorgimento</title> of the Allied Nations is welcome.
And <title>The Book of Italy</title> will serve this purpose excellently
well.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>More than once before now I have commented upon
that almost unique gift that Mr. <name rend="sc">Jack London</name> has of
transferring physical energy to fiction. His characters
must always be about some sinew-straining business that
makes the reader ache in sympathy. However in <title>The
Little Lady of the Big House</title> (<name rend="sc">Mills and Boon</name>) the author
seems to have allowed himself and his creations an unwonted
holiday. Here is no fierce struggle for existence,
but the fruits of it upon a millionaire ranche in California.
<title>Dick Forrest</title> was the millionaire, by heritage and his own
success; a great farmer and a breeder of shires. He had a
wife, the <title>Little Lady</title> of the title, and a Big House that was
one of the most eligible dwellings in fiction. A plain recital
of the arrangements ("tweaks" we should have called them
at school) in <title>Dick's</title> open-air bedroom makes the ordinary
home look like ten cents. Mr. <name rend="sc">London</name> certainly knows
how to luxuriate when he gives his mind to it. Moreover
there was a wonderful swimming-bath, with a concealed
submarine chamber in which the <title>Little Lady</title> used to hide
for the terror of uninstructed guests (she was rather that
<pb xml:id="page304" n="pg 304"/>
kind of person), and a great music-room for her to play
<name rend="sc">Rachmaninoff</name> in and flirt with the Other Man. This is
all the tale. Eventually the flirtation becomes serious
and the <title>Little Lady</title> is driven to suicide, with a death scene
of rather unconvincing sentiment. The fact is, I am afraid,
that Capuan ease does not altogether suit the super-strenuous
beings whom Mr. <name rend="sc">Jack London</name> designs. They are
too energetic for it, and, lacking an outlet, tend to become
melodramatic. I hope that next time he will take us back
to the muscle-grinding.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>When the War broke out Mr. F. W. <name rend="sc">Wile</name>, an American
gentleman, was living in Berlin as the correspondent of
<title>The Daily Mail</title>. Having read his book, <title>The Assault</title>
(<name rend="sc">Heinemann</name>), I may say that I judge him to be singularly
alert and wide-awake and admirably fitted for the position
he occupied. He has no scintilla
of hatred or animosity for the
German people as individuals,
but he wishes to see Germany
beaten. "I wish her beaten,"
he says, "for the Allies' sake
and for my own country's sake.
A victorious Germany would be
a menace to international liberty
and become automatically a
threat to the happiness and
freedom of the United States."
He saw the furious transports
of patriotism and hatred to
which the Berlin mob gave
way; he witnessed the brutal
attack on the British Embassy,
and he was himself denounced
as an English spy, was arrested
and was lodged in jail, whence
he was rescued only by the
direct interposition of the American
Ambassador. All these
incidents he relates in a very
vivid way and with a certain
dry humour that adds to the
effect. His description of the
manner in which, on his way
to prison in a taxi with two
German policemen, he managed
to destroy a telegraph code
which was in his breast pocket,
is positively thrilling. Had it
been discovered on him, nothing,
he thinks, would have availed to
save him, so delirious were his
captors with rage and suspicion. Certainly a delightful
people. Finally he was allowed to leave Berlin and travel
to England as a member of Sir <name rend="sc">Edward Goschen's</name> party.
In the later portion of this book Mr. <name rend="sc">Wile</name> castigates us, not
too unkindly, but, perhaps, a little too insistently, for not
being ready, for not realising what war means and for being
self-complacent. Since his criticisms are based on affection
for us we can make an effort to kiss the rod, especially
as he discerns signs of improvement in us. Incidentally
I may add that he is, perhaps, not altogether fair to Lord
<name rend="sc">Haldane</name>, but, <title>per contra</title>, he gives Lord <name rend="sc">Northcliffe</name> a
high testimonial to character and behaviour.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>
                        <title>Cordelia</title> (<name rend="sc">Melrose</name>) is a story as agreeable as its name,
or as the pretty, if rather chocolate-box-school, picture on
its wrapper. One small defect I find in the dissipation of its
interest. Beginning with one hero, it goes on with another;
and the result is some confusion for the reader who
has backed the wrong horse. But Mr. E. M. <name rend="sc">Smith-Dampier</name>
might very justly retort that this is but fidelity
to life. When in the early chapters we see the first hero
turned from home by an unsympathetic parent, and
faring forth to seek romance in a new world, it was
surely reasonable to suppose that he would eventually be
rewarded by the pretty lady of the wrapper, especially as
<title>Savile Brand</title> (though his name inevitably suggests tobacco)
is a character drawn with understanding and skill. But
Mr. <name rend="sc">Smith-Dampier</name> is good at lovers. He has another,
even better, up his sleeve. This is <title>Peter</title>, the forty-year-old
American cousin, who cherishes a tender regard for
<title>Mistress Cordelia</title>. I should explain that all this happened
in the time of powder, lace coats, and witches. This last
is important. Those were the days when <title>Cherchez la
sorcière</title> was the unfailing remedy
in New England for every
ill, material or emotional. It is
from this, coupled with the mistaken
jealousy of her sister, that
<title>Cordelia's</title> troubles come, and so
nearly turn her story to tragedy.
The main motive may remind
you a little of that grim play
of witchcraft that we saw at
the St. James's Theatre some
years ago. But fortunately
the end is more comfortable.
<title>Cordelia</title>, in short, is a
nicely-flavoured romance of old
America, with at least three
unusually well-drawn characters
to give it substance. I have no
doubt at all of its success.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e2244" type="div3">
                    <head>OUR ECONOMISTS.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/304.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Lady Poore's</name>
                        <title>Recollections
of an Admiral's Wife</title> (<name rend="sc">Smith,
Elder</name>) is as excellent a book of
its kind as readers of <title>Punch</title> are
likely to find reviewed in a month
of Wednesdays. Scrapbooks of reminiscences
are so often dumped
upon a surfeited world that it
is at once a pleasure and a duty
to draw attention to a volume
of real worth and significance.
Wherever <name rend="sc">Lady Poore</name> was living—whether
in Australia before
the War or in Chatham after
August, 1915—her main object
was to arrive at a sympathetic
understanding of the people with whom she had to deal, and,
without a hint of patronage, to be of service to them. It is
impossible to read of the work she did and helped to do
during the last dozen years or so without recognising how
possible it is to be official and still remain very human. In
spite of little outbursts of opinion which refuse to be suppressed,
Lady <name rend="sc">Poore</name> is as discreet as the most censorious
of censors could desire. One of her anecdotes—for the
most part well told and fresh—is as funny a tale as I have
I ever encountered; but I will leave you to find it for yourself.
Altogether a book to thank the gods for.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"On the way to Berea, Mr. Lloyd George met the Rector of the
parish, and both cordially shook hands."—<title>Scotsman.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Are we to infer that as a rule, when these two gentlemen
meet, only one of them shakes hands?</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>