<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Punch, or the London Charivari, Vol. 150, February 2, 1916</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <idno type="gutenberg">22313</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>This text is freely available for re-use under US and UK law, consult
                            your local legal restrictions if elsewhere.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This text is a TEI version of a Project Gutenberg text originally located at
                            <ptr target="http://www.gutenberg.org/dirs/2/2/3/1/22313/"/>. As per their license agreement we have removed
                        all references to the project's trademark, however have included this
                        pointer to the original in case you want the plain text, or their XHTML
                        version. </p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2008-06-27T16:12:47.863+01:00"/>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:id="d1e44" type="div2">
                <head>CHARIVARIA.</head>
                <p>According to the Correspondent of <title>The Daily Mail</title> who
described the festivities at Nish, the King of <name rend="sc">Bulgaria</name> "has a curious duck-like waddle." This is
believed to be the result of his effort to do the Goose-Step while
avoiding the Turkey-Trot.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Owing to the extraction of benzol and toluol from gas for the
purpose of making high-explosives it is stated that consumers may
have to put up with some decrease in illuminating power. It is
expected, in view of the good object involved, that the
announcement will be received in a spirit of toluoleration.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>We cannot agree with the actor who complains that his manager
forbids him to wear his armlet on the stage. The sympathies of the
audience might be entirely deranged by the discovery that the
elderly villain was an attested patriot while the young and
beautiful hero was either ineligible or a slacker.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Describing the depressed condition of the laundry trade a
witness at the Clerkenwell County Court said, "We are eight million
double collars short every week." It is shrewdly conjectured that
they are in the neighbourhood of the Front.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Nothing in the course of his Balkan pilgrimage is reported to
have pleased the <name rend="sc">Kaiser</name> so much as a
steamer-trip on the Danube. It was looking so sympathetically
blue.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The Government is going to close Museums and Picture-galleries
to the public. No one shall accuse us of being Apostles of
Culture.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>It is said that the Australian and New Zealand soldiers now in
London are very fond of visiting the British Museum, and take a
particular interest in the Egyptian antiquities. But it is not true
that they now refer to England as "The Mummy Country."</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Austrians and Hungarians are said to be quarrelling as to
whether the occupied Serbian territory should eventually belong to
the Monarchy or the Kingdom, and the jurists on either side are
ransacking the history of the past for arguments to support their
respective cases. Here we have another instance of the fondness of
learned men for disputing about purely academic questions. Serbia
will belong to the Serbians.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>An American gentleman, who started out to visit his wife when
she was staying with her mother and failed to find her after three
days' search, excuses himself on the ground that he had forgotten
her maiden name. He puts it down to absence of mind; and his
mother-in-law is inclined to agree with him.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Soap is the latest article to be placed on the list of absolute
contraband; and it is now more certain than ever that the Germans
will not come out of the War with clean hands.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>In view of the impending paper-famine a widely-circulated
journal announces its readiness to receive back from the public any
parcels of old copies marked "waste paper." In the opinion of its
trade-rivals the inscription is superfluous.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A suggestion has been made by a Registrar in Bankruptcy that the
Tercentenary of <name rend="sc">Shakspeare's</name> death
should be celebrated by the performance in every large town of one
of the Bard's plays; and some regret has been expressed that
anybody should take advantage of a national celebration to boom his
own business.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"'How many of us realise that, were it not for America, the War
to-day in Europe, as fought, could not even exist?'" is the
question put, according to a New York correspondent, "by Mr. Gutzon
Borglum, the great American sculptor." Still the War has its
compensations. But for its existence we might never have heard of
Mr. <name rend="sc">Gutzon Borglum</name>, the great American
sculptor.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A correspondent, describing the recent food riots in Berlin,
says that they were chiefly due to "women who were fed up with the
difficulty of providing meals for their families."</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The following notice was found affixed to a building somewhere
near the Front: "<hi rend="sc">Sir Officers</hi>,—Ask
the bathroom's key to the office. The bathroom shall be wash by the
servant after bath. Sir Officer without servant shall not have the
key." It sounds rather abrupt.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Owing to the Government demand that nothing in the way of
unnecessary expenditure should be allowed, it is expected that all
paid lecturers on War Economy and National Thrift will be given a
week's notice.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Opposing a suggestion of the Wandsworth Borough Council to
discontinue the issue of fiction from the free libraries, a member
of the Women's Freedom League said that a novel was to a woman what
a pipe was to a man. Well, not quite, perhaps. We never saw a man
begin a pipe at the wrong end.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/81-300.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>From an article by Mr. <name rend="sc">Austin
Harrison</name> in <title>The Sunday Pictorial</title>:—</p>
                <quote>"A few strange gentlemen attitudinise in Westminster on
principle, but these men would cut capers of principle in any case,
like Mr. Snodgrass when he went skating."</quote>
                <p>Or <title>Mr. Winkle</title> when he wrote verses.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>"In the Continental boat-trains the warning, 'Licht
linauslehnen,' has not been removed from the windows...
Occasionally you see that 'Nicht linauslehnen' has been
indignantly pasted over."</quote>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Provincial
Paper.</title>
                </bibl>
                <p>The latter is certainly a little more German than the other.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>After a description of the new lighting order:—</p>
                <quote>"The regulations will impose a great deal of work on
the police, and it is the duty of the public to make it as light as
possible."</quote>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Hampshire Observer.</title>
                </bibl>
                <p>
                    <title>Lux</title>, in fact, <title>a non lucendo</title>.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e217" type="div3">
                    <head>A Lonely Life.</head>
                    <quote>"Nothing but margarine has entered my door since the
War began."</quote>
                    <bibl>
                        <author>Dr. C. W. Saleeby</author>
in <title>Daily Chronicle</title>.</bibl>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page82" n="pg 82"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e235" type="div2">
                <head>THE WATCH DOGS.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e239" type="div3">
                    <head>XXXIV.</head>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">My dear Charles</name>,—We're having a
great time with our new arrival, one of those confounded civilians,
who are only let into the business because the business, in these
modern and highly complicated days, cannot be carried on without
them. He's a jolly old Lieutenant of about fifty years; he has a
concentrated experience of the world but doesn't remember having
been mixed up in a big European war before. At first I kept on
telling him that business is one thing and war is another, but he
wouldn't see it and persisted in doing and saying and thinking
things which were bound to land us in a national disaster. He had
no respect whatever for the Pass Memo., his central and sole idea
being to push along with the elimination of the Bosch. When he
wanted something done, he just went to the Top-man of the
department, called him "I say," and went straight to the point. The
Top-man had never been asked to do business this way before.</p>
                    <p>He put up with it a dozen times or so, but finally he had to
take steps. So he wrote a little note on a Buff slip and addressed
it, very rightly of course, to the Top-man but one; and the Top-man
but one read it and passed it very carefully to the Top-man but
two; and so, with that inevitability which is the hall-mark of the
system, it was passed and passed and passed until it came (in less
than a week) to the office of the ancient Lieutenant on the
opposite side of the street. And it ran: "Lieutenant So-and-So
should be notified that it is neither necessary nor desirable that
he should call personally at this office to transact his business.
Matters should be put forward by him through the usual course of
correspondence." The ancient Lieutenant, who wouldn't hurt
anybody's feelings for the world, felt that it was up to him to put
the matter right. So he stepped across to the Top-man's office, and
when the Top-man asked him, somewhat pointedly, if he had received
his note, the Ancient very genially replied, "Yes, thank you," and
explained that he had just looked in personally to acknowledge
receipt of same.</p>
                    <p>It sounds as if a dreadful quarrel would be raging between the
Ancient on one side and on the other the Top-man, the whole series
of under-Top-men and all persons in any way representing the
military system. You'd expect to hear that the Ancient's
conversation at mess is insubordinate, rebellious, or at least
bitterly sarcastic. No such thing; the old gentleman becomes a more
ardent militarist every day; wants to see once for all an end of
all lawyer-politicians, and all so-called "business-men." "We have
made a poor show of being civilians," is his point; "let's try
being soldiers for a generation or two."</p>
                    <p>On the whole he thinks we should find it easier to carry on as a
British Empire in uniform than as a German province in mufti. He
says that what's wrong with Prussian Militarism is that it is
Prussian; to succeed, the thing has to be run by gentlemen.</p>
                    <p>A Top-man honoured our mess the other night. Under the mellowing
influence of our Curried Bully he unbent somewhat and encouraged
the Ancient on his pet subject. Under the influence of the latter's
theories he unbent still further. He discoursed upon the true
inwardness of the military method of running an office, pausing at
last for the Ancient to say a few words. "Oh," said he, "I don't
allow myself to be put off by a trifle like that. There's many a
kind heart behind a Buff slip, and we all have our little
weaknesses." The idea of having a little weakness was so novel to
the Top-man that it caused him to choke and to be led from the
mess, eventually, in a state of nervous exhaustion.</p>
                    <p>The latest information from the trenches goes to support the
maxim that all one requires to wage war is a bold face and a gas
helmet. A very distinguished O.C. went up the other day to inspect
the trenches of his command and to express such views of their
faults and the faults of their inmates as might occur to him from
time to time. He had progressed some way up the communication
trench, when it struck him that, whereas his recent order had been
particularly menacing to everyone of whatever rank who was
discovered there or thereabouts without a gas helmet, nevertheless
he himself was at that moment innocent of such furniture.
Fortunately there came from the opposite direction an odds-and-end
private, with nothing in his favour except the wearing of the
well-known satchel so much in vogue in Flanders society for the
carrying of gas helmets. That was enough for the Commander; this
was essentially one of those privates to be called "My man," and
treated as such. Politely but firmly he was requested to part with
his satchel as a temporary loan to his General. Firmly, if
respectfully, he refused to comply. Them was his orders. The
Commander congratulated him on his very proper attitude, explained
to him the nature of the higher commands and demanded the satchel.
The man looked like being stony about it, but the Commander became
irresistibly commanding and got the satchel at last. He buckled it
on, and the party proceeded, characterising the reluctance of the
private to part with his treasure as almost an exaggerated sense of
obedience to printed orders.</p>
                    <p>Gas helmets always exercise a peculiar fascination for people
who inspect trenches, and the matter was now especially prominent
in the mind of the Commander as he marched along, outwardly
appearing to be at his happiest here, inwardly thanking goodness
that his home was elsewhere. Conceive his delight to discover a
subaltern, fresh from ablutions, with no satchel upon him! The
subaltern, distinctly aware of this amongst his many failings, was
all for being passed by as insignificant; the Commander was all for
a scene. Everybody halted, and the air became pregnant with
possibilities.... It was a nicely calculated speech, leading up
gradually to the pointed contrast between (<hi rend="it">a</hi>) overworked
Commander, weighed down with responsibilities, absorbed day and
night in momentous matters of large principle, nevertheless
infallible on smallest detail and now in possession of gas helmet,
one, and (<hi rend="it">b</hi>) very junior subaltern, free to enjoy the
open-air irresponsible life of the trenches, yet neglecting even
the few small matters entrusted to him, without same.</p>
                    <p>"And what's more, Sir," he concluded, "I doubt very much
whether, if someone gave you a helmet now, you'd know what to do
with it. Here, take mine." (The attendant Brass-hats liked the
"mine," but very discreetly kept their emotions to themselves.)</p>
                    <p>It was not a peculiarly clean or remarkably well-packed satchel
which the trembling hand of the disgraced subaltern took from the
Commander, and the latter did not intend to let attention dwell too
long upon the grimy details of its exterior. Fixing the steel eye
of conscious rectitude on his victim, he leant slightly towards him
and very unmistakably shouted at him the one dread word,
"<name rend="sc">Gas!</name>".... Unfortunately for the
Commander the subaltern not only knew what to do next, but also had
just the physical strength remaining in his fingers to start doing
it. With the eyes of all upon him (and by this time there had
gathered round quite a nice little crowd, thoroughly conversant
with the event in progress), the subaltern opened the satchel
alleged to belong to the Commander and took from it—no,
Charles, not a gas helmet, but a pair of socks—and
<hi rend="it">such</hi> socks too!</p>
                    <signed>Yours ever, <name rend="sc">Henry</name>.</signed>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page83" n="pg 83"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/83-600.png"/>
                        <head>SINKING.</head>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page84" n="pg 84"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e309" type="div2">
                <head>ON BELLONA'S HEM.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e313" type="div3">
                    <head>
                        <name rend="sc">The Misfire.</name>
                    </head>
                    <p>When I entered the third smoker there was, as there now always
is, a soldier in one corner.</p>
                    <p>Just as we were starting, another soldier got in and sat in the
opposite corner. The freemasonry of Khaki immediately setting to
work, within two minutes they knew all about each other's camp,
destination and regiment, and had exchanged cigarettes.</p>
                    <p>The first soldier had not yet left England and was stolid; the
newcomer had been in the trenches, had been wounded in the leg, had
recovered, was shortly going back, and was animated. His leg was
all right, except that in wet weather it ached. In fact he could
even tell by it when we were going to have rain. His "blooming
barometer" he called it. Here he laughed—a hearty laugh, for
he was a genial blade and liked to hear himself talk.</p>
                    <p>The first soldier did not laugh, but was interested. He thought
it a convenient thing to have a leg that foretold the weather.</p>
                    <p>"Which one is it?" he asked.</p>
                    <p>"The left."</p>
                    <p>The first soldier was disproportionately impressed.</p>
                    <p>"The left, is it?" he said heavily, as though he would have
understood the phenomenon in the right easily enough. "The
left."</p>
                    <p>Completely unconscious of the danger-signals, the second soldier
now began to unload his repertory of stories, and he started off
with that excellent one, very popular in the early days of the War,
about the wealthy private.</p>
                    <p>For the sake of verisimilitude he laid the scene in his own
barracks. "A funny thing happened at our place the other day," he
began. He had evidently had great success with this story. His
expression indicated approaching triumph.</p>
                    <p>But no anticipatory gleam lit the face of his new friend. It was
in fact one of those faces into which words sink as into a
sandbank—a white, puffy, long face, with a moustache of
obsolete bushiness.</p>
                    <p>"I thought I should have died of laughing," the other resumed,
utterly unsuspicious, wholly undeterred.</p>
                    <p>In the far corner I kept my eye on my book but my ears open. I
could see that he was rushing to his doom.</p>
                    <p>"We were being paid," he went on, "and the quartermaster asked
one of the men if he did not wish sixpence to be deducted to go to
his wife. The man said, 'No.' 'Why not?' the quartermaster asked.
The man said he didn't think his wife would need it or miss it.
'You'd better be generous about it,' the quartermaster said; 'every
little helps, you know.'"</p>
                    <p>He paused. "What do you think the man said to that?" he asked
his new friend. "He said," he hurried on, "'I don't think I'll send
it. You see, I allow her four thousand a year as it is.'"</p>
                    <p>The <hi rend="it">raconteur</hi> laughed loudly and leaned back with the
satisfaction—or at least some of it—of one who has told
a funny story and told it well.</p>
                    <p>But the other did not laugh at all. His face remained the dull
thing it was.</p>
                    <p>"You see," said the story-teller, explaining the point, "there
are all sorts in the Army now, and this man was a toff. He was so
rich that he could afford to allow his wife four thousand pounds a
year. Four thousand pounds! Do you see?"</p>
                    <p>"Oh, yes, I see that. He must have been very rich. Why was he
just a private?"</p>
                    <p>"I don't know."</p>
                    <p>"Funny being a private with all that money. I wonder you didn't
ask him."</p>
                    <p>"I didn't, anyway. But you see the point now. No end of a joke
for the quartermaster to try and get a man who allowed his wife
four thousand a year to deduct sixpence a week to send to her! I
thought I should have died of laughing."</p>
                    <p>The first soldier remained impassive. "And what happened?" he
asked at last.</p>
                    <p>"What happened?"</p>
                    <p>"Yes, what was done about it? The sixpence, I mean. Did he agree
to send it?"</p>
                    <p>The second soldier pulled himself together. "Oh, I don't know,"
he said shortly. "That's not the point."</p>
                    <p>"After all," the other continued, "the regulations say that
married men have to deduct sixpence for their wives, don't
they?"</p>
                    <p>"Yes, of course," the other replied. "But this man, I tell you,
already gave her four thousand a year."</p>
                    <p>"That doesn't really touch it," said the first soldier. "The
principle's the same. Now——"</p>
                    <p>But I could stand the humiliation of the other honest fellow, so
brimming with anecdote and cheerfulness, no longer; and I came to
his rescue with my cigarette case. For I have had misfires myself
too often.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/84-300.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>Mrs. Ruth Roberts, of Folkestone, celebrates the
completion of her 103rd year to-day. She is one of a family of
twenty-two, and her father fought with two of her sons at
Waterloo.</p>
                    </quote>
                    <bibl>
                        <title>Irish Times.</title>
                    </bibl>
                    <p>She seems to have been very young for a mother when these family
dissensions occurred.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>"Will you allow me to give a warning to Ford owners
who, like myself, jack up to obtain an easy start. A few days ago I
was doing so as usual with only one scotch. The car jumped the
jack, went over the scotch, knocked me down, ran over me, tore my
clothes to rags, bruised me all over, tore my flesh and broke my
collar-bone, and I think I got off very lightly. Of course that
will not happen to me again."</p>
                    </quote>
                    <bibl>—<title>The Motor.</title>
                    </bibl>
                    <p>He will either drink the Scotch first or not have one at
all.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page85" n="pg 85"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e457" type="div2">
                <head>THE FAUNA OF THE FRONT.</head>
                <p>Chief among the fauna of the Front is, of course, the Bosch, a
subterranean animal of unpleasant habits, which is now classed as
vermin. He has been so thoroughly dealt with elsewhere that I shall
leave him on one side, and confine my few observations to smaller
and pleasanter creatures. The remaining fauna of the Front are (1)
mice; (2) rats; with a few interesting extras, furred and
feathered, which deserve more serious treatment than I can give
them.</p>
                <p>At home the mouse is regarded with contemptuous annoyance as a
petty but persevering thief; while the rat commits his grosser
depredations in an atmosphere tinged with horror. Out here it is
different, for we are perforce neighbours. Indeed, we bipeds are in
a sense trespassers upon the domain of the subterranean peoples. At
home one seldom sees a rat or mouse save from above, and to look
down upon anything is invariably to misjudge it. But here we share
the hospitality of the underground and meet its freehold tenants on
a level.</p>
                <p>From the earth walls of the sanctuary where this small tribute
is written mice look down upon our table with its newspaper cover,
diffidently waiting for us to finish our meal and permit them to
dine. We regard them as shy visitors—though are we not
billeted on them?—not as sneaking thieves, and by the light
of our candles perceive how sleek, bright-eyed, neat-handed and
agile they are. In one dug-out I know a certain mouse who will drop
on your shoulder and sit there a while in the friendliest manner,
trying in his tiny modest way to play the host. Up above, in the
open air, they are to be seen in swarms sharing our watchfulness.
This gun-shaken valley is honeycombed with their little round
funk-holes, into which they flash at any sudden noise. It is merely
going downstairs where we are all at home.</p>
                <p>The social instincts of the rat are less highly developed. His
visible visits to the mess are rarer, but we overhear his
conversation in his tunnels that open on our shelves, the patter of
his pink feet across the canvas overhead, and the muscular
squirming of his body in some tight place about the sandbag
wainscot. Like a friendly dog he trots about your dug-out by night,
bumping with trustful carelessness against the fragile legs of your
rustic bed. You hear him crooning to himself or a pal, in his
content—a placid, complacent little sound very different from
the grating squeak or squeal of the unhappy Ishmaels you used to
know. Certainly he will help himself to a little cake, if such a
thing is to be had, for he feels at home, as he doubtless wishes
you to do. If you do not care to share your dainties, you can hang
them from the roof.</p>
                <p>In the trenches themselves the rat is almost a domestic animal.
Town rats are lean, persecuted and vicious; nobody loves them. But
those who hobnob with us here are fed, like our Army, on Army
rations, together with more than their share of private luxuries,
and consequently are stout and contented-looking, and display none
of the ill-bred and disconcerting haste of the hereditary fugitive
of our drains and cellars. If you happen to stand still and silent
for a few moments, you will hear some cheery old rascal come
sniffing and grunting along the parapet, not so much in search of
food as to enjoy the air—or so his manner would indicate.</p>
                <p>Between the Army and these other dwellers in earths and burrows
there must henceforth be a bond of true sympathy.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/85-400.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>
                    <title>La Grèce Antique</title>: Hellas. <title>La Grèce
Moderne: Hélas!</title>
                </p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>To be added to our collection "Glimpses of the
Obvious":—
         <quote>"We feel more than ever that the Past is all behind us
and the Future all in front."</quote>—<title>Reading
Standard.</title>
                </p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>From a trade circular:—</p>
                <quote>"We are installing 15 of our largest size Patent
Fool-proof Steam Kettles at Woolwich Arsenal."</quote>
                <p>Zeppelin crews please note.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page86" n="pg 86"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e526" type="div2">
                <head>LAST THOUGHTS ON GALLIPOLI.</head>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Once more sits Mahomet by Helles' marges</l>
                        <l rend="i2">And smokes at ease among his cypress-trees,</l>
                        <l>Nor snipes from scrubberies at British targes</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Nor views them wallowing in sacred seas,</l>
                        <l>But cleans his side-arms and is pleased to prattle</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Of that great morning when he woke and heard</l>
                        <l>That in his slumbers he had fought a battle,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">A bloody battle, and a little bird</l>
                        <l>Piped (in the German) at his side, and said,</l>
                        <l>"The something infidels have been and fled."</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Cautious he crept from out his mountain-ditches,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Down the long gully, past the Water Towers;</l>
                        <l>By Backhouse Point he nosed among the niches,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">But they were hushed, and innocent of Giaours;</l>
                        <l>Still fearful found the earthy homes we haunted,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Those thirsty stretches where the rest-camps
were,</l>
                        <l>Then to the sea slunk on, a trifle daunted</l>
                        <l rend="i2">By wreathéd wires and every sort of snare,</l>
                        <l>And came at last, incredulous, to find</l>
                        <l>The very beach all blasphemously mined.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Now on each hand he eyes our impious labels,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">
                            <name rend="sc">Bond Street</name> and
<name rend="sc">Regent Street</name>, those weary ways;</l>
                        <l>Here stands the <name rend="sc">Pink Farm</name>, with the
broken gables,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Here <name rend="sc">Oxford Circus</name> marks a
winding maze;</l>
                        <l>But most, I ween, in scarred grave-ridden regions</l>
                        <l rend="i2">O'er many a battle-scene he loves to brood,</l>
                        <l>How Allah here was gracious to his legions,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">How here, again, he was not quite so good,</l>
                        <l>Here by the <name rend="sc">Brown House</name>, when the
bombs began,</l>
                        <l>And they—don't mention it—they turned and ran.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>And we no more shall see the great ships gather,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Nor hear their thundering on days of state,</l>
                        <l>Nor toil from trenches in an honest lather</l>
                        <l rend="i2">To magic swimmings in the perfect Strait;</l>
                        <l>Nor sip Greek wine and see the slow sun dropping</l>
                        <l rend="i2">On gorgeous evenings over Imbros' Isle,</l>
                        <l>While up the hill that maxim will keep popping,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">And the men sing, and camp-fires wink awhile,</l>
                        <l>And in the scrub the glow-worms glow like stars,</l>
                        <l>But (hopeless creatures) will not light cigars;</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Nor daylong linger in our delvéd lodges,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">And fight for food with fifty thousand flies,</l>
                        <l>Too sick and sore to be afraid of "proj's,"</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Too dazed with dust to see the turquoise skies;</l>
                        <l>Nor walk at even by the busy beaches,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Or quiet cliff-paths where the Indians pray,</l>
                        <l>And see the sweepers in the sky-blue reaches</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Of Troy's own water, where the Greek ships lay,</l>
                        <l>And touch the boat-hulks, where they float forlorn,</l>
                        <l>The wounded boats of that first April morn;</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Nor wake unhappily to see the sun come</l>
                        <l rend="i2">And stand to arms in some Cimmerian grot—</l>
                        <l>But I, in town, well rid of all that bunkum,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">I like to think that Mahomet is not;</l>
                        <l>He must sit on, now sweltering, now frozen,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">By many a draughty cliff and mountain holt,</l>
                        <l>And, when rude fears afflict the Prophet's chosen,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Gird on his arms and madly work his bolt,</l>
                        <l>While round the heights the awful whispers run,</l>
                        <l>"<title>The bard of <name rend="sc">Punch</name> is landing with
his gun.</title>"</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e761" type="div3">
                    <head>Condescension.</head>
                    <p>"<name rend="sc">Through stress of war</name> Baronet's
Niece will <name rend="sc">order</name> a Gentleman's
<name rend="sc">Household</name>."—<title>The Times.</title>
                    </p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e782" type="div2">
                <head>UNWRITTEN LETTERS TO THE KAISER.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e786" type="div3">
                    <head>No. XXXIV.</head>
                    <div xml:id="d1e790" type="div4">
                        <head>(<title>From the Frau Professor <name rend="sc">Tintenklecks</name>.</title>)</head>
                        <p>
                            <name rend="sc">All-Mightiest Kaiser</name>,—With the
humblest assurance of my everlasting respect I desire to lay bare
to you, since you are without doubt the Father of your People, my
inmost thoughts as to this terrible War in which we have now for
eighteen months been engaged. I have some right, I think, for my
husband is that same Professor Tintenklecks whose <hi rend="it">opusculum</hi>
on "International Law in Relation to World Power" was received with
special favour by your Majesty, who summoned the beloved writer to
your Palace, and with your own gracious right hand were pleased to
beat him with some force on his back, saying that "this
Tintenklecks is a tremendous fellow, and there should be more such
in the world." How well I remember that evening—it was a year
before the War—and how in honour of the Professor we had a
Poetry supper, at which each guest recited some verses of praise,
and at the end little Amalie Siegeltisch, the daughter of our
colleague, placed on the brows of the Professor a laurel-wreath
which, however, pricked his with-much-hair-unadorned head, and had
therefore, after a great deal of pleasant witticisms, to be taken
off.</p>
                        <p>So when the War at last broke out my husband and I were amongst
the loudest Hosannah-shouters and singers of true German patriotic
songs, for we believed then that the War would be a short one, and
that after a few great victories we should make a brilliant peace
on our own terms, having utterly smashed all our enemies and having
taken England's war-ships and her colonies for our own. "Long he
cannot last," said my Professor, speaking of the War. "The French
are a degenerate race, and we shall be in Paris in a month. The
English are given up to games, and their mercenary army—I
have it on the highest authority—cannot for a moment stand
against our German heroes. The Russians are slow and disorganised
and useless for war. For me you need not be afraid, my dear. In
this war a man of my age will not be required." So he spoke; and
now where is he and what has become of him? He has lost a leg, his
right hand has been shot through, and he is in a hospital in
Poland. Shall I ever see him again, I wonder.</p>
                        <p>Well, we have had victories in plenty, according to the
Generals. Every time we move from one place to another we gain, it
seems, an overwhelming triumph and cause to fly every one who is
opposed to us. Twice already your Majesty has announced that before
the leaves fell from the trees there would be peace, and our brave
soldiers would return safely to their homes; but, alas, it has not
so happened, and the dreadful fighting still goes on, and many
thousands of our women lose their fathers, their husbands, and
their sons. With every victory (as they call it) peace, which
should be nearer at hand, seems to retire further and further away,
and only sorrow and wretchedness come close to us. And that is not
all. Our food, like everything else we have to buy, is so dear that
we women find it above all things difficult to provide ourselves
with what we need for our daily life, and the worst of it, they
say, has not yet come. I could understand that if we had been
defeated; but we have been ever victorious and yet we are in want.
It is useless for Pastor Hassmann to tell us on Sundays that we
must endure to the end. We are prepared to do what we can, but we
think, too, that since we have been so magnificently victorious we
should have peace quickly, so that we may all once more try to have
some happiness in this world.</p>
                        <p>I remain, in the deepest devotion,</p>
                        <signed>Your loyal, <name rend="sc">Kunegunde
Tintenklecks</name>.</signed>
                        <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                        <pb xml:id="page87" n="pg 87"/>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e829" type="div2">
                <head>MR. PUNCH'S POTTED FILMS. THE DOMESTIC DRAMA.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e833" type="div3">
                    <head>WHAT A LITTLE CHILD CAN DO.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/87-1-300.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/87-2-300.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/87-3-300.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/87-4-300.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/87-5-300.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/87-6-300.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page88" n="pg 88"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/88-600.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e879" type="div2">
                <head>MEDITATIONS OF MARCUS O'REILLY.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e883" type="div3">
                    <head>
                        <name rend="sc">Lucy.</name>
                    </head>
                    <p>We called her Lucy because she came from the country and "dwelt
on a wide moor." We never knew her real name.</p>
                    <p>She came like a ray of sunlight into our dull sordid town once a
week with immaculate white apron, wearing a cap of an older,
honester world, carrying a basket of delicious country butter made
up in appetising rolls. On the clean napkin which covered the top
of the basket always reposed a huge door-key, "to keep," she said,
"the butter from turning." And the white hair of her and those
wonderful blue eyes which looked you through and through! No wonder
my wife was in love with her and refused from that time to eat the
dull town-grocer's wares.</p>
                    <p>My wife often muses as to the real cause of the general
superiority of dwellers in the country over the apologies for
humanity who live in towns. She says it is moral fibre. She comes
from the country herself and is quite unbiassed. For me I think it
must be living so much amongst sheep and lambs and woolly
things.</p>
                    <p>I shouldn't have said myself that our town butter was without
fibre, but this is a matter of taste.</p>
                    <p>My wife would often close her eyes when eating Lucy and conjure
up pictures of her own simple girlhood days, of the country
rectory, of the rooks singing matins and vespers in the trees.
Country people often get like this over an egg at breakfast. I
didn't eat Lucy myself, as my taste is ruined by my vicious town
breeding; besides, Lucy was a luxury in war-time, and Dossett's
Genuine Creamery has for me a meatier savour.</p>
                    <p>Cecilia always gave Lucy more than the market value for her
butter and a cup of tea besides, while they chatted occasionally
over things dear to rural hearts, accidents by flood and field,
turnips and parochial vestries. My wife used to marvel at the
superior firmness of Lucy's butter, which was ever the same, Lucy's
explanation being that she had a wonderfully cool hand.</p>
                    <p>Our local inspector, a man of the latest and most scientific
knowledge, confirmed this statement. In introducing Lucy to our
resident magistrate he said she was the coolest hand he had ever
known. It was a bad case. It had ten per cent. too much of this,
and fifteen per cent. too much of that, and the rest was the
cheapest margarine and stirring. There wasn't a cow within five
miles of her place and he didn't believe she had ever seen one.</p>
                    <p>We haven't met Lucy since. My wife says that <name rend="sc">Wordsworth</name> was often taken in, just like that. And
she has heard, anyhow, that Lucy was born in Bradford. So that it
proves nothing.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>Hymn for Volunteer Corps digging trenches for the defence of
London:—
         <quote>"O Parados! O Parados! 'tis weary working
here!"</quote>
                    </p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>"The baby should go out every day, except when it is
storming."</quote>—<title>New York Sunday Herald.</title>
                    <p>In that case try a wind-pill.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>To-day's Russian communiqué
says:—</p>
                        <p>In Persia, on the road to Kermanshah, we have occupied
the town of Kangavar.</p>
                        <p>Note.—Kangavar is a town of 15¾
inhabitants in the Province of Ardilan."</p>
                    </quote>—<title>Aberdeen Evening
Express.</title>
                    <p>This is carrying accuracy to an extreme, even for Scotland.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page89" n="pg 89"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/89-600.png"/>
                        <head>THE CHALLENGE.</head>
                        <head>"HALT! WHO COMES THERE?" "NEUTRAL." "PROVE IT!"</head>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page90" n="pg 90"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e975" type="div2">
                <head>ESSENCE OF PARLIAMENT.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e979" type="div3">
                    <head>(<name rend="sc">Extracted from the Diary of Toby,
M.P.</name>)</head>
                    <p>
                        <title>House of Commons, Monday, January 24th.</title>—At Question
time House crowded in response to urgent Whip issued in
anticipation of division on Third Reading of Military Service Bill.
Members ready to vote; disinclined to remain to hear speeches,
delivered on Second Reading and Committee stages, reiterated by
small minority on Report. Thus it came to pass that when on stroke
of half-past nine this milestone passed, Benches were almost
empty.</p>
                    <p>Filled up when Third Reading moved, and debate lamely set on
foot again. <name rend="sc">Walter Long</name>, who has greatly
helped <name rend="sc">Bonar Law</name> in his successful
management of Bill, set good example by moving Third Reading
without additional word of comment or argument. Example thrown
away. More last words spoken under embarrassing accompaniment of
private conversation and other signs of impatience.</p>
                    <p>Shortly after eleven o'clock division taken, revealing existence
of solid minority of three dozen. Oddly enough, whilst rattling
majority on Second Reading was hailed with enthusiastic cheering,
that on Third Reading was heard in silence, Members hurrying off in
search of taxis.</p>
                    <p>
                        <title>Business done.</title>—By majority of 347, in House of 419
Members, Military Service Bill read a third time and passed on to
Lords.</p>
                    <p>
                        <title>House of Lords, Tuesday.</title>—Military Service Bill
turned up for Second Reading. Full attendance and a gathering of
Commoners in their pen above Bar seemed to indicate important
debate. Turned out to be only less dull than that which slumbered
round closing stage in the Commons. <name rend="sc">Lansdowne</name> pluckily endeavoured to give note of
novelty to topic by saying "not what the Bill was but what it was
not." Even this ingenious device did not succeed in investing
proceedings with anything approaching animation.</p>
                    <p>The <name rend="sc">Weary Weardale</name>, who through long
public life has tried in succession both branches of the
Legislature and found them equally withered, was doubtful whether
the measure would appreciably affect its avowed purpose of
increasing number of men with the Colours. With instinct of good
Liberal—in his time <name rend="sc">Philip
Stanhope</name> was known in the Commons as an almost dangerous
Radical—he turned and rent "certain leaders who have
surrendered a precious principle and in so doing are undermining
the authority and existence of the whole Liberal Party." Still,
though prospect was gloomy, he would not despair.</p>
                    <p>"The Liberal Party," he said, "will rise again" (<name rend="sc">Halsbury</name> shook his head doubtfully) "and will shed
the leaders who have deserted it."</p>
                    <p>Having thus delivered his soul <name rend="sc">Weary
One</name> did not challenge a division.</p>
                    <p>
                        <title>Business done.</title>—Military Service Bill read second
time without division.</p>
                    <p>
                        <title>House of Commons, Wednesday.</title>—Once more, the last
time in history of session of unparalleled length and importance,
House crowded. Peers' Gallery full. From Diplomatic Gallery the
United States, Norway, Sweden, Denmark and Holland, represented by
their Ministers, looked on, eagerly listening.</p>
                    <p>Resolution, moved by <name rend="sc">Shirley Benn</name>,
urged Government to enforce against enemy a blockade as effective
as possible. In one of his comprehensive, quietly delivered and
powerful speeches <name rend="sc">Edward Grey</name> showed
that situation is not so easily managed as amateur diplomatists
below the Gangway believe, or as fractious newspapers, bent on
damaging the Government even if the Empire falls, assert. Explained
in detail steps taken by Foreign Office to deal with it. House
listened critically but approvingly. Took note of fact that
<name rend="sc">First Lord of Admiralty</name> emphatically
cheered denial of one of the malicious rumours current—that
in the task of preventing supplies reaching the enemy the Foreign
Office spoils the work of the Navy.</p>
                    <p>Sharp, almost angry burst of cheering greeted passage towards
close of speech in which <name rend="sc">Foreign
Secretary</name> declared that maximum effort in this country,
whether military, naval or financial, is at the disposal of our
Allies in carrying on the War against Prussian militarism.</p>
                    <p>"With them," he confidently but still quietly said, "we will see
it through to the end."</p>
                    <p>Speeches following expressed general satisfaction with this
statement, supplemented by one addressed to neutrals. Courteously
assured them of desire not to make things unnecessarily irksome.
But pointed out that in the matter of preventing supplies reaching
the enemy by circuitous routes Great Britain has her own work to do
and means to do it thoroughly.</p>
                    <p>
                        <title>Business done.</title>—Resolution advocating effective
blockade talked out.</p>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Thursday.</name>—Parliament prorogued.
Reversing <name rend="sc">Charles Lamb's</name> conscientious
habit at the India Office, where, having arrived late, he made up
for it by going away early, Parliament, having toiled through
exceptionally long Session, treats itself to briefest possible
recess. Reassembles 15th February.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/90-300.png"/>
                        <head>REDUCED IMPORT OF PAPER: WHAT WE MAY COME TO.</head>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1106" type="div3">
                    <head>Diana Up to Date.</head>
                    <quote>"<name rend="sc">Manageress</name> (35), thorough
business woman, accustomed to control stag."</quote>—<title>Women's
Employment.</title>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>From an account of the reception of British soldiers in
Rome:—</p>
                    <quote>"As the hour for departure approached the band played
alternately the 'Marcia Reale' and 'Rule, Britannia,' while our men
sang 'Tipperary.'"</quote>—<title>The Times.</title>
                    <p>We fear the proceedings were not so harmonious as we had been
led to suppose.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>"<name rend="sc">Gentleman's Shooting Estate</name>
for Sale, 240 acres, or would Let on Lease; near London
Bridge."</quote>—<title>Advt. in "The Standard."</title>
                    <p>Shooting the arches is splendid sport.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>"2.45 a.m. —When
Grossmith lit a cigarette someone said, 'This is all right. We
bring a civilian here, and he lights up within hailing distance of
the Germans.'</p>
                        <p>         2.46  p.m. Grossmith
put out his cigarette."</p>
                    </quote>
                    <bibl>
                        <title>Daily Mirror.</title>
                    </bibl>
                    <p>Now that tobacco is going up again it would be a boon to smokers
if Mr. <name rend="sc">Grossmith</name> would tell us how he
keeps a cigarette going for twelve hours.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>"The fire which broke out at Bergen on Saturday was
mastered by three o'clock on Sunday morning. About 400 buildings,
mostly very valuable property, were destroyed. The value of the
houses which were burnt down is about £1,111,111, and the
total damage is estimated at £5,555,555."</p>
                    </quote>—<bibl>
                        <title>Edinburgh
Evening News.</title>
                    </bibl>
                    <p>The exactitude of these figures would convince even an insurance
company.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page91" n="pg 91"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/91-600.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1192" type="div2">
                <head>THE PLEA OF THE HOMELESS.</head>
                <p>Most of the petitions from natives which find their way into
print for the removal of the white man's gravity hail from our
Indian Empire. But the Babu's monopoly can be assailed. The
following recent and genuine example is from West
Africa:—</p>
                <p>
                    <title>"To Sir —— ——, Commander of
the New Work Shops.</title>
                </p>
                <p>"Sir, read to the end!</p>
                <p>"<name rend="sc">Dear British Commander of
Influence</name>,—I am with cordial gratitude to put this pen
before you, saying since I came down from my native land I had been
trie for a house, even by rentable, but none for me in that
village, where I lieve still. But a certain friend of mine do
advice me to stay with him, during the last December up to now. And
yet that young man's wife has come from his native land, with these
there is no room before me at all. Therefore I wish with my lowly
voice to beg your honour to find me even a half house of your
kitchen at any place where you like, or either the same place where
I am. By your own desire. Please Sir if not! try and get me a
boards such as a glass packing cases and a few planks for poles.
But Sir I know myself very well, that it will be very difficulty
before you, simple because you have none of carpenters. Therefore
do try by your own authority to supply me those boards and planks,
and I shall find myself a joiner as a day contract to build it for
me! because my elder brother also shall help. Therefore dear Lord I
hope you shall give ear for my lowly speak and then have mercy on
your meekly servant with good reply. I have the most honour to be
Sir</p>
                <signed>"Your humble Clerk."</signed>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e1220" type="div3">
                    <head>For "Ineligibles" only.</head>
                    <quote>"<name rend="sc">Wanted</name>, Bricklayers for
pointing 12 houses at Belvedere; peacework."</quote>—<title>Provincial
Paper.</title>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1235" type="div3">
                    <head>Commercial Modesty.</head>
                    <p rend="sc">"M. JACOB &amp; CO.,<lb/>
                        <name rend="sc">Confectioner and Glacier.</name>
                        <lb/>
Pastry of sorts."</p>
                    <p>
                        <title>Madras Mail.</title>
                    </p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1257" type="div3">
                    <head>The Zeal of the Convert.</head>
                    <p>Sir <name rend="sc">Thomas Whittaker, M.P.</name>, as
reported by <title>The Yorkshire Evening Post</title>:</p>
                    <p>
                        <quote>"Objection to compulsion on principle was all nonsense.
Compulsion was the only safe-guard we had against anarchy,
barbarism, law, order, justice, and freedom."</quote>
                    </p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1276" type="div3">
                    <head>Cromwelliana.</head>
                    <p>
                        <quote>"On Friday last a centenarian passed away at Whithall,
Galway, in the person of Mrs. Catherine Hynes, who had attained the
remarkable age of 102. The old lady had a remarkably retentive
memory, recalling with ease incidents which occurred three
generations ago. Her recollection of Cromwell's campaign was
particularly clear."</quote>—<title>Connacht Tribune.</title>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <quote>"The other alien peer is the twelfth Viscount Taaffe,
of the Irish peerage, an Austrian subject, as his predecessors have
been since their estates were confiscated by Cromwell after the
Battle of the Boyne."</quote>—<title>Sunday Times.</title>
                    </p>
                    <p>The late Mrs. <name rend="sc">Hynes</name> was perhaps the
authority for this statement.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p rend="sc">"ALLIES' WARSHIPS<lb/>
                        <name rend="sc">Keep Turks on Tender Hooks at
Gallipoli</name>."</p>
                    <p>
                        <title>Express and Echo (Exeter).</title>
                    </p>
                    <p>This is rather hard on the enemy, who thought the Allies had
taken their hook long ago.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page92" n="pg 92"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1328" type="div2">
                <head>AT THE FRONT.</head>
                <p>Home again! The base softened its heart on the very morning on
which I had practically decided to attend a parade next day if I
were called in time, and released me with an enormous command to
conduct to the War. I told the senior N.C.O. at the station of
entrainment that I would regard him as personally responsible if he
dropped any of the men on the line or under the engine on the way
up, and was just off to look for food when the R.T.O. told me the
train was due out in two minutes. After making quite sure that he
wasn't a Major I reminded him that for that matter the War had been
due to be over last September; also that I had used some of his
trains before and that he couldn't teach me two-pennyworth about
them I hadn't known from childhood. This I said courteously but
firmly, and thereafter felt better and bought eight boiled eggs, a
ham sandwich made so hastily that the ham came to be altogether
omitted, three oranges, and a large mineral-water. The train was in
the station for three-quarters-of-an-hour after I returned. I
passed the time pleasantly by walking up and down in front of the
R.T.O.</p>
                <p>And now I am here. Glory apart, I could think for a long time
without hitting on anywhere beastlier to be except perhaps just the
other side of a breastwork thirty yards off where the Bosch has
been dropping heavy crumps in threes with monotonous regularity
since an indecent hour this morning. I have been partly asleep,
partly waiting for one to drop thirty yards short. There is no one
to talk to except a chaffinch, who thinks of nothing but his
appearance. If I thought of mine I should go mad. I am wet under
and through and over everything—wet, not with rain, but with
mud. You have heard that there is mud in Flanders?</p>
                <p>But the worst part really is the number of hours in a day; we
have as many as ten nowadays in which movement is simply not done.
Where dawn finds you, dusk releases you. That is here; I believe we
have some real trenches somewhere behind. But we of the ten hours'
stretch run out of employment early in the morning and remain there
the rest of the day. Of course you can eat—if your rations
really came up last night—but not, I think, continuously for
ten hours. A very inferior officer—not I—has invented a
recipe for the ten-hour day which may appeal to some similarly
loose-ended officer. You take an air-pillow and lie with your
gum-booted feet on it till the position becomes intolerable; then
you remove the pillow, sit up and pick the mud off it. When it's
clean you do the same thing again. One tour of this duty will take
an hour if you are conscientious. Its inventor claims that it makes
the sun fairly bustle down the sky.</p>
                <p>There are advantages in solitary feeding. Haven't you ever
wanted, when confronted with a lunch tongue, to hack out all the
nice tonguey bits for yourself and leave the bully beef parts to be
used for soup or some other domestic economy? Well, I hack out the
tonguey bits every day. True, I usually have to eat the bully beef
parts next meal, but—<title>à la guerre comme à la
guerre</title>—I always might have been casualtied between meals,
and then think what a fool I'd feel over my failure to make the
most of the first.</p>
                <p>I've come to the conclusion that this Army isn't really fair.
Some regiments I've met always seem to be doing three weeks' rest
down Boulogne or Nice or somewhere like that. Thrice and four times
have I come and come back to this battalion, and every blessed time
they've been either in trenches when I arrived, or situated
directly behind the trenches and going up, it might be, to make
some more.</p>
                <p>Sometimes we go up to dig, sometimes to carry, sometimes both.
On the night of my re-arrival I went up with the digging party, and
have the honour to report the following conversation between a
certain one of our diggers and a friend who loomed up carrying
about four engineer dug-outs, two coils of barbed wire, and a maul.
You could just make out the man under it all as he stumbled
erratically along a mud-ridden track.</p>
                <p>"'Ello, Steve," says the digger, "wot's yer game to-night?"</p>
                <p>Steve stopped for a second to look at his interrogator and then
observed genially as he moved on,</p>
                <p>"Oh, just killin' time, you know."</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/92-300.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1373" type="div2">
                <head>TERCENTENARY TWITTERINGS.</head>
                <p>The letters that follow are only a small selection from those
that have been inadvertently forwarded to us in response to the
appeal of <title>The Westminster Gazette</title> for suggestions as to the
most appropriate method of celebrating <name rend="sc">Shakspeare's</name> tercentenary:—</p>
                <div xml:id="d1e1386" type="div3">
                    <head>
                        <name rend="sc">A Hint to Greater Britain.</name>
                    </head>
                    <p>The name of the new capital of the Australian Commonwealth is
not irrevocably fixed, and it seems to me that a splendid
opportunity is now offered our brethren overseas to commemorate the
genius of the foremost British man of letters by linking his name
with the new Antipodean metropolis. I should not venture to dictate
the exact form which it should take, but "Willshake" seems to me to
meet the requirements of the case very happily, though the claims
of "Avonbard" also deserve consideration.</p>
                    <signed>
                        <name rend="sc">Phillibert Harker.</name>
                    </signed>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1402" type="div3">
                    <head>
                        <name rend="sc">Bird and Bard.</name>
                    </head>
                    <p>As <name rend="sc">Shakspeare</name> overtopped all other
men, so should his memorial tower over all other monuments. I
cannot help thinking that the re-erection of the Wembley Tower in
the form of a gigantic swan soaring into the empyrean to the height
of say two or three thousand feet would prove a satisfactory
solution of the problem. Whether it should be black or white is a
question which might be referred to a small committee of experts,
such as Sir <name rend="sc">Sidney Lee</name>, Sir <name rend="sc">Herbert Tree</name> and Miss <name rend="sc">Marie
Corelli</name>.</p>
                    <signed>
                        <name rend="sc">Mile End.</name>
                    </signed>
                    <p>P.S.—A good alternative method of celebrating the
tercentenary of <name rend="sc">Shakspeare</name> would be the
execution on Shakspeare Cliff, at Dover, of a colossal portrait of
the immortal dramatist, somewhat on the scale of the famous "White
Horse." Once the outline had been marked out by a competent artist
the rest of the work could be easily <pb xml:id="page93" n="pg 93"/> completed <hi rend="it">gratis</hi> by
the Volunteers, and the total cost would be negligible.</p>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1441" type="div3">
                    <head>
                        <name rend="sc">A Frugal Suggestion.</name>
                    </head>
                    <p>I venture to think that no better way of paying homage to the
genius of <name rend="sc">Shakspeare</name> could be devised
than for all the newspapers throughout the country to devote their
best pages on the day to suitable extracts from his works. This
arrangement has the extra inducement of being economical as well as
appropriate.</p>
                    <signed>
                        <name rend="sc">Reginald Jobson</name>,<lb/>
                        <title>Registrar in Bankruptcy</title>.</signed>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1465" type="div3">
                    <head>
                        <name rend="sc">A Great Scientist Speaks Out.</name>
                    </head>
                    <p>What we want is to convert <name rend="sc">Shakspeare</name>
into a genuine educational instrument, and that is impossible so
long as he is only available in his present archaic form. A new
edition of the Plays, purged of their classicism and romanticism
and expressed in language of scientific accuracy, is peremptorily
demanded in the interests of national efficiency.</p>
                    <signed>
                        <name rend="sc">X. Ray, F.R.S.</name>
                    </signed>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1484" type="div3">
                    <head>
                        <name rend="sc">A Fastidious Critic.</name>
                    </head>
                    <p>You ask me, "What are my own personal plans in connection with
the anniversary?" It is on record that a very distinguished divine
stayed in bed on the day following the announcement of the death of
Lord <name rend="sc">Beaconsfield</name>, so as to avoid the
horrid temptation of reading what was said about him in the
newspaper, which was the divine's pet aversion. I propose to follow
this excellent example on Shakspeare Day.</p>
                    <signed>T. H.</signed>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1500" type="div3">
                    <head>
                        <name rend="sc">America's greatest Poet sends
Greeting.</name>
                    </head>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>From across the stormy ocean,</l>
                            <l>Prompted by a deep emotion,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">I despatch my salutation on a card;</l>
                            <l>For although I cannot meet thee</l>
                            <l>In the flesh, I still can greet thee,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">
                                <name rend="sc">William Shakspeare</name>, as a
worthy brother bard.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>In these times of stress and passion,</l>
                            <l>When the sword is all the fashion,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Only minstrelsy can keep the world in tune;</l>
                            <l>For the poet is a healer,</l>
                            <l>And both <name rend="sc">Will</name> and <name rend="sc">Ella Wheeler</name>
                            </l>
                            <l rend="i2">Are a blessing and a comfort and a boon.</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1563" type="div3">
                    <head>
                        <name rend="sc">A Cemeterial Celebration.</name>
                    </head>
                    <p>No memorial to <name rend="sc">Shakspeare</name> can be
adequate which does not express in some concrete shape the
universality of his appeal. This end might be attained by erecting
a cenotaph in his honour in every churchyard and cemetery in
England. I admit that such a scheme would cost money and so might
be contrary to the spirit of economy which ought to animate
everyone at this hour. But a beginning might be made even now, and
I have composed a Funeral March in <title>Hamlet</title> the proceeds of
which I would gladly devote to the purpose,</p>
                    <signed>
                        <name rend="sc">Algernon
Brookwood.</name>
                    </signed>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/93-600.png"/>
                        <head>HOW TO TALK TO THE WOUNDED.</head>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1598" type="div3">
                    <head>A Short Way with Lecturers.</head>
                    <p>
                        <quote>"To-morrow the Central Methodist Mission will celebrate
the anniversary of its rescue and social work. The Sisters of the
people are to take part in the morning service, and in the
afternoon Mr. —— is killed for an address on 'The
Social Outlook.'"</quote>—<title>Sydney Daily Telegraph.</title>
                    </p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>The <name rend="sc">Kaiser</name> to <name rend="sc">Ferdinand</name>:—</p>
                    <p>
                        <quote>"I have begged your Majesty to accept the dignity of
Prussian Field-Marshal, and I am with my Amy happy that you, by
accepting it also in this sense, have become one of
us."</quote>—<title>Irish Paper.</title>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">German Empress</name>, to her husband: "And
who is Amy?"</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page94" n="pg 94"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1642" type="div2">
                <head>AT THE PLAY.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e1646" type="div3">
                    <head>
                        <name rend="sc">"Please Help Emily."</name>
                    </head>
                    <p>The date at which <title>Emily</title> needed so much assistance was
clearly <title>ante bellum</title>, for there is no mention of hostilities,
no gun-fire is heard from the direction of Westende, and Belgium is
still bathing. But it must have been only just before the War, for
the emancipation which the female sex here enjoys is marked by an
extreme modernity. A decade or two ago we might have been shocked
at the spectacle of a young lady turning up at a bachelor's flat at
9 <name rend="sc">A.M.</name> on a Sunday in a ball-frock,
after a night out at a dancing-club. Lately we have learnt to bear
such escapades without flinching. But it was not so with
<title>Emily's</title> guardian, <title>Sir Samuel Lethbridge</title>, very
Victorian in his stuffy prejudice in favour of the decencies; and
it was necessary to put him off with a tale of her sudden departure
to Brussels to render first aid to an aunt stricken with mumps. In
order to give colour to this fabrication <title>Emily</title> urges <title>Dick
Trotter</title>, the bachelor of the flat (as soon as he returns from
his own night out), to conduct her to the alleged invalid. He
consents, but not without protest, for he is a <title>roué</title>
of the old school and cannot approve of these platonic adventures;
besides, he is about to <title>se ranger</title> by marriage with somebody
else and (a matter of detail, but most inconvenient) is under
contract to take her to Brighton for the day.</p>
                    <p>A fairly preposterous start, you will say; yet the delightful
naturalness which Miss <name rend="sc">Gladys Cooper</name> and
Mr. <name rend="sc">Charles Hawtrey</name> bring to the
situation gives it almost an air of possibility. But, once we are
at Ostend, and have been introduced to <title>Trotter's</title> incredibly
inappropriate fiancée (she is a niece of the same aunt and
has followed under protection of a tame escort), we are prepared to
launch freely and fearlessly into the rough and tumble of
farce.</p>
                    <p>It is in vain that Miss <name rend="sc">Gladys
Cooper</name>, over her <title>petit déjeuner</title>, preserves a
natural demeanour, even to the point of talking with her mouth
full; the light humour of the First Act declines to the verge of
buffoonery. The devastating confusions which ensue in the matter of
identity and relationship (in our author's Ostend you assume, till
corrected, that all couples are married); the intervention of the
local gendarmerie, headed by a British detective; the arrest of
half the party (including the aunt, arrived in perfect health and
ignorance <title>en route</title> for England) on a nameless charge in
connection with <title>Emily's</title> suspected abduction—all this
is in the best Criterion manner.</p>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/94-200.png"/>
                        <head>EMILY GIVES DICK THE GLADYS EYE.</head>
                    </figure>
                    <p>In the Third Act, though we never recover the rapture of the
First, the humour touches a higher level; but what it gains in
<hi rend="it">finesse</hi> it loses in spontaneity. Here we meet <title>Emily's</title>
father, returned from lecturing in the States on social ethics. The
scandal of his daughter's conduct leaves him indifferent, for a
long and varied experience of the morals of many lands, in the
course of which he has married as many as eighteen wives, having
made a point of adopting for the time being the
system—polygamous or other—of the country in which he
happens to find himself, has taught him that nothing is right or
wrong except as local opinion makes it so. We are allowed to gather
that heredity may have had some influence in the moulding of
<title>Emily's</title> character; and if we may hope for its continuance
into the next generation there seems every prospect that the
children she may bear to <title>Trotter</title> (now released from
<title>Julia</title> and free to marry the right woman) will not have their
development hampered by excess of prudery.</p>
                    <p>Mr. <name rend="sc">Charles Hawtrey</name> as <title>Trotter</title>
played with his old easy skill and seemed to take a more than usual
interest in the play. He was supported (as they say) by a
particularly brilliant cast, including Miss <name rend="sc">Lottie
Venne</name> as the aunt, Mr. <name rend="sc">Eric Lewis</name> as <title>Emily's</title> father, Mr.
<name rend="sc">Frederick Kerr</name> as <title>Sir Samuel</title>,
Miss <name rend="sc">Helen Haye</name> in the thankless part of
<title>Julia</title>, and Mr. <name rend="sc">Nigel Playfair</name> as
a self-effacing phantom of a lover. All were in great form; but,
next to Miss <name rend="sc">Gladys Cooper</name>, whose
natural charm and ingenuous <title>espièglerie</title> were a
perpetual delight, I offer my profoundest compliments to the short
but extraordinarily clever performance of Mr. <name rend="sc">H. R. Hignett</name> as <title>Trotter's</title> man
<title>Francis</title>. This is the day of stage valets, but he was an
exceptional treasure. To a quiet taste for philosophy he added an
infinite tact; and by the lies which he poured into the telephone
to cover his master's breach of engagement to <title>Julia</title> he moved
<title>Emily</title>, herself a gifted artist, to admiration.</p>
                    <p>The author, Mr. <name rend="sc">H. M. Harwood</name>, must
be congratulated on a farce that at its best was really excellent
fun. And he may take it for flattery, if he likes, when I say that
a good deal of his dialogue might be adapted into the French
without offending our gallant Allies on the ground of a too insular
squeamishness.</p>
                    <signed>O. S.</signed>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1805" type="div3">
                    <head>THE INDURATION.</head>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>Think not, dear love, because my cheek</l>
                            <l rend="i2">With grief grows neither grey nor hollow,</l>
                            <l>Because no pharmacist I seek</l>
                            <l rend="i2">In quest of arsenic to swallow,</l>
                            <l>Because I do not wince and weep</l>
                            <l rend="i2">By day and night for cardiac pains,</l>
                            <l>That my fond passion falls on sleep,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Or, secondly, my worship wanes.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>For these are strenuous days of strife</l>
                            <l rend="i2">That steel the soul of every Briton;</l>
                            <l>Sterner and stronger grows our life</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Till simple bards become hard-bitten;</l>
                            <l>So when, each Thursday, I propose</l>
                            <l rend="i2">(As usual) to wed my fair,</l>
                            <l>I frankly find her changeless "No's"</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Not half so poignant as they were.</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>From an almanack of appropriate quotations:—</p>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l rend="i8">"<name rend="sc">January 27.</name>
                            </l>
                            <l rend="i10">Thursday.</l>
                            <l rend="i4">
                                <title>German Emperor born</title>, 1859.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>O welcome, pure-ey'd Faith, white-handed Hope,</l>
                            <l>Thou hovering angel, girt with golden
wings.—<title>Milton.</title>"</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>
                        <quote>"If men well up in years would cultivate a habit of
breathing properly and always holding themselves erect when walking
and sitting, we would find fewer elderly people bent double when we
do."</quote>—<title>Daily Express.</title>
                    </p>
                    <p>Our gay contemporary has been caught bending on this
occasion.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>
                        <quote>"He asked the Government not to muzzle the ox that laid
golden eggs."</quote>—<title>The Daily Argosy
(Demerara).</title>
                    </p>
                    <p>It wasn't really an ox; it was a bull.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>From a country retail chemist's appeal to the Local Tribunal for
his son's exemption from Military Service:</p>
                    <p>"I cannot dispense with him"—or, presumably, without
him.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page95" n="pg 95"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/95-600.png"/>
                        <head>ONCE BIT, TWICE SHY.</head>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1958" type="div2">
                <head>OUR BOOKING-OFFICE.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e1962" type="div3">
                    <head>(<title>By Mr. Punch's Staff of Learned Clerks.</title>)</head>
                    <p>When <title>Hargrave Ladd</title>, who was a solicitor in a very fair
way of business, with an agreeable but unemotional wife, happened
to be getting into an omnibus at the moment when <title>Stella
Rayne</title> fell off the top of it, he unconsciously put himself in
the way of a lot of bother. Naturally, as a gentleman and the male
protagonist of a novel—<title>Let Be</title> (<name rend="sc">Methuen</name>)—he could do no less than pick the
girl out of the mud and see her home in a cab. Whether, quite
strictly speaking, he need have called next day to see how she was
getting over the accident is another matter. Certainly his
interfering aunt, <title>Mrs. Dering</title>, was of the opinion that
<title>Hargrave</title>, as a married man, was displaying an excess of
courtesy towards the pretty tumbler. As for Miss <name rend="sc">Sybil Campbell Lethbridge</name>, who has written the tale,
she gives no indication of her views one way or the other. Indeed
this attitude of humorous tolerance for humanity is Miss
<name rend="sc">Lethbridge's</name> most striking
characteristic. It is at once a source of strength and weakness to
the book, making, on the one hand, for the reality of the
characters, and, on the other, for a certain non-conductiveness of
atmosphere that robs their emotions of warmth. Anyhow, the
inevitable happens, and <title>Hargrave</title> falls in love with
<title>Stella</title>, who in turn reciprocates his passion up to almost
the last page in the book, when, having come to the edge of the
precipice and made every preparation for her leap into the gulf of
elopement, she does a mental quick-change and walks away as the
contented betrothed of Another. So <title>Hargrave</title>, making the best
of a good job, rejoins <title>Mrs. H.</title>; and one may suppose that, if
any more distressed damsels fall off omnibuses in his presence, he
will prudently "let be." You may think with me that this abrupt
finish lessens the effect of an otherwise well-written and
entertaining story.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>Miss <name rend="sc">Muriel Hine</name> in <title>The
Individual</title> (<name rend="sc">Lane</name>), essaying a
problem novel, does not disdain the old-fashioned way of the woven
plot and the dramatic incident. Her hero, <title>Orde Taverner</title>,
surgeon by trade and eugenist by profession, falls in love with
<title>Elizma</title>, a Cornish beauty and rare fiddler. His inquiries as
to her eugenical fitness having been answered satisfactorily but
inaccurately, he marries, to find that <title>Elizma's</title> mother
really died insane. His principles conquer his desire for children,
and his decision is communicated to the fiery <title>Elizma</title>, who,
fierce maternalist that she is and coming of a wild stock that
never stuck at anything, undertakes a desperate flirtation by way
of solving the difficulty in her own heroic way—at least you
will certainly make this kind of a guess, but on investigation you
may find that you've been wrong! Happily in the end a deathbed
confession proves the second version of her birth as inaccurate as
the first. She really comes of quite untainted stock, so the
eugenist is satisfied and husband and wife reconciled. That is to
say the author runs away from her problem, which was perhaps, all
things considered, the wisest thing to do. She has some eye for
character and has made a good thing of her <title>Elizma</title>, but has
let herself scatter her energies over a team too large to be driven
with a sure hand. And why, oh why did she drag in the War? Or call
her butler <title>Puffles</title>? But she keeps the interest of her story
going, and you mustn't skip or you may be set off on a hopelessly
wrong tack.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page96" n="pg 96"/>
                    <p>So great is my admiration for the humorous gifts of Mr.
<name rend="sc">William Caine</name> and so strong my gratitude
to him for such books as <title>Boom</title> and <title>Old Enough to Know
Better</title>, that I have decided to erase from my memory with all
possible speed his latest effort, <title>Bildad the Quill-Driver</title>
(<name rend="sc">Lane</name>.) A man with so many bull's-eyes
to his credit may be forgiven an occasional miss; and, to be
candid, <title>Bildad the Quill-Driver</title> seems to me to come nowhere
near the target. Most of Mr. <name rend="sc">Caine's</name>
work would be the better for a certain amount of condensation, but
this is the only occasion on which he has really lost control of
his pen. He has had the unfortunate idea of writing a comic
<title>Arabian Nights</title> in close imitation of the style of the
original translation, even to the insertion of short poems at every
possible opportunity. Now, this is one of those ideas which at
first blush would seem to contain all the elements of delightful
humour; but it has the deadly flaw that it involves a monotony
which becomes after a few pages more than irritating. For a while
the novelty is entertaining, and then the reader becomes crushed by
the realisation that he has got to rely for his amusement on the
same sort of joke repeated over and over again for more than three
hundred pages. And, once that happens, the doom of the book is
sealed, for the adventures of <title>Bildad</title> are not in themselves
diverting—his love-affair with the giantess is as unfunny a
thing as ever I yawned over—and if you cease to chuckle at
the burlesque pomposity of the style there is nothing left. There
are some things which do not lend themselves to sustained parody,
and the manner of the <title>Arabian Nights</title> is one of them. But, as
I say, I am not going to allow this book to shake my opinion that
Mr. <name rend="sc">Caine</name> is one of our most engaging
humorists.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/96-300.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>I recommend, absolutely without reserve, a war book entitled
<title>Day by Day with the Russian Army</title> (<name rend="sc">Constable</name>). It is written by Professor <name rend="sc">Bernard Pares</name>, the Official British Observer with
the Russian Armies in the Field, and is the real thing. Although
incidentally it is to be praised as a modest and lucid piece of
writing, well in keeping with the character of an author whose
habit of viewing an action from the most dangerous, because the
most interesting, point can be discovered only by reading between
the lines, primarily it is to be prescribed as a sovereign tonic
against German-made depression. The writer, after being present at
the conquest of Galicia and the triumphant advance to the top of
the Carpathians, after witnessing much of the historical Russian
retreat under pressure of overwhelming artillery superiority, and
after conversing freely with his friends of all ranks on different
sectors of the Front whilst offering greetings in the name of their
English comrades in arms, announces finally, in a wholly
satisfactory fashion, his unalterable conviction as to the
unqualified supremacy of our Allies when on anything like equal
terms with their opponents as regards munitions of war. And that is
a matter which, though never in doubt, it is pleasant to hear again
in tones of authority at a time when we believe the Russian lack of
supplies is at last being made good. The evidence is the more
complete because not only do we learn of the interrogation of many
prisoners, but because a long extract from the diary of one of
them, an Austrian officer, is included, to point the difference in
spirit between the two armies. The demoralisation of the Austrian
forces, even when advancing, is so strikingly presented that one
cannot doubt their dependence on German domination and German
batteries to hold them together at all. Although Professor
<name rend="sc">Pares</name> attaches several excellent maps,
he is not really much concerned with questions of strategy, but has
devoted himself to just two points—<hi rend="it">moral</hi> and
munitions.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>I am afraid that Mrs. <name rend="sc">Hodgson Burnett</name>
is in a little danger of overdoing it. She knows (who better?) the
briskness of the popular demand for long-lost heirs; and she may
well have argued that the longer he has been lost, the more squalid
his present environment, and the more brilliant his heritage, the
more assured would be the heir's welcome. Perhaps indeed this may
be so in America; but for this side, as I say, I have my doubts. I
daresay your own intuition will tell you that the hero of <title>The
Lost Prince</title> (<name rend="sc">Hodder and Stoughton</name>)
is a prince who has been lost. In fact so effectually had the
branch of the regal house to which <title>Prince Ivor</title> belonged been
mislaid that the story opens upon him dwelling in a London slum
with no companions but a mysterious father and a crippled
playfellow (called <title>The Rat</title>). All sorts of mysterious things
are constantly happening just out of sight; and presently the
dynastic intrigues of Mrs. <name rend="sc">Burnett</name>
launch the two boys upon a secret journey through Europe, to convey
to a number of pleasantly melodramatic conspirators the message
that "The Lamp is Lighted!" As their object is expressly stated to
be protection for a small principality, the fact that the
interviews include one with Emperor of <name rend="sc">Austria</name> has in these days a quaintly anachronistic
effect, and at least serves to emphasise the neutral origin of the
story. However, they are of course successful; and in the last
chapter <title>Prince Ivor</title> manages to be enormously astonished at
finding that the mysterious monarch of Samavia, for whom he has
been working, is none other than his own father—an obvious
fact that, with truly royal tactfulness, he had contrived to ignore
throughout the story. My advice to the author is to write up her
villains (at present they haven't a chance) and make the whole
thing into a film play. The wanderings of the two boys offer a fine
opportunity for scenic variety; while the sentiment is of precisely
the nature to be stimulated by a pianoforte accompaniment. As a
three-reel exclusive, in short, I can fancy <title>The Lost Prince</title>
entering triumphantly into his appropriate kingdom.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>
                        <quote>"<name rend="sc">Unfurnished Room</name> to Let in
Clyde Road; quiet house; convenience for washing once a week if
necessary; rent 3s."</quote>—<bibl>
                            <title>Hastings and St. Leonards
Observer.</title>
                        </bibl>
                    </p>
                    <p>It sounds dirt-cheap.</p>

               <!--Gutenberg License information removed.-->
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>