<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Punch, or the London Charivari, Vol. 150, March 1, 1916</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <idno type="gutenberg">22687</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>This text is freely available for re-use under US and UK law, consult
                            your local legal restrictions if elsewhere.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This text is a TEI version of a Project Gutenberg text originally located at
                            <ptr target="http://www.gutenberg.org/dirs//////"/>. As per their license agreement we have removed
                        all references to the project's trademark, however have included this
                        pointer to the original in case you want the plain text, or their XHTML
                        version. </p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2008-06-27T16:13:12.44+01:00"/>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:id="d1e44" type="div2">
                <head>CHARIVARIA.</head>
                <p>The Volunteers have at last been
recognised. There has been nothing
like it since the great recognition-scene
in <title>Electra</title>.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The case has been reported of a
Stepney child which has developed a
disease of the brain, as the result of an
air raid. Similar cases are said to
have been observed in the neighbourhood
of Fleet Street.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>It now transpires that the
music of St. Paul's Cathedral
emanates from an organ of
German construction. There
seems to be some doubt as to
whether an explanation is due
from <title>The Westminster Gazette</title>
or <title>The Times</title>.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The mysterious shortage of
butter in Germany, which
has resulted in measures being
drafted limiting the consumption
to 4 ozs. per week per
adult, is now explained. Count
<name rend="sc">von Bernstorff</name> has used up
all the available supplies on
Congress.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The General Omnibus Company
has made the announcement
that it will not employ
any women drivers for its
omnibuses. The company's
officers fear that if women were
so employed there would be an
absence of that racy repartee
which alone prevents traffic
from reaching a condition of
indescribable congestion.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The demand for second-hand
pianos now for the first time
in the history of the trade far
exceeds the supply. It is not
only in Germany that War and
frightfulness go hand-in-hand.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The capture of Mush by the Russian
army of the Caucasus is an event the
importance of which has not been fully
recognized. It is undoubtedly the place
from which the Turkish official reports
of victory have been issued.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The Marconi Company have announced
that "deferred plain language
telegrams" will again be received.
More truckling to the Tory Press!</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A traveller returning from East
Africa reports that, notwithstanding
the military operations that are taking
place in various parts of the country,
rhinoceroses appear to be increasing in
numbers. It is explained that the
falling-off in the European demand for
potted reed birds is responsible for the
phenomenon.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>It is announced that the Cabinet are
to take a portion of their salaries in
Exchequer Bonds. Not to be outdone
the members of the Reichstag are said
to have agreed to soil their fingers
with dirty British gold rather than
hinder the German Government's
operations for correcting the depreciation
of the mark.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The suggestion has been put forward
that, as a timely War economy, well-to-do
people should give up their hot-houses.
There seems to be a division
of opinion, however, as to whether the
hot-house plants should be given their
liberty, or (as economy would seem to
dictate) be killed for the table.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Australia has suspended the trade-marks
of 450 German articles. It would
be interesting to know if the most historic
German trade-mark, "<name rend="sc">Made in
the United States</name>," is among these.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"Mr. Julian Kimball (of Covent
Garden and the London Opera House),"
says the Musical critic of <title>The Daily
Mail</title>, "is a singer you can watch as
well as listen to." The desirability of
concealing the faces of some of our
principal singers in the past is undoubtedly
one of the reasons why
England has lagged behind in the
musical art.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A well-known candidate for the East
Herts Division is said to be
urgently in need of motor cars.
His opponents however point
out that the need to economise
in petrol was never more
urgent than at present.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Speaking on the question of
the shortage of freights Mr.
<name rend="sc">Runciman</name> stated, a few days
ago, that he did not know that
ostrich feathers took up much
room. Has he never been to a
matinée?</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>In the same connection a
member of the Ladies' Kennel
Club writes: "I let them take
my husband for their horrid
old War without grumbling,
but when they tell me that
poor little Nanki-Poo can't
have his ostrich-feather pillow
to lie on I think it is too
much!"</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/145.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"The profits of the Bradford
Dyers' Association exceed the most
sanguinary expectations."</p>
                    <p rend="i10">
                        <title>Morning Paper</title>.
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>The influence of the War,
again.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>S.P.C.A., please note.</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"Dogs are generally from 9 to
18 inches long and the teeth from
3 to 8 inches long; the service
pattern are from 12 to 15 inches
long with 6 inch teeth. For straight
dogs the ends of the teeth should be
slightly further apart than at their
root.  Dogs when heated red-hot can be
twisted till their teeth make any required
angle with each other, generally a right
angle; they are then known as skew dogs."</p>
                    <p rend="i10">
                        <title>Military Engineering</title>.
</p>
                </quote>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"The offensive eggs were first placed in a
mangle, and the slow, crude, and obnoxious
process was gone through of crushing them.
The pugnacity of the smell arising from this
progress became appalling."—<title>Grocers' Journal</title>.
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>Fit to knock one down, in fact.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"Lady, 45, domesticated, Protestant, furniture,
wishes Correspondence with Respectable
Widower and Bachelor; view matrimony."—<title>Southport
Visitor</title>.
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>One of the two gentlemen will have to
be content with the furniture.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page146" n="pg 146"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e227" type="div2">
                <head>A CURE FOR DEPRESSION.</head>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Moments there are of transient gloom</l>
                        <l rend="i2">When life for me appears to lose</l>
                        <l>Its rosy aspect and assume</l>
                        <l rend="i2">The turnip's pessimistic hues;</l>
                        <l>As when o' mornings, gazing out</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Across my patch of fog-grey river,</l>
                        <l>I feel a twinge of poor man's gout</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Or else a touch of liver;</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Or when, forgetting <name rend="sc">Watts's</name> rhymes</l>
                        <l rend="i2">On puppy-dogs that bark and bite,</l>
                        <l>
                            <title>The Westminster</title> attacks <title>The Times</title>,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Starting a most unseemly fight;</l>
                        <l>Or when I find some Labour sheet</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Still left at large to boom rebellion,</l>
                        <l>Or hear the thin pacific bleat</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Of "my hon. friend" <name rend="sc">Trevelyan</name>;</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>When enemy craft career above,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Unchallenged (till they've had their fling);</l>
                        <l>Or <name rend="sc">Little Willie's</name> vernal shove</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Anticipates the dawn of Spring;</l>
                        <l>When Neutrals want an open door</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Kept wide for their commercial dealings,</l>
                        <l>And we must risk to lose the War</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Rather than hurt their feelings.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Such moments, making Hope look bleak,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">And Courage turn a little blue,</l>
                        <l>Even with hearts as tough as teak</l>
                        <l rend="i2">May well occur; but, when they do,</l>
                        <l>This thought will readjust your bile</l>
                        <l rend="i2">And prove the best of appetisers:—?</l>
                        <l>
                            <title>Would I exchange</title> (here's where you smile)</l>
                        <l rend="i2">
                            <title>Our chances with the <name rend="sc">Kaiser's</name>?</title>
                        </l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <p>O.S.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e375" type="div2">
                <head>UNWRITTEN LETTERS TO THE KAISER.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e379" type="div3">
                    <head>No. XXXV.</head>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e383" type="div3">
                    <head>(<title>From <name rend="sc">Enver Pasha</name>.</title>)</head>
                    <p>Sire,—Surely the course of human affairs is often
strange and perplexing. When we formed the Committee
of Union and Progress and deposed the wretched <name rend="sc">Abdul</name>
from the Sultanate no sane man can have thought that
you and I should ever be friends. <name rend="sc">Abdul</name> was your friend;
you and yours had lavished upon him and his creatures all
your arts for the purpose of obtaining influence and promoting
the interest—forgive me for saying it—not so much
of Turkey as of the German Empire. When therefore we
emerged, and <name rend="sc">Abdul</name> with his system retired, all your
beautiful schemes seemed to be shattered into pieces so
small that no human ingenuity could avail to pick them up
and fit them together again. Yet lo and behold, the
impossible has happened. <name rend="sc">Abdul</name> remains in darkness, I
and my colleagues are in power, and you and I are even
more closely knit together than is altogether desirable for
me and those whom (indirectly, perhaps, but not the less
effectively) I help to govern. I am entitled therefore to
have a heart-to-heart talk with my bosom-friend, and, anyhow,
whether I am entitled or not, that is what I propose
to have. You may tell me in your genial way that I am
only an upstart, but I answer that I occupy my position
not because my father and my grandfather were big men,
but because I myself, through my own plans and by my
own strength, did certain things which in my judgment
had to be done.</p>
                    <p>What I now feel, O my friend, is this: I am beginning
to doubt whether in all this tremendous confusion of fighting
I have made the right choice. It wasn't <hi rend="it">necessary</hi> for
us Turks to fight at all; it wasn't even desirable. We had
suffered a severe set-back in the first Balkan War, and in
the second we were only just able, owing to the consummate
folly of that silly knave, your friend, <name rend="sc">Tsar Ferdinand</name>,
to snatch a brand or two from the burning. What we
wanted was rest, and had it not been for you we might
have had it—yes, and our wounds might have been healed
and our finances restored, while others endured privation
and loss.</p>
                    <p>All that, as I say, we might have had; but from the
day when the <title>Goeben</title> arrived off Constantinople we were
doomed. That, indeed, was a master-stroke on your part,
but for us it has meant misery on an ever-increasing scale.
What were your promises? We were to have Egypt, but
you were to be there too, and you were to hold the Bagdad
railway and the regions through which it ran. We were to
help you in conquering India, but you were to keep it for
yourself when once it was conquered. We were to have a
free hand with the Armenians. Well, we have had it, and
the Armenians are fewer by half-a-million than they were.
Pleasant as it is to contemplate the destruction of those
restless and disloyal infidels, it cannot be said that we have
gained any advantage from it, for the Russians have taken
Erzerum and are sweeping through Armenia in a mighty
and irresistible torrent, while our Turkish armies are
scattered to the winds of heaven. Strong as you are and
prodigal of promises, here you have failed to make good
your pledges of help, and nowhere else do you seem able
to achieve anything, except the crushing of little nations.</p>
                    <p>I look back with loathing upon the day when I was
mad enough to listen to you and to become a partner in
your schemes. You flattered us, nay, you even fawned
upon us in order to secure your ends, and, now that our
forces have been joined with yours, ruin menaces my
country and my race. You, forsooth, allow yourself to
be held up as a great prophet of Islam and a Heaven-sent
protector of its faith; but we who see our nation
crumbling into dust owing to your selfish ambition may
be pardoned if at last we look to ourselves and attempt
to save what still remains to us. To work, as they say, for
the King of <name rend="sc">Prussia</name> has never been a profitable undertaking.</p>
                    <p>Yours,  <name rend="sc">Enver.</name>
                    </p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Fireworks were thrown from the gallery and the audience rushed
on the platform, pelting the Pacifists with red ochre. The meeting
ended with the sinking of Rule Britannia."—<title>Egyptian Gazette.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>The Pacifists appear to have had the last word, after all.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Mill Manager Honoured.—Mr. —— has been elected a Fellow
of the Royal Society for the encouragement of fits."—<title>Times of India.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>We do not recognise the Society, but imagine it may be
the Taylorian Institute.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"It will take about 12 days for goods traffic to become normal
again, although of course passenger traffic is not interfered with in
the slightest. In the meantime the booking of elephants and other
perishables has been stopped."—<title>Rangoon Times.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Unless, of course, they leave their trunks behind them.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>We observe that Mr. <name rend="sc">Waters Butler</name> has been appointed
a member of the Liquor Control Board, with the hearty
approval of the Birmingham Beer, Spirit and Wine
Trade Association. If there is anything in a name no
one should be better able to hold the balance between
them and the teetotalers.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page147" n="pg 147"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e492" type="div3">
                    <head>THE MILITARY REASON.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/147.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page148" n="pg 148"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/148.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e512" type="div2">
                <head>AT THE FRONT.</head>
                <p>Some officers like putting up barbed
wire, not so much, I think, from any
real deep-seated affection for the stuff
itself, or from any confidence in the
protection it affords—its disintegration
being one of the assumed preliminaries
of an attack—as for the satisfaction of
writing in the Weekly Work Report,
"In front of X276 we put up 97 rolls
of barbed wire; in front of S279, 342
rolls; in front of X276a, 3,692 rolls ..."
and so on.</p>
                <p>An officer who overdoes this sport of
kings gets a trench a bad name; it
becomes a trench with a great wiring
tradition to be maintained. One of us
took over a legacy from one of these
barbarians last trip. H.Q. had got
wind of his zeal and was determined
that we for our part should not be idle.
It was murmured in billets, it was
whispered upon the <title>pavé</title>, that for the
officer taking over B116 there was a
great wiring toward. The officer taking
over B116 hated wiring worse than
bully beef. He said you either die of
pneumonia through standing still pretending
to supervise, or tire yourself to
bits and earn the undying contempt of
your party by pretending to take an
active share in the game.</p>
                <p>Howbeit he took over B116 and was
told by the Next Man Up to wire to his
heart's content. He asked the Next
Man Up just where he wanted the
wiring to be performed. The Next Man
Up waved an airy arm in the direction
of the Hun, and observed, "Out there,
of course. Think we wanted you to wire
Hampstead Heath?" Then the B116
officer took the N.M.U. to the parapet
and showed him waving acres of high
wire, low wire, loose wire, tight wire,
thick wire, thin wire, two ply, three
ply, and four ply, plain and barbed,
running out and out into the dusk.</p>
                <p>The N.M.U. gave it all a dispassionate
sort of look, and merely said, "Oh,
go out in front of all that. The Bosch
is miles off just here."</p>
                <p>Now B116 is a front line trench in a
re-entrant. The Hun trench facing it
is also in a re-entrant, the original front
lines on both sides having been crumpled
and flooded out of existence. So when
night fell the officer of B116 took his
party and set out, and he went on and
on, and then on, and there was still
wire. And he went on and on and on.
And there were bits of old trenches and
saps and listening posts, but still wire.
And he went on and on and there were
more bits of trench and more wire.
And he went on and on—and I know
this is true because he told me—and
on and on until (no, he did not come
back to our own trench, he had a
compass) an exceptionally good lot of
fireworks went up, and he was fired at
and bombed by Germans behind and
Germans in front and Germans on
either side, and, mind you, he was still
in the wire. So he waited until all the
Germans appeared to have killed each
other or gone to sleep, and brought his
party laboriously back to B116, from
which he sent to the Next Man Up a
message which ran: "If you want me
to wire Bosch third line, kindly arrange
for artillery preparation."</p>
                <p>It is some days now since they put
up any wire in front of B116.</p>
                <p>It is a fact well known to all our
most widely-circulated photographic
dailies that these German gunners
<pb xml:id="page149" n="pg 149"/>
waste a power of ammunition. The
only criticism I have to make is that I
wish they would waste it more carefully.
The way they go strewing the stuff
about round us is such that they're
bound to hit someone or something
before long. Still we have only two
more days in, and they seldom give us
more than ten thousand shells a day.</p>
                <p>We are in billets now, and frankly,
I am beginning to be very exercised
about my boots. When I say "my
boots" I mean rather the boots concerning
me than "the boots that are
mine." I wanted, some couple of
months ago, a new pair of boots. I
told the Quartermaster, and he looked
at my then boots superciliously and
said he could quite believe it.</p>
                <p>I rashly left it at that, imagining
something would happen. A man
like a quartermaster, who rolls in boots,
would, I felt, think nothing of sending
along a dozen pairs before breakfast,
with a chit telling me to give away
what I couldn't use. But no. It seems
every boot in his store was numbered.</p>
                <p>I approached him again, and demanded
boots, soberly, seriously and strenuously,
I even offered to pay for them. This
appeared to cheer him a little, and he
murmured something about Army
Form 247 x2b, not at present in stock,
but indispensable to the issue of the
most negligible boot on payment. My
further efforts were, owing to exigencies
of my military situation, conducted
through emissaries. My servant would
demand of his company agent nightly,
what about them boots? And the
company agent would reply—also
nightly—that, if the officer would send
his size down, the matter would be
put through at once. For five nights
running my size in boots went down
with the empty water tins. On the
last night I added a sketch of my
feet and of my present boots, with
scale of kilometres subjoined, a brief
history of footgear in Flanders from
pre-Cæsarian times to the present day,
one piece of broken lace from the old
boots, and anything else that struck
me as likely to put the matter a little
further through.</p>
                <p>The lace appeared to put quite a new
idea into their heads. The advance
booting agent now seemed to think
that if I had some boots already I
might get the new pair by a process
known as exchange, which takes less
time and has the additional advantage
of not costing anything. This struck
them as an excellent new game for
several days while they were deciding
which was the right army form for an
officer desirous of exchanging boots.
At last all appeared fixed up. I came
back into billets with every confidence
of finding a couple of boots waiting for
me on the mat. Of course I didn't
really <hi rend="it">believe</hi> they would be there; I
only had every confidence. Anyhow
they were not.</p>
                <p>This morning the Quartermaster
called in person. He wanted to know
what size I took in boots.</p>
                <p>I expect now that the matter will be
put through almost at once.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e567" type="div3">
                    <head>OUR BOYS.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/149.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>An Impending Apology.</p>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Chaplain would appreciate portable Gramophone
for clearing station."—<title>The Times.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page150" n="pg 150"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e595" type="div2">
                <head>HARD CASES.</head>
                <p>Among other applications which were
recently heard for exemption from the
new Compulsory Service Act for unmarried
men we extract the following:—</p>
                <p>Mr. Isaac Goldstein claimed exemption
for his clerk, a stalwart youth of
twenty-two, on the ground that he was
indispensable to him in his business.</p>
                <p>Asked what his business was the
applicant said he was a bookmaker.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> I thought there was
no racing now.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Goldstein.</title> Oh, yes. Steeple-chasing
every week.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> Do people still go to
races and bet?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Goldstein.</title> Of course they do.
Why not?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> I fancied they might
have found other things to do. Also I
fancied that money might be short.</p>
                <p>The applicant said that there was
plenty of money about if you knew
where to look for it.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> And who ride the
horses?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Goldstein.</title> The jockeys, of course.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> They prefer that to
doing anything more serious for their
country?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Goldstein.</title> They are doing something
very serious for their country.
They're preserving the breed of horses.
Where would old England's horseflesh
be without races and steeplechases?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> You say this young
man is indispensable to you. How?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Goldstein.</title> He is my clerk. He
writes down the bets. I haven't got
time to write down bets myself; I'm
too busy taking them. He's one of the
quickest clerks in England. I should
go broke if I hadn't got him.</p>
                <p>Application refused.</p>
                <p>Mr. Joe Tummilee applied for the
exemption of a comedian playing in his
revue, "Never mind the War." This
young man, he said, who was twenty-nine,
was the life and soul of the piece,
and if he joined the Army the applicant
would be put both to inconvenience
and loss.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> Are there not older
or married actors that you could employ
for this great work?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Tummilee.</title> They're not so good.
The comedian in question was a very
agile dancer and was also good-looking.
Other men might not attract the
public.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> Is the attraction of
the public essential?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Tummilee (surprised).</title> Naturally.
How should we managers live otherwise?
Besides, when a great war is
going on it's a national duty to try
and make people forget. My theatre,
you perhaps are not aware, is a favourite
resort for wounded soldiers, who are
never so happy as when they are there.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> Surely all that
happiness will not disappear because
this one performer is missing?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Tummilee.</title> Most of it. He's the
great draw.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> Has it not occurred
to you that the country ought to come
first?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Tummilee.</title> I consider I'm doing
a great deal for the country, and he too,
by making it laugh.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> You must find an
older funny man or soon we may all
be weeping.</p>
                <p>Application refused.</p>
                <p>Mr. Samuel Bland claimed exemption
on the ground that he disapproved of
war and physical force.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> What would you do
if you caught a burglar in your house?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Applicant.</title> I should lock him in and
call for the police.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> Then you don't mind
relying on the physical force of others
for your own protection?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Applicant.</title> That is part of the machinery
of civilisation.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> So, I fear, is an army.
Do you pay your taxes?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Applicant.</title> Yes.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> Why?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Applicant.</title> Because there is
Scriptural warrant for it.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> But you know that
a large part of them goes to maintain
our fighting men. Without money we
should have to give in.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Applicant.</title> I obey the law. I don't
necessarily know where the money is
going.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> Your position is very
illogical. Either you should take your
part in defending your country or obey
your conscience and either go to prison
for refusing to pay taxes for the carrying-on
of the War, or emigrate to some
place more like Utopia than this is. As
it is you take advantage of other men's
readiness to fight and even to die for
you, and actually pay them to do so, but
raise conscientious objections to doing
either for yourself. A conscience that is
so adaptable is not worth considering.</p>
                <p>Application refused.</p>
                <p>Harry Cadgsmith, who said he was
a picture-palace proprietor, applied for
exemption for the commissionaire who
stood outside the building and invited
people in.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> How old is he?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Cadgsmith.</title> Thirty-four.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> Is he strong?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Cadgsmith.</title> Very. He is also
highly trained; he wears uniform and
calls out the attractions. The cinema
is one of the principal alleviations of
modern life and but for this man's
powerful voice many people might pass
by and never enter.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> What kind of pictures
do you show?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Cadgsmith.</title> The best.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> Are they English?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Cadgsmith.</title> Some are. But the
public prefer American ones. I always
pride myself on giving the public what
it has the sense to want.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> Might it not be
better employed elsewhere? Making
munitions, for example?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Cadgsmith.</title> That is nothing to
do with me. My business is to supply
a demand.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> What is your chief
film this week?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Cadgsmith.</title> It is a very fine
story entitled "The Prince of Crooks."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>The Chairman.</title> Could not a woman
take this man's place?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Mr. Cadgsmith.</title> Not to do it justice.</p>
                <p>Application refused.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e913" type="div2">
                <head>SUAVE MARI MAGNO.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e917" type="div3">
                    <head>(New Style).</head>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>'Tis sweet, so sage <name rend="sc">Lucretius</name> wrote of yore,</l>
                            <l>To watch a storm-tossed vessel from the shore,</l>
                            <l>Or safely placed, when hosts in conflict close,</l>
                            <l>To view the battle as it ebbs and flows;</l>
                            <l>But he, poor ancient, never knew the rare</l>
                            <l>Delight afforded by an easy-chair,</l>
                            <l>Wherein the slippered critic, at his ease,</l>
                            <l>His ample writing-pad upon his knees,</l>
                            <l>Primed with historic and romantic lore,</l>
                            <l>Indites his weekly comment on the War;</l>
                            <l>Revises or expands official news</l>
                            <l>With graphic touches and resplendent hues;</l>
                            <l>Teaches the doubtful battle where to rage</l>
                            <l>And sprinkles diagrams on ev'ry page;</l>
                            <l>Creates new posts or, at his own sweet will,</l>
                            <l>Proceeds expected vacancies to fill;</l>
                            <l>Deposes Kings, Prime Ministers, Grand Dukes,</l>
                            <l>And rival pundits suitably rebukes.</l>
                            <l>A hundred thousand readers every week</l>
                            <l>For solace in his commentaries seek,</l>
                            <l>Swear by his arguments, and swear at those</l>
                            <l>Which rival quidnuncs artfully oppose.</l>
                            <l>Matched with an occupation such as this</l>
                            <l>Philosophy is destitute of bliss;</l>
                            <l>He only breathes content's untroubled air</l>
                            <l>Who wages warfare from a snug armchair.</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page151" n="pg 151"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/151.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1023" type="div2">
                <head>GOOD OPENINGS FOR M.P.'s.</head>
                <p>
                    <title>The Manchester Guardian</title> complains
that there is a remarkable monotony
about the opening of speeches in the
House of Commons.</p>
                <p>"On Wednesday forty-five speeches
(not counting brief efforts in the way
of interjections) were delivered, and in
thirty cases the speeches began with
the first person singular. Only fifteen
members could think of anything more
original." It appears that four speeches
began with "I beg," four with "I
should like," three with "I wish," and
three with "I am sure."</p>
                <p>It may be a little daring, perhaps, to
suggest that some originality should
be introduced into the methods of Parliamentary
orators (writes a correspondent);
but as one whose courage
has never failed him in telling other
people how to go about their business
I venture to suggest a few openings
which possibly have never yet been
utilised.</p>
                <p>As it is half the battle, to the speaker,
to grip interest at the very outset, the
following might be tried: "Drip, drip,
drip—the blood fell from the ceiling."
This would cause departing Members
to drop sharply back into their seats.
Only a little ingenuity would be required
to make these words the opening
of a speech on any timely topic.
Our aristocratic legislators could make
certain of arresting attention by beginning,
"In the words of a friend of mine,
a well-known Peckham butcher"—another
gambit that could be made to
suit any subject, from the shipping
problem to the Zeppelin nuisance.</p>
                <p>Or again, "The missis woke me up
in the middle of last Tuesday night,
and said"—This is the kind of
homely touch that would ensure a
sympathetic hearing.</p>
                <p>Members might also make a good
start with "'Twas" and "Methinks,"
even at the risk of being accused of the
use of unparliamentary expressions.</p>
                <p>If they would only study the poets
I they would find plenty of bright and
original openings. What better could
be desired than <name rend="sc">Browning's</name>
                </p>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>"So, at home, the sick tall yellow Duchess</l>
                        <l>Was left with the infant in her clutches,"</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <p>if occasion should arise in the House
for criticism of the heartless action of a
Local Tribunal in disallowing a Duke's
claim for exemption?</p>
                <p>Many a man possesses an undiscovered
knack of extempore rhyming,
a gift which has seldom or never been
exercised in the House of Commons.
That will be a bright day for legislators
when a Member rises in his place and
begins something like this: "Sir, if
the House will bear with me one
moment, I should like to say that I,
for one, cannot agree that we have
found the perfect way of dealing with
a gross neglect to which all honest
men object." Any Member who could
keep up that sort of thing for half-an-hour
(and some, no doubt, could, if they
would only practise) would achieve
lasting fame, not only for his originality,
but because of the remarkable scenes
amid which his concluding lines would
almost certainly be uttered.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"The Germans planned to expel the British
from South Africa, aided by disinfected Boers."</p>
                    <p rend="i6">
                        <title>Englishman (Calcutta)</title>,
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>But, in the end, it was General <name rend="sc">Botha</name>
who cleared out the Germs.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page152" n="pg 152"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/152.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1105" type="div2">
                <head>MY DUG-OUT.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e1109" type="div3">
                    <head>(A Memory of Gallipoli)</head>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>It was my home, not ringed with roses blowing,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Nor set in meadows where cool waters croon;</l>
                            <l>Parched wastes were round it, and no shade was going,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Nor breath of violets nor song-birds' tune;</l>
                            <l>Only at times from the adjacent dwelling</l>
                            <l>Came down with Boreas the quaint, compelling</l>
                            <l rend="i6">Scent of the Tenth Platoon.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>And there not hermit-like alone I brooded,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">But ant and lizard and all things that crawl</l>
                            <l>With great grasshoppers by brigades intruded;</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Therein the tortoise had his homely stall;</l>
                            <l>Green flies and blue slept nightly in their notches,</l>
                            <l>Save when a serpent, in the middle watches,</l>
                            <l rend="i6">Came and disturbed us all.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>There, where the sun, the senseless sun, kept pouring,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">And dust-clouds smothered one about the chest,</l>
                            <l>While secret waters filtered through the flooring</l>
                            <l rend="i2">(In case the heat should leave one <hi rend="it">too</hi> oppressed),</l>
                            <l>Always I lay in those sad fevered seasons</l>
                            <l>Which Red-Hat humourists, for mystic reasons,</l>
                            <l rend="i6">Regarded as our "rest."</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>For it was home; and when I was not in it,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">But in the trenches, it was home indeed;</l>
                            <l>When mad foes fired at twenty rounds a minute</l>
                            <l rend="i2">(Not, I may say, the regulation speed),</l>
                            <l>For me far more it harboured my Penates;</l>
                            <l>I missed my animals; I missed my gay teas</l>
                            <l rend="i6">With Alf, the centipede.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>And I am shocked to think that that same ceiling</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Shields now some Mussulman of lowly strain;</l>
                            <l>Yet, though he knows me not, I can't help feeling</l>
                            <l rend="i2">That something of my spirit must remain,</l>
                            <l>And if, in that rich air the man should mellow</l>
                            <l>In mind, in soul, and be a better fellow,</l>
                            <l rend="i6">I have not lived in vain.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>And it may be, when worlds have ceased to wrestle,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">I shall go back across the Midland foam</l>
                            <l>At special rates in some large tourist vessel</l>
                            <l rend="i2">To my late hollow in the Sultan's loam,</l>
                            <l>And there clasp hands with that uplifted warrior,</l>
                            <l>Compare brief notes and wonder which was sorrier</l>
                            <l rend="i6">To have to call it home.</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1272" type="div3">
                    <head>How to treat a Wife.</head>
                    <p>Extract from lecture by N.C.O.:—</p>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Your rifle is your best friend, take every care of it; treat it as
you would your wife, rub it all over with an oily rag every day."
</p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"The court was crowded by Gaelic Leaguers and the proceedings
were marked by some disorderly scenes, until the magistrates ordered
their continuance."—<title>Dublin Evening Mail.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Then, of course, being in Ireland, they ceased.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>A Provincial Paper, reporting a speech upon heroes of
the present War, represents the speaker as referring to
"Bill Adams in Leigh Hunt's poem." This is the first time
within our knowledge that our old friend <title>Abou Ben Adhem</title>
has been confounded with that other popular figure, the
fictitious hero of Waterloo!</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page153" n="pg 153"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1312" type="div3">
                    <head>THE NEW FRIGHTFULNESS.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/153.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page154" n="pg 154"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1325" type="div2">
                <head>A STRONG SOUTH-EASTER.</head>
                <p>I have been having further trouble
with my neighbour, Petherton, whose
place adjoins mine, being divided from
it by a hedge. Beyond the hedge lies
Petherton's small paddock, where his
poultry amuse themselves, and, beyond
that, Petherton's house and garden.</p>
                <p>But, however good a fence may be, it
will not keep out, or keep in, smells.
Therefore when Petherton engaged in
apparently chemical operations giving
off the most noxious gases I was
rapidly forced to the conclusion that
he ought to have a different kind of
boundary between his property and
mine, and also that the air of our
neighbourhood no longer rivalled that
of Bexhill, especially when the wind
blew from the south-east.</p>
                <p>Wishing to remedy this state of
affairs without recourse to unpleasant
measures, I sat down to write to
Petherton.</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Dear Petherton</name>,—These continual
south-easterly winds portend rain, I
fear, and so I hope you have wrapped
your parsnips up to protect them from
the probable excess of moisture which
is so injurious to all such plants.</p>
                    <p>My primary object in writing is not
so much anxiety about the health of
your vegetables, but to ask whether
you have noticed a most unpleasant
odour which seems to be heading north-west;
at any rate it is more unpleasant
if possible when the wind is from the
south-east than at any other time.</p>
                    <p>It does not appear likely that the
smell should have come from the
German lines, so we must look nearer
home for the cause of the trouble.
Don't you think we ought to take joint
action to get the nuisance ended?</p>
                    <p>Yours, <name rend="sc">H. J. Fordyce.</name>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>Petherton's reply was a bulky packet
which, being opened, revealed a tin of
dog soap. I could only infer that he
wished to saddle Togo, our prize-bred
Airedale, with the blame. Coward!</p>
                <p>However, true to my determination
to be friendly if possible, I wrote:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Dear Fred</name>,—Thanks for the Camembert.
Thomas our cat has not quite
completed the Moonlight Sonata which
he has spent several nights in composing,
but as soon as it is published I
will send you a copy of it in return.</p>
                    <p>My nephew, over from France on
short leave, came to see us yesterday
but left hurriedly. He said that the
air was too reminiscent of a place
where he was severely gassed. <title>Don't
you notice anything?</title>
                    </p>
                    <p>Yours as ever,  <name rend="sc">H. J. Fordyce</name>.
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>Within an hour of the delivery of
this letter another parcel arrived from
Petherton. It contained three ordinary
clothes-pegs and a brief note, which
ran:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="sc">Sir</hi>,—I thought even you would be
able to take the hint contained in my
previous parcel. As however it was
evidently lost on you, I am writing to
suggest to you more plainly that you
should wash your dog. I noticed its
deplorable condition when I passed it
in the road the other morning, and am
surprised that the simple explanation
of the trouble has not occurred to you
before.</p>
                    <p>Should the course I recommend have
no good effect, I can only suggest your
shooting, selling or otherwise disposing
of the malodorous pest, or else wearing
one of the protectors of which I enclose
three. They are somewhat archaic in
design, but should just suit you and
your household.</p>
                    <p>Yours faithfully,</p>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Frederick Petherton.</name>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>I replied:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Good old Freddie</name>,—What a genius
you are! Of course the dog is the
culprit. I was offered fifteen pounds
for him the other day and refused it.
No doubt I should have received a
better offer but for the defect, which
you so readily noticed, in the animal's
condition. I have just had him shampooed
and when he is dry I will examine
him and report to you at once.</p>
                    <p>Many thanks for the charming nose-protectors,
which however I return, as
they are all too large. I wonder if you
would mind changing them for sevens;
these appear to be eight-and-a-halfs.</p>
                    <p>I am glad the wind has veered to
the north-east. Your parsnips will no
doubt share my joy. By the way was
it you I saw yesterday in your paddock
holding your nose just before the wind
shifted round? The man, whoever it
was, was looking at your poultry,
which appear to be drooping.</p>
                    <p>Yours till the wind changes,</p>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">H. J. Fordyce</name>.</p>
                    <p>P.S.—If I can get a good stamp-album
in town to-day I will send it to
you. A change of hobby is often very
beneficial.
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>I followed this up with another
letter in the afternoon, couched in
more formal terms:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="sc">Sir</hi>,—In fulfilment of the promise
contained in my previous letter of to-day's
date I have the honour to inform
you that my dog Togo is not the cause
of the trouble. As soon as he was dry
I fastened him up in the middle of my
drawing-room, and my household, myself
included, sniffed at him from all
points of the compass. Then, leaving
him still chained up, we went into the
garden and nearly fainted from the
pestilential odours borne on the breeze,
which was again south-east.</p>
                    <p>If you have not suffered it seems
clear to me that either (<hi rend="it">a</hi>) you have a
curious taste in scents, or (<hi rend="it">b</hi>) you have
no sense of smell. I think you should
call in an expert, in the case of (<hi rend="it">a</hi>) a
brain specialist, or in the case of (<hi rend="it">b</hi>) a
nose-plumber. In the meantime I
intend to consult another sort of expert,
the Sanitary Inspector.</p>
                    <p>Yours obediently, except in such a
matter as this,       <name rend="sc">H. J. Fordyce</name>.
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>I wrote to the Inspector that night
and received the following within
twenty-four hours:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Dear Sir</name>,—Yours of yesterday's date
to hand, and in reply I regret that I am
unable to assist you in the matter as
your neighbour, Mr. Petherton, is engaged
on important experimental work
for the Government in connection with
the manufacture of asphyxiating gases,
thus causing the unpleasant odours
about which I have received several
complaints recently. I have been in
communication with Mr. Petherton on
the matter, but he seems unable to
abate the nuisance. I am surprised
that he has not explained the position
to you himself.</p>
                    <p>I remain, Yours obediently,</p>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">M. Tarbutt.</name>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="it">pp</hi>. A. C.
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>On receiving the above I wrote to
Petherton:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Dear Fred</name>,—Only a few words to
say that I have just heard the great
news. Heartiest congratters. As a
strafe-scent-manufacturer you are IT.
<title>À bas les Boches!</title>
                    </p>
                    <p>But why so close about it all this
time? If you had only let me know
about it sooner I would have dug a
trench in my garden and slept in it, instead
of complaining. Henceforth I
shall turn my nose (well respirated) to
the south-east every morning as an act
of homage.</p>
                    <p>Give it 'em hot, old man; don't mind
us; we love it now. When you get
stuck for any fresh ingredients refer to
<title>Macbeth</title>, Act 4, Scene I, though I
should be inclined to think you have
done this already.</p>
                    <p>Yours gratefully, <name rend="sc">H. J. Fordyce</name>.
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>So far I have received no reply from
Petherton. In the circumstances I excuse
his apparent hauteur.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e1539" type="div3">
                    <head>"Ships that pass in the Night."</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"A large number of our kinsmen from over
the seas were unmarried, and he would like to
see for every shipload of them that came over
a shipload of women from this country sent
out to be mated to them."—<title>Daily Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>It looks as if it might be stalemate.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page155" n="pg 155"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1559" type="div2">
                <head>ESSENCE OF PARLIAMENT.</head>
                <p>
                    <title>Monday, February 21st.</title>—Although
<title>de minimis non curat lex</title>, our law-makers
delight in very small jokes.
When Mr. <name rend="sc">Cecil Beck</name>, as Vice-Chamberlain
of the Household, delivered <name rend="sc">His
Majesty</name>'s reply to the Address the
House of Commons was chiefly interested
in watching how he would accomplish
the feat of walking backwards
from the Table to the Bar. More than
once in past history the task has proved
too much for the man who essayed it,
and the orderly retreat has degenerated
into a shambling rout. But there was
no such hitch to-day. Progressive
politician though he is, Mr. <name rend="sc">Beck</name> retraced
his steps with graceful ease,
and fully deserved the applause that
rewarded his effort.</p>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/155a.png"/>
                </figure>
                <p>Irreverent opponents of the <name rend="sc">Prime
Minister</name> have sometimes compared
him to <title>Micawber</title>, on the ground that
he was always waiting for something
to turn up. I found another link to-day
between these celebrated characters.
As Mr. <name rend="sc">Asquith</name> unfolded the details of
the two new Votes of Credit, one of
120 millions to clear up the present
financial year, the other of 300 millions
to start the new one, he reminded me
of <title>Micawber</title> calculating his indebtedness
to <title>Traddles</title>. While professing a
proper alarm at the colossal amount of
the expenditure—nearly two thousand
millions already, or twice the cost of
the twenty-two years' war against
<name rend="sc">Napoleon</name>—he rolled these gigantic
figures off his tongue as if he loved
them. You will remember <title>Copperfield's</title>
remark when the famous I.O.U. had
been handed over: "I am persuaded
not only that this was quite the same
to Mr. Micawber as paying the money,
but that Traddles himself hardly knew
the difference until he had had
to think about it." The
<name rend="sc">Prime Minister's</name> financial
optimism left the House
under much the same impression,
and Mr. <name rend="sc">McKenna</name>
rather deepened it by the
declaration that with prudence
and statesmanship
our credit would survive the
War however long it might
last.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Tuesday, February 22nd.</title>—For
nearly ten years, without
a break, Mr. <name rend="sc">George
Lambert</name>, Yeoman, as the
reference-books describe
him, sat on the Treasury
Bench as Civil Lord of the
Admiralty. Then the Coalition
came along and his
place knew him no more.
For eight long months he
has yearned to let the new Administration
know what he thought of them,
and to-day he seized the opportunity
furnished by the Vote on Account.</p>
                <p>Beginning with a moving tale of
how the War Office took several weeks
and a traction engine to move a load
of hay two miles from a rick to a
railway station in his native Devon,
the Yeoman proceeded with other
counts of his indictment. The <name rend="sc">Prime
Minister</name> mentioned yesterday a new
plan by which an outside Committee,
composed of business men and headed
by a Cabinet Minister, was checking
the expenditure of the Service Departments.
(The cost of shells, we were
told to-day by Dr. <name rend="sc">Addison</name>, has been
brought down to a figure which means
an economy of £400,000 a week on our
future production.)</p>
                <p>But Mr. <name rend="sc">Lambert</name> would have none
of it. Speaking with all the authority
of his long official experience he laid
down the dictum that one Cabinet
Minister could not supervise another.
Next he attacked the new Order in
Council, which makes the Chief of the
Staff responsible for the orders given to
the Army, declaring that it reduced
Lord <name rend="sc">Kitchener</name> to the level of a
civilian; and finally he denounced the
Government for not making more use
of Lord <name rend="sc">Fisher</name>. Under the stress of
these terrific blows the Government
ought to have reeled, if it did not fall.
But nothing happened, except that the
Votes on Account for four hundred and
twenty millions were by half-past seven
duly passed.</p>
                <p>In the Lords meanwhile the Government
was sustaining a heavier attack,
arising out of their failure to stop all
supplies from reaching Germany. Lord
<name rend="sc">Sydenham</name> attributed it to the Declaration
of London, which had crippled the
Navy; Lord <name rend="sc">Beresford</name> thought it
was the result of trying to run a war
with a Cabinet that included twenty-one
amateurs. Lord <name rend="sc">Lansdowne</name>, a
master of the quip modest, thereupon
stated the Government's intention to
add a twenty-second to the twenty-one
by appointing a Minister of Blockade.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Wednesday, February 23rd.</title>—At
Question-time, Mr. <name rend="sc">Asquith</name> announced
that the new Minister was Lord <name rend="sc">Robert
Cecil</name>. It is close upon fifty years since
another Lord <name rend="sc">Robert Cecil</name> (who had
just become Lord <name rend="sc">Cranborne</name>) entered
the Cabinet of Lord <name rend="sc">Derby</name>.</p>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/155b.png"/>
                </figure>
                <p>In consequence of the recent decision
that no Member shall in future receive
two salaries it had been rumoured
that Parliamentary salaries would be
abolished altogether. There were signs
of heartfelt relief from
various quarters of the
House when the <name rend="sc">Premier</name>
met the suggestion with an
uncompromising "No."</p>
                <p>Captain J. S. <name rend="sc">Rankine</name>,
the khaki-clad giant who
took his seat for East Toxteth
to-day, had a warm
reception, all the more
grateful in view of the blizzard
that raged without.
The temperature of the
House fell rapidly, however,
when Mr. <name rend="sc">Snowden</name> proceeded
to outline his views
on the subject of peace. In
vain he attempted to show
that there was a considerable
party in Germany
ready to come to terms if
only they knew what our
<pb xml:id="page156" n="pg 156"/>
terms were. Members listened in chilly
silence. They thawed into laughter
when the Hon. Member with some
lack of humour quoted the German
<name rend="sc">Chancellor's</name> declaration, "We do not
threaten small nations;" and they
cheered when he quoted, with intent
to condemn, Lord <name rend="sc">Rosebery's</name> statement
that Germany must be utterly
crushed. Nor was the House more
impressed by Mr. <name rend="sc">Trevelyan's</name> proposal
that as there might be a peace-party
in Germany it was our duty to
"state our full terms and find out."</p>
                <p>The <name rend="sc">Prime Minister's</name> reply was,
I fear, very painful to the pacificists.
The German <name rend="sc">Chancellor's</name> statement
he found to be one of "colossal and
shameless audacity." German Socialists
might prate of peace, but only
twenty out of five times that number in
the Reichstag had the courage to vote
against the War Credit. Our terms
were already on record in the speech
which he made at the <name rend="sc">Lord Mayor's</name>
Banquet in 1914. Until Belgium—"and
I will add Serbia"—has been
fully reinstated, until France is secured
against aggression, until the smaller
nationalities are safeguarded, until
the military domination of Prussia is
destroyed, "not until then shall we or
any of our gallant Allies abate by one
jot our prosecution of this War." The
cheers that greeted this declaration
lasted almost as long as the speech
itself. In the ensuing debate Mr.
<name rend="sc">Ponsonby</name>, Sir W. <name rend="sc">Byles</name>, and one or
two others emitted what Mr. <name rend="sc">Stanton</name>
picturesquely described as "the croakings
and bleatings of the fatted lambs
who had besmirched their own country."
But they created no effect. Mr. <name rend="sc">Snowden</name>'s
early peace had been nipped by
the frost.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Thursday, February 24th.</title>—In both
Houses the administration of the Military
Service Act was again the subject
of criticism. From the explanations
given by Lord <name rend="sc">Newton</name> and Mr.
<name rend="sc">Tennant</name> it appears that most of the
complaints against the recruiting officers
for over-pressure have come from
men who were applying for armlets,
not for exemption. As Lord <name rend="sc">Newton</name>
put it, a man, if he wants to obtain
an armlet, must run the risk of being
taken for some kind of service. Mr.
<name rend="sc">Tennant</name> reminded some of his critics,
not superfluously, that the object of
this Act was to get men to serve.</p>
                <p>Lord <name rend="sc">Derby</name>, fresh from his triumph
as Director of Recruiting, is to act as
Chairman of the new Joint Committee
which will supervise and co-ordinate
naval and military aviation. For him,
as for that other <title>Ariel</title>, "there's more
work." The same is now true of Colonel
<name rend="sc">Lockwood</name> who, since the opening of
the Session, has been in a condition
of suspended animation. The Kitchen
Committee, in the opinion of many
Members the most important of all the
Committees, had not been set up, and
consequently could not elect a Chairman.
How Members have lived
through more than a week without
any visible means of securing subsistence
it is not for me to reveal. Suffice
it to say that no case of absolute
starvation has come to my notice. To-day
all is well. The Kitchen Committee
is again in being, and "Uncle
Mark" has once more been appointed
Minister of the Interior (unpaid, except
by the gratitude and affection of his
fellow-Members). Fresh responsibilities
have now been thrust upon him.
This afternoon it fell to him, as temporary
Leader of the Opposition, to ask
the customary question as to next
week's business. Having heard the
<name rend="sc">Prime Minister's</name> reply, he sat for a
few moments as if lost in thought, calculating,
no doubt, by a rapid process
of mental arithmetic what the Consolidated
Fund Bill, Supplementary Estimates
and the Civil Service Vote would
amount to in terms of dinners, teas
and other light refreshments.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/156.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>On a bookseller's stall in Liverpool:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"<title>The English Nation</title>. A really cheap lot."
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>We find them most expensive to keep up.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page157" n="pg 157"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1803" type="div2">
                <head>ON THE SPY-TRAIL.</head>
                <p>Jimmy says his bloodhound is always
very glad to get loose after being tied
up all night, and it's because <name rend="sc">Harvey</name>
discovered the circulation of the blood.
Jimmy says Faithful doesn't know he
has got the circulation of the blood,
but he always has a little run round
when he gets free. It only takes him
about five minutes to do his round,
and an hour and a-half afterwards you
would never believe he had been round
at all, things are so quiet again.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says the man next door told
him he didn't mind so much about
the circulation of the blood as the
circulation of the bloodhound. Jimmy
says it's because his chickens all begin
shouting Hooray! as soon as Faithful
starts, and they get up trees to watch
him instead of being busy laying eggs
at twopence each. Faithful doesn't
want them to go up trees, Jimmy says,
and tries to make them come down,
but they won't—not on any account—and
he has to leave them for other
things that require his attention.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says there's a charwoman in
one of the houses on Faithful's beat,
and sometimes you can hear her trying
to char him, and then lots of things
come out through the front door, with
Faithful in the middle of them. Sometimes
you don't know which is Faithful
and which is a scrubbing-brush, and
it's because of the revolution. Jimmy
says if Faithful notices that anything
wants doing on his way round he
always tries to do it, even though
nobody knew that it wanted doing.
Faithful got a sparrow out of a greenhouse
like that, Jimmy says. It was a
cheeky sparrow and kept flying about
at Faithful and hiding behind the pots
on the stage. Jimmy says bloodhounds
don't stand any nonsense of that sort,
and the sparrow ought to have known
it. But it kept looking round flower-pots
at Faithful and chirruping at
him sideways, and didn't realise that
its life hung by a thread.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says the best of well-trained
bloodhounds is that they never get flurried;
they go about their work systematically.
The sparrow didn't seem to
know that, Jimmy says, and when
Faithful got on the stage and began
clearing the decks for action it actually
had the face to go and pick up a worm
that came out of one of the pots that
fell on the ground. Jimmy says whenever
a pot rolled off the stage Faithful
always looked over the edge to see if it
had arrived safely. He is always careful
like that.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says the sparrow only escaped
by the skin of its teeth, because just as
Faithful had got everything out of the
way and was going to set to work in
earnest, the sparrow flew out and went
and sat up in a tree chirruping like
anything. Faithful was absolutely disgusted
with it, Jimmy says.</p>
                <p>Jimmy took his bloodhound out to
the Hill Farm one morning. The
farmer was very glad to see Faithful
again, Jimmy says; he told Jimmy that
they were going to cut corn and there
would be a main of rabbits in them for
sure. Jimmy says bloodhounds have
to turn their hands to anything these
days, even catching rabbits. Faithful
didn't seem to mind, Jimmy says, but
<pb xml:id="page158" n="pg 158"/>
it seemed very curious to hear the deep
baying of a bloodhound in a peaceful
cornfield.  Jimmy says it made the
men stop work and look at each other,
and the man who was driving the reaping-machine
got down to see where it
wanted oiling. You see he hadn't heard
a bloodhound before.</p>
                <p>There was another dog there, Jimmy
says, in case the rabbits came out too
quickly for Faithful to catch them all.
The first rabbit that came out didn't
have any chance, Jimmy says. It bolted
out as hard as it could, and there was
a splendid race between the rabbit and
Faithful. You see the rabbit was
making for a burrow in the hedge, but
old Faithful got there first and tried to
get his head down it, to cut off the
rabbit's retreat. Jimmy says
the rabbit was nonplussed, and
the other dog caught it easily.
It is beautiful to see two dogs
work together like that, Jimmy
says.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says Faithful didn't
require the help of the other
dog with the next rabbit that
came his way, but the other
dog was very impulsive. You
see Faithful was lying down
with his mouth open trying to
look like a rabbit hole, and he
did it so well that the rabbit
came straight at him. Jimmy
says Faithful swerved about
ten yards to one side in order
to hurl himself bodily at the
rabbit, and he would have done
it if the other dog hadn't poked
his nose in.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says the other dog
killed the rabbit, but Faithful
went up and smelt at it like
anything. Faithful is a splendid smeller,
Jimmy says. He can retrieve rabbits
almost as well as he can catch them.</p>
                <p>The farmer was surprised to see how
quickly Faithful got off the mark at
the sound of the gun. You see the
farmer was standing close by Faithful
and he had no sooner shot at a rabbit
than away went Faithful right across
two fields, retrieving as hard as he could.
Jimmy had to fetch him back from
doing it.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says it was a new experience
for the men to have a trained bloodhound
in the harvest field, and they
could talk of nothing else whilst they
were having their dinners.  You see
two of the men had mislaid their
dinners somehow, and every time they
looked at Faithful they kept wondering.
One man said his dinner was in a
pudding-basin, and he looked everywhere.
Faithful did his best to help
him, Jimmy says, and kept just two
yards ahead of him, twisting in and out.</p>
                <p>The man noticed something was
the matter with Faithful and advised
Jimmy to have his neck wrung: he
offered to do it himself.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says the man seemed very
suspicious because Faithful looked so
T.B. (you know: Totally Bulged); but
Jimmy took up Faithful and shook
him for the man to hear, and there
wasn't any sound of broken crockery
at all.</p>
                <p>The other man who had lost his dinner
didn't bother to look for it; he was
busy cutting a stick out of the hedge,
and when he had done it he borrowed
a piece of bacon from another
man to present to Faithful. Jimmy
says you do it by saying, "Dear little
doggie," in a husky voice. Jimmy
says bloodhounds don't like husky
voices, they get on their nerves. So
Faithful refused the bacon as hard as
he could.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says he knew Faithful would
follow him, and sure enough, when he
had got a mile on his way home, there
was Faithful waiting for him, holding
the pudding-basin in his mouth by the
cloth.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says when he got home there
was quite a crowd round the house
where Faithful had removed the greenhouse
from off the sparrow. A policeman
told Jimmy all about it. It
appeared, so the policeman said, that
some person or persons unknown had
got to know that the people in the
house were harbouring a German
governess and had smashed up the
greenhouse in revenge. The greenhouse
looked as if it had been struck by a
bomb, the policeman said, and when
the people saw it they knew their
secret was out and went and confessed
to the police. The policeman told
Jimmy that they had just taken the
German governess away to the police-station.</p>
                <p>Jimmy says that when he got home
he sat down and looked at Faithful for
half-an-hour—just looked at him. To
think that Faithful had been on the
Spy Trail all the time and Jimmy never
knew it!</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e1868" type="div3">
                    <head>An Incisive Beginning.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Mr. Gordon Hewart, opening the president
of the London Chamber of Commerce ..."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>The Star</title>.
</p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>The Hebdomadal Council of Oxford
University have suspended for six
months the filling of the Professorship
of Modern Greek, the view apparently
being that there is no one
about just now who understands
the modern Greek.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/158.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"<title>The Rivista Marittima</title> publishes
details of a new German ironclad,
which is claimed to be totally unsinkable....
It is said to be a
Dreadnought-cruiser, fitted with
triple skins of armour, stuffed with
non-resisting material."—<title>Times.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>It sounds like one of our conscientious
objectors.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"The albatross—its docility was
charming—soon occupied a splendid
isolation on the tarpaulined covered
hatchway platform.... I shall in
future read Keats' 'Ancient Mariner'
with an accentuated interest."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Natal Witness.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Coleridge's</name> "Ode to a Nightingale"
was rejected as dealing
with the wrong bird.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Young Lady-Attendant for Allies'
Rifle Range, to replace one getting
married; the 3rd in 12 months doing the
same; good remuneration, and comfortable
job."—<title>Glasgow Citizen.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Bow and arrow or .303, Cupid's markmanship
remains unerring.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"<name rend="sc">The Man who dined at Krupp's and
worked with the Kaiser</name>."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Morning Paper Heading</title>.
</p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>The <hi rend="it">menu</hi> at <name rend="sc">Krupp's</name> is not given, but
was probably some form of pig.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1978" type="div3">
                    <head>Another Impending Apology.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"SCOTCH NURSES IN SERBIA.</p>
                        <p>GERMAN DOCTOR'S IMPRESSIONS.</p>
                        <p>'VERY FORBIDDING.'"</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Egyptian Gazette.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>From a notice of a recent novel:—</p>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"The present reviewer's pen cleaves to the
roof of his mouth when he tries to describe
it."—<title>Evening Standard.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>That should teach him to get rid of the
nasty habit of sucking the nib.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page159" n="pg 159"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e2022" type="div3">
                    <head>MULE HUMOUR.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/159a.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/159b.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/159c.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/159d.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page160" n="pg 160"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e2051" type="div2">
                <head>OUR BOOKING-OFFICE.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e2055" type="div3">
                    <head>(By Mr. Punch's Staff of Learned Clerks.)</head>
                    <p>I think I never read a story that impressed me as more
untimely than this to which Mr. <name rend="sc">Ivor Brown</name> has given
the title of <title>Security</title> (<name rend="sc">Secker</name>). It is about an Oxford Don,
one <title>John Grant</title>, who became, as others have become, irked
by the placid routine of Senior Common-Room existence,
and yearned for adventure. So he came to London, and
got his first dose of it as a labour-agitator and backer of
strikes. I suppose that the atmosphere of labour-agitating
and strike-backing is skilfully conveyed (that of Oxford
donship undoubtedly is), but I can't tell you how antique
it all seems. These scornful quotations from an imaginary
Capitalist press and the fierce denial that industrial strife
was ever assisted by foreign agencies—it all sounds like a
voice from ancient history. One rubs one's ears at it.
Eventually militant Socialism wearies <title>John</title> as much as
academic torpor had done, and to escape from both he
marries a wife. More atmosphere, this time of a dreary
little seaside town and its so-called society. But <title>John</title>
fares no better here; and at last, on his return from a
walking holiday, he finds that
<title>Mrs. John</title>, unable to put up
with him any longer, is putting
up without him at a London
hotel in company with Another.
That seems a situation
insecure enough to satisfy the
most exacting. But even from
this nothing results, and husband
and wife drift together
again. I like to think that
nowadays, what with Zeps and
other things, poor old <title>John</title>
may grow really contented.
Meanwhile, clever as it is, the
tale seems oddly anæmic and
unreal. It is like those tragically
trivial journals of 1914
that still survive in the dusty
waiting-rooms of dentists. I
don't suggest that Mr. <name rend="sc">Brown</name>,
whose previous book I much admired, should write about
the War; but I could wish him a little more in tune with
the spirit it has produced.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>
                        <title>Faith Tresilion</title> (<name rend="sc">Ward, Lock</name>) is a book of brave and of
some diabolical deeds, but as Mr. <name rend="sc">Eden Phillpotts</name> sees to
it that his murderers and wreckers get their due he leaves
me with the hopeful feeling that what happened to super-criminals
a hundred years or so ago will also be their fate
in this year of grace. <title>Faith</title> is the type of heroine with
whom readers of this amazingly industrious author are
familiar—a fearless girl who does a man's work without
for a moment becoming unsexed. She was in a difficult
position enough, for her brother was a smuggler and she
was in love, head to heels, with the local gangster.  There
are other complications, but this is the chief one, and it is
worked out in Mr. <title>Phillpotts</title>' best West-country manner.
I accept <title>Faith</title> and salute her, but it is before her mother
that I completely bow the knee. Mrs. <title>Tresilion</title> was paralysed
up to her waist, which was just as well, for if her
activities had not been limited she would have swamped
the whole book. As it was she lay in bed, drank gin,
directed various operations with her eye fixed rather upon
this world than the next, and told her visitors precisely
what she thought of them. I am thankful not to have met
this devastating lady in the flesh, because to be called "a
hookery-snidy, trundle-trailed king-crab," and then told to
kiss her, would have been more than I could bear.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>I feel that Miss <name rend="sc">Constance Holme</name> will be the first to
agree with me on reflection that as a beginning of a chapter
in <title>The Old Road from Spain</title> (<name rend="sc">Mills</name>) the following will
not do: "The long bright day idled interminably to its
tryst with night. Luis ate his lonely meals in the silent
room," etc. It illustrates a defect of her rather over-intense
method. She would readily forgive me this stricture if she
could know the eagerness with which I read her picturesque
pages to find out exactly what was the matter with the
<title>Huddlestons</title> of Thorn. From a Spanish ancestor, who
had been wrecked with the Armada, they had inherited a
<name rend="sc">curse</name>. It was a very original curse, and I dare not
deprive you of the pleasure of finding out what it was for
yourself. Miss <name rend="sc">Holme</name> puts in her background of mystery
with skilful touches and handles her characterisation with
a good deal more subtlety than your mere mystery-monger
can command. She observes both men and things with
affection, writes of them with imagination. <title>Rowly Huddleston</title>,
the committee-ridden squire of Thorn, looks like a
careful portrait from life, and
probably somebody also sat
for that faithful soul, <title>Crane</title>,
the butler. A book to be commended.
Its defects are the
defects of exuberance, the sort
one only begins to notice after
one has said, "Hello! this is
pretty good!"</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>
                        <title>The Greater Glory</title> (<name rend="sc">Hodder
and Stoughton</name>) is a collection
of very short sketches concerned
with the War. They
are a little unequal, some being
better than others, and others
(naturally) being worse than
some. They all reveal their
author, Miss <name rend="sc">Evelyn Orchard</name>,
as possessed of a pleasantly
unforced style, and perhaps
rather more ease than imagination. One of them, my own
favourite, the story of a parson who enlisted, is conspicuous
as containing so admirable a recruiting speech that I can
only hope it is transcribed from life.  Having said so
much, perhaps I may be forgiven by Miss <name rend="sc">Orchard</name> if I
add that I would rather have read her up upon some lighter
theme. Her tuneful pipe contains some very pleasant
notes, both of sentiment and humour, but is altogether too
thin for variations upon so tremendous a motive as she has
chosen. I express, of course, only my personal feeling; but
I am certain that unless a book can rise to the magnitude
of the War it had best leave it alone. Still it may well be
that others will find interest, and even consolation, in these
little papers. They have at least the charm of simplicity,
and are obviously the products of a gentle and sympathetic
nature. Thus, Miss <name rend="sc">Orchard</name> can still see the pathos of
the German private. Well, well.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/160.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e2177" type="div3">
                    <head>A PIOUS HOPE.</head>
                    <p>[Suggested by an interview between M. <hi>Sazonoff</hi> and Mr. <name rend="sc">Harold
Begbie</name> in <title>The Daily Chronicle</title>.]</p>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>The Russian statesman, <name rend="sc">Harold Begbie</name> thinks,</l>
                            <l>Is a good egg and not a subtle Sphinx;</l>
                            <l>Some day perhaps he will a better egg be</l>
                            <l>And tell us frankly what he thought of <name rend="sc">Begbie</name>.</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>