<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Punch, or the London Charivari, Vol. 150, January 19, 1916</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <idno type="gutenberg">22610</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>This text is freely available for re-use under US and UK law, consult
                            your local legal restrictions if elsewhere.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This text is a TEI version of a Project Gutenberg text originally located at
                            <ptr target="http://www.gutenberg.org/dirs//////"/>. As per their license agreement we have removed
                        all references to the project's trademark, however have included this
                        pointer to the original in case you want the plain text, or their XHTML
                        version. </p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2008-06-27T16:12:57.166+01:00"/>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:id="d1e44" type="div2">
                <head>CHARIVARIA.</head>
                <p>In a description of Lord <name rend="sc">Kitchener's</name>
home at Broome Park we read that
on the way there one passes a kind of
crater known by the rustics as "Old
England's Hole." And a little farther
on you come to the man who got Old
England out of it.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A German professor advocates the
appointment of State matrimonial
agents. Elderly and experienced ladies
and gentlemen should be employed to
bring young people together, and "unostentatiously
to give them practical
counsel, conveying their remarks tactfully,
and in such a way as not to
awaken the spirit of contradiction
found in youthful minds;"
paying due regard, moreover,
to theories of eugenics and
heredity. The Winged Boy
disguised as an antique German
professor makes an attractive picture.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Some anxiety was caused in
America by the news that the
<name rend="sc">Ford</name> Peace party was to meet
in the Zoo at the Hague. But
they have all emerged safely.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The Governor of South Carolina,
who was one of the members
of this heroic mission,
left the Hague in a great hurry
and returned to America before
the rest of the delegates. Much
curiosity is expressed as to what
the Governor of North Carolina
will have to say to him on this
occasion.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>In spite of the Government's
official discouragement of any
further rise in wages a demand for an
increase of no less than 33-1/3 per cent,
has been made by the "knockers-up"
in the Manchester district. For going
round in the chill hours of the morning
and wakening the workers, these blood-suckers
(chiefly old men and cripples)
receive at present the princely remuneration
of threepence per head per
week; and they have now the effrontery
to ask for fourpence.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The German Government has decided
to raise the charge for telegrams.
<name rend="sc">Wolff's</name> Bureau has instructed its correspondents
that in order to meet this
new impost the percentage of truth
in its despatches must be still further
diminished.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Before the opening of the Luxemburg
Parliament two members of the Opposition
threw the chairs belonging to
Ministers out of the window. It is
feared that something of the kind may
be attempted at Westminster, since
several Members have been observed to
cast longing eyes upon the Treasury
Bench.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>With a view to increasing the food-supply
the German Government have
extended the time for shooting hares
from January 16th to February 1st,
and for pheasants from February 1st
to March 1st. The dachshund season,
we understand, will be continued for
the duration of the War.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Count <name rend="sc">Kospoth</name>, a member of the
Prussian Upper House, in the course
of an energetic plea for economy, remarks
that "at one's country-seat one
can very well do without a motor-car,
and even with two to four horses in
stables instead of six or eight."
This was read with great satisfaction
by the Berlin <title>Hausfrau</title> on a meatless
day when the bread-card was exhausted.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>The House of Commons was quite
relieved when Sir <name rend="sc">George Reid</name> took
his seat. There had been some fears
that he would take two.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A young woman who mistook Vine-street
police station for a tavern, and
was fined ten shillings for drunkenness,
is reported to have expressed the
opinion that there is room for improvement
in the nomenclature of our public
edifices.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"My grave doubt," writes a Conscientious
Objector regarding his fellows, "is
whether there is any reasonable chance
that most of them will be able to convince
a tribunal that their conscientious
objection is real." It may comfort him
to know that his doubt is very widely
shared.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"<name rend="sc">Dear Mr. Punch</name>," writes a soldier
at the Front who has been reading the
Parliamentary reports,—"Do you think
an officer out here who developed
'conscientious objections' might get
a week's leave?"</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>In the course of a debate in the
Reichstag on the German Press Bureau
it was revealed that the Censor had
struck out quotations from <name rend="sc">Goethe</name> as
being dangerous to the State.
Our man who tinkered with
<name rend="sc">Kipling</name> is wonderfully bucked
by this intelligence.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Bread is the staff of life, and,
in the view of certain officers
in the trenches, whose opinions
we cannot of course guarantee,
the life of the Staff is one long
loaf.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Extracted from the report of
an enthusiastic company commander
after a brisk action
with some tribesmen on the
Indian Frontier: "The men
were behaving exactly as if
on ceremonial parade. They
laughed and talked the whole
time...." We seem to recognise
that parade.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e160" type="div3">
                    <head>Extract from letter from an Unconscientious Slacker.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/041.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"We have from the first declared
that should the voluntary system fail
to supply the men needed to win the
war and who could be spared from
civil war we would accept and support it."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Manchester Guardian.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Unfortunately, to judge by the proceedings
at the Labour Conference, the
claims of civil war are very heavy.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>This paragraph from "Town Topics"
in <title>The Liverpool Echo</title>—</p>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"We know that many of our men—especially
the single ones, judging by the Derby
figures—are sheltering behind skirts"—
</p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>helps to explain this one:—</p>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Several lady tram-conductors in the city
declare they are denied the common courtesies
far more by women passengers of the female
gender than by men."
</p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>The insistence upon the sex of the uncivil
females is necessary to distinguish
them from the male civilians.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"<name rend="sc">Furnished</name> house (small) wanted in Edinburgh;
with ballroom, h. &amp; c."—<title>Scotsman.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Hot for the chaperons and cold for the
dancers.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page42" n="pg 42"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e235" type="div2">
                <head>TO THE PRO-SHIRKERS.</head>
                <quote type="note">[Thirty-nine Members voted against the Second Reading of the
Military Service Bill.]</quote>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l rend="i10">     You that in civilian lobbies,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">          While the battle-thunder rolls,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">     Hug your little party hobbies,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">        So to save your little souls,</l>
                        <l>Treating England's deadly peril like a topic for the polls;</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l rend="i10">     Half of you—the record's written—</l>
                        <l rend="i10">        Lately strode to Downing Street</l>
                        <l rend="i10">     And for love of Little Britain</l>
                        <l rend="i10">        Wallowed at the <name rend="sc">Premier</name>'s feet,</l>
                        <l>Urging him to check the wanton waste of our superfluous Fleet.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l rend="i10">     Had your passionate prayer been granted</l>
                        <l rend="i10">        And the <name rend="sc">Kaiser</name> got his way,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">     Teuton crushers might be planted</l>
                        <l rend="i10">        On our hollow tums to-day,</l>
                        <l>And a grateful foe be asking what you want for traitors' pay.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l rend="i10">     Disappointed with the Navy,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">        You in turn were keen about</l>
                        <l rend="i10">     Putting Thomas in the gravy,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">        Leaving Thomas up the spout,</l>
                        <l>Lest if adequately aided he should wipe the strafers out.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l rend="i10">     Well, our memories may be rotten,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">        Yet they'll stick to you all right;</l>
                        <l rend="i10">     Not so soon shall be forgotten</l>
                        <l rend="i10">        Those whose hearts were fixed more tight</l>
                        <l>On the salvage of a fetish than the winning of the fight.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l rend="i10">     When the Bosches bite the gutter</l>
                        <l rend="i10">        And we let our tongues go loose,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">     Franker words I hope to utter</l>
                        <l rend="i10">        In the way of free abuse,</l>
                        <l>But at present I am badly hampered by the party truce.</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <p>O. S.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e365" type="div2">
                <head>WHITTLING THEM DOWN.</head>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">Dear Mr. Punch</name>,—I know you must be longing to have
my analysis of the Derby figures. I hasten to comply, for
I may say that I have never, since the War began, had
finer scope for my individual talents. Never have I had—not
even in the great Copper Controversy—a bunch of
figures of which it may more truly be said that they are
not what they seem, that there is more in them than meets
the eye, and that they contain wheels within wheels.
And first of all, Sir, I hope you will allow me to explain
where I am in this matter; everybody's doing it; and you
will then see at once the moral grandeur of my attitude.
I am a convinced believer in the Voluntary System, always
have been—on principle. But I am willing to sacrifice
even that for victory. If it can be shown that by compulsion
<title>one single man</title> can be added to our forces who would
not have volunteered (even if he had been scientifically
bullied), I will be willing to adopt conscription. But, Sir,
it cannot be shown.</p>
                <p>The crux of the situation admittedly lies with the figures
of the Single Men. (In case of misapprehension I should
make it clear that when I spoke above of "one single man"
I did not mean one unmarried man, but one sole man).
We have to begin our attack upon this figure of 651,160
unstarred single men unaccounted for. It seems a good
many. But wait a bit. We shall now proceed to concentrate
a powerful succession of deductions. It only needs a
fearless and patriotic ingenuity.</p>
                <p>Let us not disregard obvious facts. From this number
we must subtract—</p>
                <p>(1) Ministers of religion: 5 per cent.<lb/>
(2) Mercantile Marine:      5 "<lb/>
(3) Medically unfit:          40 "<lb/>
(4) Criminals:                    1-3/4 "<lb/>
(5) Badged:                     10 "<lb/>
(6) Indispensables:           10 "
</p>
                <p>Total 71-3/4 per cent. You see we are already getting on.
But before going any further we had better consolidate the
ground already won by making certain additions, in case
any one man has been counted twice. These are—</p>
                <p>
(1) Ministers of religion who are also medically unfit.<lb/>
(2) Criminals in the mercantile marine.<lb/>
(3) Ministers of religion in the mercantile marine.<lb/>
(4) Criminals who are medically unfit.<lb/>
(5) Indispensable criminals.<lb/>
(6) Badged criminal ministers of religion.
</p>
                <p>These categories taken together may be put at 7-1/4 per
cent. of our 71-3/4 per cent., and must be deducted from the
deductions. There are also the blind, halt and maimed,
deaf, dumb and inebriate, but I am willing to throw all
of them in so as to be on the safe side.</p>
                <p>So far we have to deduct, then, some 66-1/2 per cent. from
our total. We must do better than that if we are to get on
the right side of negligibility. So now we come to examine
the canvass. A good many men were not canvassed, or at
least misunderstood the canvasser. I know of one man
in my constituency (unstarred, unbadged, fit, single and
of army age) who thought the fellow had come to collect
for Foreign Missions, to which he has a conscientious
objection.</p>
                <p>Along with these I propose to deduct the great class of
what I shall call the Self-centred. These are they who
not only were never canvassed, but didn't even so much as
hear about it, who had probably given up newspapers as a
war economy and were living quiet virtuous lives in out-of-the-way
places. Add to them removals and conscientious
objectors (<hi rend="it">less</hi> allowance for conscientious removals) and
we have a total not short of 27-1/2 per cent.</p>
                <p>Then again, as the supply of recruits becomes exhausted,
it must always be remembered that we are dealing with a
residuum. That is to say, those that remain are always
growing more conscientious, more criminal, more unfit,
more mercantile and so on. However, I count nothing for
that, for I haven't much of my total left to dispose of, and
I have still to deal with spoiled cards.</p>
                <p>Everyone who has assisted at a contested election knows
very well that many mistakes occur. I propose to allow 3
per cent. for illegible cards which prevented the canvasser
from tracking his prey, 4 per cent. for those who failed to
find the recruiting office owing to misdirection, but will be
sure to find it before long, and 1/2 per cent. for sundries, such
as men who were temporarily confined to the house.</p>
                <p>Our final result is thoroughly satisfactory, and one that
must give Compulsionists some food for thought, for however
much they may wish to introduce the principle they
cannot desire to reduce our forces in the field in the middle
of a great war. In a word, we must deduct 101-1/2 per
cent. from 651,160. That gives us an adverse balance
of 9,767. This means that, if the present Bill is to go
through and compulsion is definitely adopted, nearly half a
division of our present army must be disbanded forthwith.
It is just as well that we should see clearly what we are
heading for.</p>
                <p>It has given me great pleasure to have the opportunity
of clearing up this vexed question.</p>
                <p>I am,  Yours as usual,</p>
                <p rend="sc">
            Statistician Bis.
         </p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page43" n="pg 43"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/043a.png"/>
                    <head>For neutrals</head>
                </figure>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/043b.png"/>
                    <head>For natives</head>
                </figure>
                <p>.............</p>
                <pb xml:id="page45" n="pg 45"/>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e473" type="div3">
                    <head>THE IRREPRESSIBLES.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/045.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e484" type="div2">
                <head>EVEN.</head>
                <quote type="note">
                    <p>
["Even the food of the men was wholesome
and abundant."—<title>Report</title> of a German Correspondent
who visited the High Canal
Fleet.]
</p>
                </quote>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Sing ho! for the Fleet in the Kiel Canal.</l>
                        <l>Where every man is the <name rend="sc">Kaiser</name>'s pal,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">And lives upon beer and bread;</l>
                        <l>And they all have food, so help them <name rend="sc">Bill</name>!</l>
                        <l>For every officer gets his fill</l>
                        <l rend="i2">And even the men are fed.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>His beard as long as his hair is short,</l>
                        <l>
                            <name rend="sc">Von Tirpitz</name> says with a mighty snort,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">"We've money and men and boats;</l>
                        <l>We're here to-day and we're here to-morrow;</l>
                        <l>Pass up the beer and drink death to sorrow;</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Why, even our Navy floats!</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>"Behind the locks of our snug retreat</l>
                        <l>We hurl defiance at <name rend="sc">Jellicoe's</name> Fleet</l>
                        <l rend="i2">From Rosyth down to Dover!</l>
                        <l>We look across at the wet, wet sea</l>
                        <l>And we drink our beer till even we</l>
                        <l rend="i2">Are almost half-seas over!</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>"Our men can eat, and they even drink;</l>
                        <l>They walk and talk, and they almost think;</l>
                        <l rend="i2">They can turn to the left and right;</l>
                        <l>And when we strike a blow in the back,</l>
                        <l>Or sink a liner or fishing-smack,</l>
                        <l rend="i2">By Odin, they even fight!"</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Two headlines that appeared side by
side in the same issue of an Evening
Paper:—</p>
                <p>"WOMAN WILL PROBABLY BE TRIED
IN CAMERA.<lb/>
GERMAN FEARS FOR LENS."</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"'Most of the world's real literature was
written by poor authors in their garrets.'</p>
                    <p>'Quite so. Homer, for example, wrote in
the Attic.'"—<title>Evening Paper.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>Did he now? And we were always
taught that he wrote (or, rather, sang)
in the Ionic.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>From an article on the Clyde disputes:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"Contrary to the instructions of the
Munitions Ministry, peace-prices are sometimes
reduced, with resulting friction."</p>
                    <p>
                        <title>Daily News.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>We are glad to learn that the Scotch
workmen do not belong to the peace-at-any-price
brigade.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e651" type="div2">
                <head>THE CONQUEST.</head>
                <p>Every January so long as I can
remember it has been difficult; but
this year more so than ever. I cannot
say why, except that last year was
peculiarly eventful and momentous.</p>
                <p>The odd thing is that one begins so
well. For the first day, at any rate,
one can do it quite easily; but it is
after then that one has to be vigilant;
and however vigilant one is there are
off-guard moments when the fatal slip
occurs.</p>
                <p>Nor will any mechanical device
assist you, for nothing can successfully
defeat the wandering of the mind.
Continuous concentration is an impossibility;
there is nothing for it but
habit—a new habit that shall be as
strong as the old—or the total cessation
of all correspondence and (O that
'twere possible!) all making out of
cheques.</p>
                <p>Still conquest comes sooner or later,
and I have reached that point in my
own struggle. I have at last finally
got over the tendency to write 1915.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"As a result of the Labour Conference at
Westminster yesterday, a resolution was sunk
on Lake Tanganyika."—<title>Western Daily Press.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>The best place for it.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page46" n="pg 46"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e686" type="div2">
                <head>A NEW THEATRICAL VENTURE.</head>
                <p>A friend of mine has started as
manager of his first theatre these
holidays. It may seem to you an unpropitious
moment for such a beginning,
but in many ways this special theatre
is exceptionally well guaranteed against
failure. The proprietor was kind enough
to invite my presence at his opening
performance. As a matter of fact I
had myself put up the money for it.</p>
                <p>Naturally I was anxious for the thing
to be a success. The theatre stands
on what you could truthfully call a
commanding situation at one
end of the schoolroom table.
It is an elegant renaissance
edifice of wood and cardboard,
with a seating accommodation
only limited by the
dimensions of the schoolroom
itself, and varying with the
age of the audience. The
lighting effects are provided
in theory by a row of oil
foot-lamps, so powerful as to
be certain, if kindled, to consume
the entire building; in
practice, therefore, by a number
of candle-ends, stuck in
the wings on their own
grease. These not only furnish
illumination, but, when
extinguished (as they constantly
are by falling scenery)
produce a penetrating aroma
which is specially dear to the
managerial nostrils.</p>
                <p>The manager, to whom I
have already had the pleasure
of introducing you, is Peter.
I have been impatiently waiting
for the moment of Peter's
first theatre, these nine years.
Like marbles or <title>Treasure
Island</title>, it is at once a landmark
and a milestone in the
present-giving career of an
uncle. So I had devoted some considerable
care to its selection.</p>
                <p>In one respect Peter's theatre reminds
me of the old Court in the days
of the <name rend="sc">Vedrenne-Barker</name> repertory.
You recall how one used to see the
same people at every performance, a
permanent nucleus of spectators that
never varied? The difference is that
Peter's permanent nucleus are neither
so individually agreeable nor in any
true sense enthusiasts of the drama.
Indeed, being painted on the proscenium,
with their backs to the stage,
the effect they produce is one of studied
indifference. Nay more, a horrible suspicion
about them refused to be banished
from my thoughts; it was based partly
upon the costumes of the ladies, partly
on the undeniably Teutonic suggestion
in the gentlemen's uniforms. However,
I said nothing about this to Peter.</p>
                <p>Despite the presence of these unpleasing
persons, the opening performance
must be pronounced a real success.
Perhaps more as a spectacle than anything
else. Scenically the show was
a triumph; the memory of the Forest
Glade especially will remain with me
for weeks by reason of the stiff neck
I got from contorting myself under
Peter's guidance to the proper angle
for its appreciation. But histrionically
it must be confessed that things
dragged a little. Perhaps this was
due to a certain severity, not to say
baldness, in the dialogue as spoken.
Not having read the script, I have a
feeling that it might be unfair to judge
the unknown author by the lines as
rendered by Peter, who was often pre-occupied
with other anxieties. As, for
example, the scene in the Baronial
Castle between its noble but unscrupulous
proprietor and a character introduced
by Peter with the simple notice:
"This is a murderer coming on now."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Baron.</title> Oh, are you a murderer?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Murderer.</title> Yes.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Bar.</title> Oh, well, you've got to murder
the Princess.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Murd.</title> All right.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Bar.</title> That's all of that scene.</p>
                <p>Crisp, of course, and to the point;
but I feel sure that there must have
been more in the interview as originally
written.</p>
                <p>Perhaps, again, the cast was to blame
for whatever may have been disappointing
in the performance. Individually
they were a fine company, passionate
and wiry of gesture, and full of energy.
Indeed their chief fault sprang from an
incapacity to remain motionless in
repose. This led to a notable lack of
balance. However sensational it may
be for the exit of every character to
bring down the house, its effect is
unfortunately to retard the action of
the piece.</p>
                <p>Personally I consider that
the women were the worst
offenders. Take the heroine,
for example. Lovely she may
have been, though in a style
more appreciated by the late
<name rend="sc">George Cruikshank</name> than by
myself; but looks are not
everything. Art simply didn't
exist for her. Revue might
have been her real line; or,
better still, a strong-woman
turn on the Halls. There
was the episode, for instance,
where, having to prostrate
herself before the Baron, she
insisted upon a backward exit
(with the usual result) and
then made an acrobatic re-entrance
on her knees.</p>
                <p>Tolerant as he was, even
Peter began at last to grow
impatient at the vagaries of
his company. Finally, when
the Executioner (a mere
walker-on of no importance
whatever) had twice brought
ridicule upon the ultimate
solemnities of the law by
his introduction of comic
dives off the scaffold, the
manager rang down the curtain.
Not before it was time.</p>
                <p>"They're lovely to look
at," he observed, surveying the supine
cast, "but awfully difficult to do anything
with."</p>
                <p>"Peter," I answered gratefully, "as
an estimate of the theatrical profession
your last remark could hardly be improved
upon."</p>
                <p>Of course he didn't understand; but,
being dramatist as well as uncle, I
enjoyed saying it.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/046.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"February 3.—A total eclipse of the sun,
partly visible at Greenwich as a partial eclipse.
Eclipse begins to be visible at Greenwich at
4.31 <name rend="sc">P. M.</name>; ends after the sun has set."</p>
                    <p>"February 3.—A partial eclipse of the
moon, partly visible at Greenwich. Begins
at 4.31 <name rend="sc">P. M.</name>"—<title>Churchman's Almanack.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>This double obscuration will make
navigation very difficult for sky-pilots.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page47" n="pg 47"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e803" type="div2">
                <head>BADGES.</head>
                <p>My companion had the habit of
muttering to himself and I was relieved
when he leant over and spoke to
me. He was a dry little man of middle
age, with a nervous kindly face and
eyes that twinkled with the voluntary
spirit. I had seen him on summer
evenings clipping his hedge and pruning
his roses, for we lived nearly opposite
to each other. Suddenly he emerged
from his newspaper and said in a quick
determined way, "What this country
wants, Sir, is more buttonholes. The
best suits have only two buttonholes;
that is to say, only two that are
superfluous, the rest are all needed by
buttons. It's a scandal, Sir!"</p>
                <p>"Isn't there one at the bottom of
the waistcoat?" I asked.</p>
                <p>"Quite useless," he said with much
energy, though smiling very kindly.
"Quite useless for the purpose. The
matter," he added, "would not be so
urgent if we had more sleeves. Worse
even than the dearth of buttonholes is
the lack of eligible sleeves. In peace
time two sleeves may have been sufficient;
to-day ... Well, you can sympathise."
He looked (still smiling) at
the khaki armlet that bound my arm
and the Special Constable's badge that
nestled in my overcoat.</p>
                <p>He had the shy decisiveness of a man
who seldom spoke his mind. If necessary
I would have wrested his name
from him and pretended a relationship
with his wife. But he needed no
encouragement.</p>
                <p>"At the beginning, when one was
just a special constable, it didn't matter
so much. I wore my badge and my
armlet when I was on duty and sometimes
when I was not. Even when I
joined our Volunteer Corps I was not
seriously embarrassed. After all, one
could alternate the badges and the
armlets and, at a pinch, wear them all
together. Then I became an unskilled
munition worker, which meant three
badges and two armlets. At first I
wore two on my overcoat and three
inside. Then I would give some of
them a rest, generally to find that I was
wearing the wrong ones on the wrong
occasions. Altogether it was very confusing."</p>
                <p>"So far," I said with some sympathy,
"I can follow you. I am myself
an unskilled War Office clerk; but
you have forgotten Lord <name rend="sc">Derby's</name>
armlet, which at the moment has the
place of honour with me."</p>
                <p>"No," he said, "I have that too.
And I have another badge. I earned
it on New Year's Day."</p>
                <p>He took off his spectacles and rubbed
them mechanically.  It gave him a
very detached appearance and he spoke
gently, without malice.</p>
                <p>"I have an aunt," he said, "by self-election,
a most worthy woman, who
was my mother's cousin. It came to
her ears that I had become a teetotaler
for the duration of the war. It
appears that there is a badge for temporary
teetotalers. She brought me
one. She begged me with tears in her
eyes to wear it. I remonstrated. I
pointed out that if every public and
private virtue is to be symbolised in this
fashion, people with few vices and a
willing heart would soon be perpetually
in fancy-dress."</p>
                <p>"And what happened?" I asked.</p>
                <p>"I wavered for a time and then
happily I found a way out. A few days
ago it occurred to me that there must
be other means, as yet untried, of advertising
one's patriotism. I saw a notice
in a restaurant I sometimes go to, 'No
Germans or Austrians Employed Here.'
'Happy proprietor,' I said, 'who can
so trumpet his honesty without increasing
either his badges or his armlets!'
The fact is that it set me thinking.
Eventually I hit on a plan. It was
very disappointing to my aunt, but it
answers wonderfully."</p>
                <p>"May I ask?" I said; "it might be
useful."</p>
                <p>"Oh, certainly, certainly. We have
bought a little enamelled plate and had
it fixed to our gate. You may have
noticed it. It has the words, 'No
Bottles.'"</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e853" type="div3">
                    <head>THE MASCOT.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/047.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page48" n="pg 48"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e866" type="div2">
                <head>THE WATCH DOGS.</head>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">My dear Charles</name>,—You didn't catch
sight of any mention of me in despatches,
did you? I have been rather too busy
myself to read the list properly, but I
did just have time to cast a casual eye
over the "H's," and I didn't notice the
name of "Henry" standing out in
heavy-leaded capitals. It must be an inadvertence,
of course. They must have
said something about me, as, for instance:
"Especially to be remarked is
the noble altruism of Lieut. Henry,
who on more than one march has been
observed to take his pack, containing
all his worldly goods, off his back and
to hand it without ostentation to some
lucky driver of a limber, saying, 'Take
it, my lad; your need is greater than
mine.'" Or again, referring to my
later career: "The pen is mightier
than the sword, but Lieut. Henry's indelible
pencil, when engaged on official
correspondence, is mightier than both."
Or at least, at the very beginning of
things, I'm quite sure the Mentioner
devoted a passing phrase to me: "By
the way, I have just received a consignment
described on the Movement Order
as 'Officer, one, Henry, Lieut.' Speaking
frankly as between ourselves, what is
it exactly? In any case I would gladly
exchange for a dozen tins of bully beef."</p>
                <p>Talking of despatches, I see that our
old friend the Regimental Anarchist has
not escaped notice. I never thought
he would, for a less unnoticeable man I
don't remember meeting. He is one of
those big untidy fellows, very nice for
purposes of war and all that, whom not
the cleverest adjutant could manage to
conceal on a ceremonial parade. His
service equipment alone was notorious
in the division. While we were still in
England he and I used to share a
billet. Every night the last thing I
saw before going to sleep was the
Anarchist trying on a new piece of
personal furniture. He had at least a
hundred aunts, and each of them had
at least a hundred bright ideas; besides
which few days went by but he paid a
generous visit to the military outfitter.
Never in my life shall I forget the
sight of him during our last moments
at home. While others were stuffing
into themselves the last good meal
they expected to taste for three years or
the duration, he was putting on patent
waterproof after patent waterproof. He
stepped forth at last, sweating at every
pore, and it wasn't raining at the time
and didn't look like raining till next
winter. The 38-lb. limit prevented his
putting more than four coats into his
valise, and his method of packing
didn't economise space. If there had
been any limit, however generous, to
the amount of room an officer may
occupy in the column of route we'd
have had to go abroad without our
Anarchist, and a much quieter and
more respectable life we'd have had
that way.</p>
                <p>Even in our earliest days in B.E.F.,
when we were well behind the firing
line, he started playing with fire.
Thinking that we shared his low tastes
he would gather us round him and
lecture us on the black arts.—"This
little fellow," he would say, fetching an
infernal machine out of his pocket—"this
little fellow is as safe as houses
provided he has no detonator in his
little head. But we will just make
sure." A flutter of excitement would
pass round the audience as he started
unscrewing the top to make sure. "Of
course," he'd continue, finding the
screw a bit stiff and getting absorbed
in his toy—"of course, if there <hi rend="it">should</hi>
happen to be a detonator inside, you
have only to tickle it and almost
anything may happen." While he'd
be struggling with the screw, the front
row of the audience would be shifting
its ground to give the back rows a
better view. "You can't be too careful,"
he'd say, passing it lightly from
one hand to the other in order to search
for his well-known clasp-knife, "for
if you're not careful," he'd explain,
tucking the bomb under his arm so
as to have both hands free to open
the knife—"if you're not careful,"
he'd say, suddenly letting go the knife
in order to catch the bomb as it slid
from his precarious hold—"if you're
not very careful" (getting to real business
with the murderous blade), "very—very—careful...."
But none of us
were ever near enough by that time
to hear what would happen if we
weren't (or even if he wasn't).</p>
                <p>And then those strange nights in the
trenches, when he and I used to be on
duty together! I would be waiting in
our luxurious, brightly-lit gin-palace of
a dug-out for him to join me at our
midnight lunch. He'd come in at last,
clad in his fleece lining, the only survivor
of his extensive collection of
overcoats, its absence of collar giving
him a peculiarly clerical look. He'd
sit down to his cocoa, but hardly be
started on the day before yesterday's
newspaper (just arrived with the
rations) before the private bombardment
would begin. I would spring to
attention; he would go on reading.
"Hush!" I'd say. (Why "Hush!"
I don't know.) "What's all that
for?" "Me," he'd say, turning to
the personal column. And then I'd
know that, seizing the opportunity of
being unobserved, he'd been out for
nocturnal stroll with a handful of
bombs, seeking a little innocent pleasure.
The gentlemen opposite, not
being cricketers themselves or knowing
anything about the slow bowler, had,
as usual, mistaken him for a trench
mortar and were making a belated reply.</p>
                <p>Only his servant accompanied him
on these jaunts. He was a nice quiet
villain, whose lust for adventure had,
I always imagine, been long ago satisfied
by a dozen or so gentle burglaries
in his civilian past. He didn't want
to kill people; his job in life was to
keep his master alive and well fed.
So when the latter went out bombing
he thought he might as well go out
with him, and occupy himself picking
turnips for to-morrow's stew.</p>
                <p>When the Anarchist wasn't distributing
bombs he was collecting
bullets. Being untidy by nature, he
didn't particularly care where they hit
him, provided they didn't damage his
pipe. That was all he cared about, his
lyddite and his tobacco. I often wonder
how it was he didn't get the two habits
of his life mixed up—fill a pipe with
H.E., light it and finish off that way.
But he didn't; he has just gone on
collecting lead, letting it accumulate
about his person until it got too heavy
to be convenient and then resorting to
the nearest hospital to have it removed.
I hear he's there now, the result, I
gather, of a bit of a show. It was his
servant who was walking about that
unhealthy field at that imprudent time
and found him. One would like to
paint a romantic picture of the meeting,
but I doubt if there was much
romance about it. I am quite sure all
the Anarchist cared about was his
tobacco pouch and all the servant was
interested in was the further collection
of vegetables, just in case.</p>
                <p>I can see our Anarchist, lying in his
little white bed in the hospital, surrounded
by his sevenpenny racing
novels (with or without covers), his
tins of navy-cut (some empty, some
full), his fleece lining, his compass,
his socks, his field-glasses, his ties,
his revolver and his last month's
letters (some opened, some not), all
jumbled happily together, with his
ragged old shaving-brush reigning
proudly in the midst. I doubt if he
knows he's been "mentioned," for one
could never get him to take interest in
any news which wasn't "sporting";
possibly he is made suspicious by the
uncomfortable presence of unopened
telegrams in all corners of his bed.
But one thing I do hope, and that is
that this bed is, at any rate, not
strewn, inside and out, with unexploded
hand-grenades.</p>
                <p>Yours ever, <name rend="sc">Henry</name>.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page49" n="pg 49"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e908" type="div3">
                    <head>WARFARE AT THE BARBER'S.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/049a.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/049b.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <p>....................</p>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/049c.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/049d.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <p>....................</p>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/049e.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/049f.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <p>....................</p>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/049g.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/049h.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <p>....................</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page50" n="pg 50"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/050.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e977" type="div2">
                <head>PROVINCIAL PATRIOTS.</head>
                <p>
                    <title>From Jim Figgis, Whitty Bridge, to
George Roberts, South Farm, Sudborough.</title>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <title>Dec. 5th.</title> 1915.</p>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">Dear George</name>,—I hear the remount
officer is coming round your part. I
have a compact little bay horse, just
the sort for the Army. We must all
do our bit now, so here's our chance.
The Vet says the horse has laminitis in
his off fore foot, but it's all my eye.
Anyhow he's the useful sort they require
for the Army. They wouldn't
look at me if I offered him, but you
can get round them. Give me fifty
quid and I'll send him over.</p>
                <p>Your friend, <name rend="sc">J. Figgis</name>.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>From George Roberts to Jim Figgis.</title>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <title>Dec. 7th,</title> 1915.</p>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">Dear Jim</name>,—Yours to hand. No one
can say that you're not a good patriot,
and I won't be No. 2. But fifty quid
for that little horse—not me. Say
thirty and he's mine, sound or unsound.</p>
                <p>Yours, <name rend="sc">G. Roberts</name>.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>George Roberts to the Hon. Mordaunt
Fopstone, White Lion Hotel, Sudborough.</title>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <title>Dec. 10th,</title> 1915.</p>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">Dear Sir</name>,—Hearing you are looking
out for horses for the Army I write to
say I have one or two which I shall be
pleased to place at your disposal and
at a very reasonable price, as in these
times we must all give up something
for the country. I shall be pleased to
see you at any time convenient, except
Tuesday, when I have to be at our local
Agricultural Show.</p>
                <p>Yours to command,</p>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">G. Roberts</name>.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>From the Hon. Mordaunt Fopstone to
George Roberts.</title>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <title>Dec. 11th,</title> 1915.</p>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">Dear Sir</name>,—Thank you for your
letter. It is very satisfactory to find
local people of your position anxious
to help. I will call at your farm on
Friday next and see the horses you
refer to. With thanks,</p>
                <p>Yours  truly, <name rend="sc"> M. Fopstone</name>.</p>
                <p>P.S.—I have been warned against a
man named Figgis. Do you know
him?</p>
                <p>
                    <title>From George Roberts to the
Hon. Mordaunt Fopstone.</title>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <title>Dec. 13th,</title> 1915.</p>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">Dear Sir</name>,—Friday will suit me very
well for your call, at any time you
please. You are quite right to avoid
Figgis; he is one of the small horse-dealing
class who are a discredit to our
country districts. Any further information
is at your service.</p>
                <p>Yours to command, <name rend="sc">G. Roberts</name>.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>From the Hon. Mordaunt Fopstone
to George Roberts.</title>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <title>Dec. 21st</title>, 1915.</p>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">Dear Mr. Roberts</name>,—I have now
pleasure in enclosing cheque for £65
for bay horse. As stated to you when
I called at South Farm, I was not in
a position to go beyond £60 without
further authorisation; this I have
now obtained. Thanking you for the
patriotic spirit you have shown in this
little business,</p>
                <p>Yours truly, <name rend="sc">M. Fopstone</name>.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>From the Adjutant, Royal Beetshire
Hussars, Tickful Camp, to Messrs.
Davison Bros., The Mart, Southtown.</title>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <title>Jan. 1st,</title> 1916.</p>
                <p>Please enter bay gelding, aged, sent
herewith, in your next sale without
reserve, as he is not sound and of no
use to Army.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Memo. from Davison Bros. to Adjutant.</title>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <title>Jan. 17th</title>, 1916.</p>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">Dear Sir</name>,—Herewith please find
cheque £5 4<title>s.</title> 3<title>d.</title> for bay gelding,
being amount realised for same, less
our commission and expenses.</p>
                <p>Yours faithfully, <name rend="sc">Davison Bros</name>.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>
                    <title>The Times</title> heads an article, "Unity
in the Air." It deals, however, with
the new Anglo-French Aviation Conference
and has nothing to do with the
latest <title>Peter Pan</title>.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page51" n="pg 51"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e1197" type="div3">
                    <head>GALLIPOLI-AND AFTER?</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/051.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page53" n="pg 53"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1210" type="div2">
                <head>ESSENCE OF PARLIAMENT.</head>
                <p>(<name rend="sc">Extracted from the Diary of Toby, M.P.</name>)</p>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/053.png"/>
                </figure>
                <p>
                    <title>House of Commons, Monday, January
10th</title>.—In spite of sharp rebuke
administered by <name rend="sc">Speaker</name> last week the
<name rend="sc">Pertinacious Pringle</name> to the fore again—to
be precise, to the <title>Forward</title>. This
the name of weekly paper that is published
in Clyde district, and has of late
emerged from obscurity by "deliberately
inciting workers," as <name rend="sc">Lloyd George</name>
said, "not to carry out Act of Parliament
passed in order to promote the output
of munitions." On motion for adjournment
<name rend="sc">Pringle</name> perceived opportunity
of attacking <name rend="sc">Minister of Munitions</name>.
Accused him of suppressing the sheet
because it had reported proceedings at
meetings attended by him in Glasgow,
at which his speech was interrupted by
noisy minority. This course of procedure
imitated by <name rend="sc">Pringle</name> when
<name rend="sc">Lloyd George</name>, replying, quoted passages
in the paper making violent attack
on the <name rend="sc">King</name> and systematic attempts
to stem flood of recruiting.</p>
                <p>"These things," said the <name rend="sc">Minister</name>, in
passage loudly cheered, "meant life or
death to our men in the field. They are
not suitable matters for Parliamentary
sport. We are dealing in tragedies. I
am doing my best to save the men at
the Front. I am entitled to be helped,
not to be harried."</p>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">Outhwaite</name>, coming to assistance of
<name rend="sc">Pringle</name>, otherwise prangling all forlorn,
jumped upon by Captain <name rend="sc">Campbell</name>.</p>
                <p>"If I had the Hon. Member in my
battalion at the Front," he said, "he
would be strung up by the thumbs before
he had been there half-an-hour."</p>
                <p>This scarcely Parliamentary; but it
passed the Chair, leaving the gallant
Captain, who modestly wears well-won
ribbon of D.S.O., time to adjure the
House to "get on with the War."</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Business done.</title>—In House barely half
full Motion carried calling upon Government
to enter into consultation with
the Overseas Dominions in order to
bring economic strength of Empire into
co-operation with our Allies in a policy
directed against the enemy.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Tuesday.</title>—Said with truth that a
speech in the House of Commons,
however forcible and eloquent, rarely
influences a vote. Some orators, however,
have gift of stirring the soul
to emotions that carry a man to actions
beyond range of conventionality. Such
an one is the Right Hon. <name rend="sc">Thomas
Lough</name>, commonly and affectionately
known through several Parliaments as
"Tommy." One of small faction of
Liberals who have not withdrawn
opposition to Military Service Bill.
Declaiming against it just now on
motion for Second Reading, he described
it as a sham.</p>
                <p>"It is not true," he said, "that young
unmarried men have held back. On
the contrary they have come forward
nobly and in great numbers."</p>
                <p>Vindication of a maligned class so
affected somebody seated in the Strangers'
Gallery that he loudly clapped his
hands. This a decided breach of
order. The Assyrians (in form of
Gallery attendants) came down upon
him like a wolf on the fold. Ordered
<pb xml:id="page54" n="pg 54"/>
him to withdraw. He explained that
he was so entirely at one with argument
of the Hon. Member for West
Islington that he preferred to remain
to listen to continuance of his speech.
Assyrians insistent on his immediate
departure. Martial spirit of young
unmarried man roused. Refused to
budge. Whereupon the Assyrians,
lifting him out of the seat, carried him
forth <title>vi et armis</title>—free translation, by
legs and arms.</p>
                <p>From his seat below the Gangway
Mr. <name rend="sc">Flavin</name> watched procedure with
wistful eyes. Remembered how towards
break of day dawning on an all-night
sitting held towards the close of
last century he also was carried forth
shoulder high, not by officers of the
House in nice white shirt fronts, with
glittering badges hung round their necks,
but by the common or street policeman
helmeted and belted. As he journeyed
he sang, "God save Ireland," his compatriots,
more or less attuned, joining
in the chorus.</p>
                <p>Recognition of historical incident
sharply marks contrast in attitude of
Irish Members then and now. Still
fighting for Home Rule they stopped
short of no outrage upon order, systematically
and successfully obstructing
public business. Military Service Bill
offers enticing opportunities for exercise
of old tactics. They might, if they
pleased, keep House sitting for weeks
fighting Bill in Committee line by line,
word by word, as was their custom of
an afternoon, and half-way through the
night, in days of old. Other times
other manners. Interposing early in
debate <name rend="sc">John Redmond</name> announced that
his party, having made their protest
against Bill in Division Lobby on
First Reading, would withdraw from
further opposition.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Business done</title>—Second Reading of
Military Service Bill moved.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Wednesday.</title>—Sir <name rend="sc">George Reid</name>, having
completed term of service as High
Commissioner of Australia, took his
seat as Member for St. George's, Hanover
Square. Carefully dismounting at
Bar from his native steed he was introduced
by <name rend="sc">Bonar Law</name>, Unionist Colonial
Secretary, and <name rend="sc">Harcourt</name>, Colonial
Secretary in late Liberal Government.
This concatenation of circumstance,
testifying to universal esteem and exceptional
personal popularity, unique
in Parliamentary records.</p>
                <p>New-comer will serve in double
capacity. Nominally Member for St.
George's, he will also be Member for
Australia, an innovation that will probably
have wider scope and formal
recognition when the Overseas Dominions
have completed their splendid
work of helping the Mother Country
to bring the War to triumphant conclusion.</p>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">George Reid's</name> career on a new stage
will be watched with keen interest in
his two antipodal homes. Since, six
years ago, he came to London, he has
acquired the reputation of being one of
the best after-dinner speakers of the
day. How will the qualities that ensure
success in that direction serve him at
Westminster? <name rend="sc">Macaulay</name> truly said,
"The House of Commons is the most
peculiar audience in the world. A place
in which I would not promise success
to any man."</p>
                <p>The <name rend="sc">Member for Sark</name> puts his
money (or such portion as is left
after paying War taxes) on the Member
for St. George's, Hanover Square-<hi rend="it">cum</hi>-Australia.</p>
                <p>Debate on Second Reading of Military
Service Bill resumed. Best thing
said during two days' talk was an incidental
remark of <name rend="sc">Birrell's</name>. Relating
<pb xml:id="page55" n="pg 55"/>
history of Bill in Cabinet he said he
had felt it his duty to say something
about Ireland.</p>
                <p>"What I said," he added, "is of
course known only to those of my
colleagues who were sitting round the
table and to such representatives of the
London Press as were sitting underneath
it."</p>
                <p>This hint explains mystery clouding
the fact that whilst the secrets of Cabinet
Councils are held to be inviolable
there are morning papers able habitually
to give detailed information of what
passes behind the locked and barred
doors.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Business done.</title>—Second Reading of
Military Service Bill carried by 431
votes against 39.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Thursday.</title>—After advancing three
minor Government Bills a stage, House
adjourned at 5.30.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/055.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e1402" type="div3">
                    <head>The Official Style.</head>
                    <p>Extract from an Indian Service
register:—</p>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Service Order 41 of 1914, dated 16-10-14.
He was appointed acting Forest Guard and
posted to Surumoni beat, in place of Chowdri
Zaicko, Forest Guard, who was devoured by a
tiger with effect from the forenoon of 16th
Oct. 1914."
</p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1418" type="div2">
                <head>AT THE BACK OF THE FRONT.</head>
                <p>Here where the world is quiet except
for the noise of the rain trickling into
one's valise through the nooks and
crannies of one's rustic apartment—here
where there is no peril from above and
no peril from in front, neither peril of
enfilade, here too—it is a Base I am
doing this sentence about—we have
our problems.</p>
                <p>To begin with there is the glorious
uncertainty of things. Some men are
here to-day and the far side of Wipers
to-morrow night. Others arrive from
England thirsting for all sorts of things
that no sane man ever wants to have anything
to do with, and are kept doing a
bomb course and a machine-gun course
on alternate days for eight months.
There is a tale told of one such who,
when he was finally sent to the trenches,
was returned as hopeless after three
days because he would do nothing
except sit beside a machine gun trying
to fill the belt with grenades. There is
no sadder story in the War.</p>
                <p>Now if I knew for certain that I was
going to be here eight months I could
marry and settle down. Or if I knew
for certain I was for Wipers to-morrow
night I could make a new will—not
that there's anything the matter with
the old one, but I met a man on leave
who put me up to some good tips in
will-making—and settle up. But as it
is part of our military system for junior
officers not to know anything I dare
not even have my letters forwarded.</p>
                <p>Anyhow, Bases are not what they
were in my young days. Of course there
were always parades; but you obviously
couldn't parade while you were
busy over some Alternative Necessary
Duty. Alternative Necessary Duties
were always my strongest suit. On
the evening of my arrival in camp I
would summon the Band Sergeant and
provide him with my programme of
work. On Monday he would please
arrange for a criminal in my detail.
On Tuesday I would use my influence
in the matter of obtaining clothing for
my detail. This would be a very
laborious task, involving three signatures
in ink or indelible pencil; but no
matter, to a good officer the comfort of
his men comes before everything. On
Wednesday I would pay my men.
Rotten job, paying out, but ensures
Generous Glow, and no expense unless
you lose the Acquittance Roll. On
<pb xml:id="page56" n="pg 56"/>
Thursday I would read Standing Orders
to the latest arrived draft; maybe they
had had this done to them once already,
but one cannot be too particular. A
private I know of who had only had
Standing Orders read to him once got
into awful trouble through carelessly
kicking a recalcitrant corporal on the
head. That just shows you. On Friday—but
I weary you, if that be
possible. Suffice it that the Base
went very well then.</p>
                <p>The trouble began, as usual, high
up. The G.O. Commanding something
most frightfully important inspected
one of our parades one morning and
found 7,528 other ranks under one
Second-Lieutenant. All might have
been well if the Second-Lieutenant had
not forgotten to fire the correct salute
of fourteen bombs (or whatever was the
correct salute). The G.O.C. investigated.
He searched the woods and
delved in the instructional trenches,
but never another officer came to light.
So he went home and, after a bad
lunch—we surmise—set himself to
abolish Alternative Necessary Duties
in a formal edict. No officer is to
absent himself from a parade except
by the express orders of an O.C. Base
Depôt.</p>
                <p>This happened several days ago, and
the ruling is probably obsolete by now,
but I am wondering how I shall break
the news to the G.O.C. if I should
happen to meet him on one of my
morning walks into town; and in my
heart of heart I know that one fine
morning I shall be cowardly, and wake
before nine, and attend my first parade
at army Base. Some zealous despatch
rider will dash hot-foot to the G.O.C.
with the news, and he will come and
rub his hands and chuckle and gloat.
It will be a Black Day.</p>
                <p>Here too there are minor points of
etiquette that vex one. Is it correct
for me, having bought half a kilo of
chocolates while waiting for a train, to
kill further time by eating them out of
a paper bag under the surveillance of
an A.S.C. sergeant? or ought I to offer
a few to the sergeant with some <title>jeu
d'esprit</title>—never coarse and never cruel—about
bully beef? Of such are the
complexities with which a Base harasses
the soul of an officer nurtured in the
genial simplicity of trench life.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>From an account of the Peace demonstration
in Berlin:—</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"The people simply turned up themselves,
and everyone was highly turned up themselves,
and everyone was highly pleased with
the result."—<title>Egyptian Mail.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>It seems to have been a complete
revolution.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1469" type="div2">
                <head>LITERARY LISPINGS.</head>
                <p>The "motive" of Mrs. Pumfrey Lord's
new novel is Christian Science, and
the hero, the Duke of Southminster, is
understood to be a composite portrait of
Lord <name rend="sc">Rosebery</name> and Mr. <name rend="sc">Gladstone</name>.
The character of the evil genius of the
plot, Lord Rufus Doldrum, is partly
modelled on <name rend="sc">Alcibiades</name>, but in its main
lines is reminiscent of Mrs. <name rend="sc">Eddy</name>
and Major <name rend="sc">Winston Churchill</name>. On
the other hand the eccentric Lord
Wymondham, who creates a sensation
by appearing at a Cabinet meeting in
accordion-pleated pyjamas, is understood
to be an entirely imaginary personage.
The novel, which has been
running in <title>Wanamaker's Weekly</title>, will
shortly be published by the Strongmans.</p>
                <div xml:id="d1e1495" type="div3">
                    <head>A Poet who Counts.</head>
                    <p>Mr. Ouseley Pampfield, who has
been recuperating at Buxton after
spraining his ankle while getting out
of his magnificent motor, is now seeing
his new volume of poems through the
press. Under the arresting title of
<title>The Soul of a Passivist</title> they will
shortly be published by the firm of
Coddler and Slack.</p>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1505" type="div3">
                    <head>The Jimmisons Again.</head>
                    <p>The Long Lanes will shortly publish
a new "Jimmison" novel, The <title>Factota</title>.
The heroine is a young lady enamoured
of the doctrine of the economic independence
of women. She enters a
Draper's Emporium in Manchester
and works her way up to the post of
manager, but heads a strike of the
work-girls. The claims of romance,
however, are not overlooked, for in the
long run <title>Retta Carboy</title>—for that is her
charming name—wins the hand and
heart of the junior partner's chauffeur,
who turns out to be son of the Earl
of Ancoats. The scene in which the
Rolls-Royce, frightened by the sight
of some Highland cattle, executes a
cross-cut counter-rocking skid, is one
of the finest things the Jimmisons have
ever done.</p>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1518" type="div3">
                    <head>Armageddon in the Making.</head>
                    <p>Governesses, so long the butt of unkindly
satire, have at last come by
their own. Miss Bertha Bowlong, who
was governess to the <name rend="sc">Kaiser</name> in the
late "sixties," is shortly about to
publish her reminiscences of her now
all-too-notorious pupil. Strange to say
it never occurred to her to set them
down till quite recently, nearly fifty
years after the event. The book, which
is now announced by the Talboys, is
rich in illuminating anecdotes of the
future <name rend="sc">War Lord</name>, as well as vivid
portraits of <name rend="sc">Moltke, Bismarck, Treitschke,
Münchhausen</name>, Eulenspiegel,
Dudelsack and other luminaries of
the Prussian capital.</p>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1534" type="div3">
                    <head>The Charm of Cannibalism.</head>
                    <p>Miss Ermyntrude Stuggy (Mrs. Raymond
Blott), whose extraordinary novel,
<title>The Lurid Lady</title>, was described by
Father <name rend="sc">Bernard Vaughan</name> as the
most "precipitous" book he had ever
preached on, has returned to England
after two years' residence among the
cannibals of the Solomon Islands.
Hence the title of her forthcoming
volume, <title>The Adorable Anthropophagi</title>,
which is already announced by Messrs.
Hybrow and Garbidge. The contents
explain why Mr. Blott has heroically
preferred to remain with the cannibals.</p>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1550" type="div3">
                    <head>Major Finch's Great Discovery.</head>
                    <p>Major Hector Finch, the famous
Nationalist M.P., philosopher, psychologist
and scholar, has made a remarkable
literary discovery. It is that
<title>Johnson's Dictionary</title> is not, as is
generally supposed, the work of <name rend="sc">Ben
Jonson</name>, but of <name rend="sc">Samuel Johnson</name>, the
son of a Lichfield bookseller. This
epoch-making revelation, briefly and
modestly outlined in a letter to <title>The
Daily Chronicle</title>, will be set forth in
detail in a massive volume of 1,000
pages, with a portrait of the author, to
be issued shortly by the House of
Swallow and Gull.</p>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1569" type="div3">
                    <head>Odds and Ends.</head>
                    <p>
                        <title>The Vegetarians</title>, a novel with a
strong dietetic interest by Janet Melinda
Didham, is announced by the firm of
Gherkin Mark.</p>
                    <p>
                        <title>The Molly Monologues</title> is the alluring
title of a volume of sketches by
Richard Turpin, shortly appearing with
Pincher and Steel.</p>
                    <p>Miss Loofah Windsor, who wrote
<title>The Washpot</title>, a successful story of last
summer, has just finished a new one of
a humorous type, called <title>What—no
Soap</title>? which the Dinwiddies will
publish in a month or two.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"A few lucky corps actually had geese to
pave the way for the Christmas pudding;
they were quartered in some place where a
whip round among the officers and a ride to
the nearest town or village secured enough
geese to feed a battalion."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Jersey Morning News</title>.
</p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Somehow we feel that this might have
been more tactfully expressed.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Mr. Dillon harangued the House for three-quarters
of an hour on militarism, <title>The Daily
Mail</title>, Suvla BaBy, and sundry other topics."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Daily Mail</title>.
</p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>An extended report of his remarks on
this interesting infant would have been
welcome.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page57" n="pg 57"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1636" type="div2">
                <head>ON THE CARDS.</head>
                <p>To many people wholly free from
superstition, except that, after spilling
the salt, they are careful to throw a
little over the left shoulder, and do not
go out of their way to walk under
ladders, and are not improved in appetite
by sitting thirteen at table, and
much prefer that may should not be
brought into the house—to these
people, otherwise so free from superstition,
it would perhaps be surprising to
know what great numbers of their
fellow-creatures resort daily to such
black arts as fortune-telling by the
cards.</p>
                <p>Yet quite respectable, God-fearing,
church-going old ladies, and probably
old gentlemen too, treasure this practice,
to say nothing of younger and therefore
naturally more frivolous folk; and
many make the consultation of the
two and fifty oracles a morning habit.</p>
                <p>And particularly women. Those well-thumbed
packs of cards that we know
so well are not wholly dedicated to
"Patience," I can assure you.</p>
                <p>All want to be told the same thing:
what the day will bring forth. But
each searcher into the dim and dangerous
future has, of course, individual
methods—some shuffling seven times
and some ten, and so forth, and all
intent upon placating the elfish goddess,
Caprice. There is little Miss
Banks, for example, but I must tell
you about her.</p>
                <p>Nothing would induce little Miss
Banks to leave the house in the morning
without seeing what the cards promised
her, and so open and impressionable
are her mind and heart that she is still
interested in the colour of the romantic
fellow whom the day, if kind, is to fling
across her path. The cards, as you
know, are great on colours, all men
being divided into three groups: dark
(which has the preference), fair, and
middling. Similarly for you, if you can
get little Miss Banks to read your fate
(but you must of course shuffle the
pack yourself) there are but three kinds
of charmers: dark (again the most
fascinating and to be desired), fair, and
middling.</p>
                <p>It is great fun to watch little Miss
Banks at her necromancy. She takes
it so earnestly, literally wrenching the
future's secrets from their lair.</p>
                <p>"A letter is coming to you from some
one," she says. "An important letter."</p>
                <p>And again, "I see a voyage over
water."</p>
                <p>Or very seriously, "There's a death."</p>
                <p>You gasp.</p>
                <p>"No, it's not yours. A fair woman's."</p>
                <p>You laugh. "Only a fair woman's!"
you say. "Go on."</p>
                <p>But the cards have not only ambiguities,
but strange reticences.</p>
                <p>"Oh," little Miss Banks will say, her
eyes large with excitement, "there's a
payment of money and a dark man."</p>
                <p>"Good," you say.</p>
                <p>"But I can't tell," she goes on,
"whether you pay it to him or he pays
it to you."</p>
                <p>"That's a nice state of things,"
you say, becoming indignant. "Surely
you can tell."</p>
                <p>"No, I can't."</p>
                <p>You begin to go over your dark
acquaintances who might owe you
money, and can think of none.</p>
                <p>You then think of your dark acquaintances
to whom you owe money, and
are horrified at their number.</p>
                <p>"Oh, well," you say, "the whole
thing's rubbish, anyway."</p>
                <p>Little Miss Banks's eyes dilate with
pained astonishment. "Rubbish!"—and
she begins to shuffle again.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/057.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>From "Notes for the Use of New
Chaplains," by an Indian Archdeacon:</p>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"I have only given advice on matters where,
to my own knowledge, an ignorance of procedure
has led to adverse criticism with regard
to breeches of etiquette."
</p>
                </quote>
                <p>Somebody seems to have been making
fun of the venerable gentleman's continuations.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page58" n="pg 58"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1736" type="div2">
                <head>UNWRITTEN LETTERS TO THE KAISER.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e1740" type="div3">
                    <head>No. XXXIII.</head>
                    <p>(<title>From <name rend="sc">Theodore Roosevelt</name>, U.S.A.</title>)</p>
                    <p>It's bully to live in a country where you can say what
you like about the bosses, and that, Sir, is what I've been
doing and mean to go on doing to you. There's no
manner of question about it, you're the biggest boss and
the most dangerous that we in this country have ever come
up against, and if our Government had only got a right
idea of its bounden duty we should have protested against
your conduct, yes, and backed our protest by our deeds
long before this; but the fact is there's too much milk and
water in the blood of some of our big fellows. They whine
when they ought to be up and denouncing, and they crouch
and crawl instead of standing upright like free and fearless
men, and giving the devil's agent the straightest eye-puncher
of which the human arm is capable. I thank Heaven, Sir,
that I'm not made on that plan. I'm out to fight humbug
and hypocrisy, even when they masquerade as friendship
and benevolence; and when I see a fellow coming along
with hundreds of pious texts in his mouth, and his hands
dripping with the blood of innocent women and children,
why, I've got to say what I think of him or die. For my
own part—</p>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>"On Bible stilts I don't affect to stalk,</l>
                            <l>Nor lard with Scripture my familiar talk;</l>
                            <l>For man may pious texts repeat</l>
                            <l>And yet religion have no inward seat."</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                    <p>A man called <name rend="sc">Hood</name> wrote that nearly eighty years ago, but
it's quite true still. I wonder what he would have written
if he'd had the bad luck to know about you and your disgusting
appeals to the Almighty, whom you treat as if He
were always waiting round the corner to be decorated with
the Iron Cross.</p>
                    <p>Now mind, I don't want you to deceive yourself. If I
dislike you and feel as if I'd sooner kick you than shake
hands with you, it isn't because I'm a peace-at-any-price
man. No man can say that about me without qualifying
for a place within easy reach of <name rend="sc">Ananias</name>; but when I
decide to take part in a scrap—and there's few scraps
going that I don't butt into sooner or later—I like to feel
that I've got a bit of right on my side. But how can <hi rend="it">you</hi>
feel that when you over-run Belgium and burn down
Louvain—that's the place that made your heart bleed,
bah!—and when you shoot down Belgian hostages and do
to death an English nurse? All that never seems to strike
you. You go on thinking of yourself as a holy humble
man whom everybody wilfully mistakes for a bully and a
tyrant. Well, you can't fool everybody all the time, you
know, and in this case it happens that everybody has got
some sound horse-sense in his head. Who wanted to hurt
you? You'd put together a great army and your commercial
prosperity was a pretty good business proposition.
You'd got a navy and you'd got a very meek and submissive
people, which didn't prevent them from being
harsh and domineering and cruel so far as other peoples
were concerned. If you wanted to have folk afraid of you
there were plenty to humour you by pretending to tremble
when you frowned and shook your head. But you weren't
going to be satisfied. You must have a war so as to show
what a great general you were, and you shoved on the old
man <name rend="sc">Francis Joseph</name> and kept urging him from behind
until everyone got tired by the impossibility of making you
come out fair and square on the side of peace.</p>
                    <p>Well, you've got your war, and I hope you like it. This
isn't one of your military promenades. This is hard, long
fighting against men whose only wish was to be left alone.
You've forced them to form a trust for the purpose of trust-busting,
and in the end they'll wear you out and have you
beaten to a frazzle in spite of all you can do. You've lost
millions of men and millions of money, and you don't seem
to get on with your final and decisive victory, and you're
still the vainest and the loudest man on earth. Isn't it
just about time you saw yourself as the rest of us see you,
an irritable lime-light hero, whose favourite effort is to sink
a <title>Lusitania</title> and pretend he had to do it because he didn't
think she'd go down or because there were too many
women and just enough children in the world? All I can
say is that I've had more than enough of you.</p>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Theodore Roosevelt</name>.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1807" type="div2">
                <head>BEYOND THE LIMIT.</head>
                <quote>
                    <p>
[The German General Staff declares that for air-warfare there
are still lacking international laws of any kind.]
</p>
                </quote>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>When Peace lured the Powers to her House at the Hague</l>
                        <l>With promises specious and welcome though vague</l>
                        <l>Of a time when the terrors of war should lie hid</l>
                        <l>And the leopard fall headlong in love with the kid,</l>
                        <l>She drew up a set of Utopian rules</l>
                        <l>For the guidance of all the best bellicose schools.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Among the more notable schemes that she planned</l>
                        <l>She fashioned them bounds to their methods on land,</l>
                        <l>Taught the whole of them, too, how humane they could be</l>
                        <l>If a scrap should occur, as it might, on the sea—</l>
                        <l>In a word, pruned the pinions of war everywhere</l>
                        <l>Save the one place that war could fly into—the air.</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>But the Hun, he forswore what he vowed at her shrine,</l>
                        <l>And behaved like a fiend on the soil and the brine;</l>
                        <l>Then he turned to his Zepps, and remarked, "I can fly,</l>
                        <l>And she never laid down any law for the sky;</l>
                        <l>Here's a chance for some real dirty work to be done;"</l>
                        <l>And he did it by simply out-Hunning the Hun.</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e1888" type="div3">
                    <head>How to Save Your Teeth.</head>
                    <p>From the Soldiers and Sailors Dental Aid Fund (43,
Leicester Square), which has done exceptional service during
the War, comes the story of an old lady who applied for a
set of teeth for her soldier grandson. When asked if he
would know how to take care of them, she replied that
she would give him the benefit of her own experience,
having always made it a rule to remove her artificial teeth
at meal times.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>Two cuttings from one issue of <title>The Egyptian Mail</title>:—</p>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"TREMENDOUS INCREASE IN RECRUITING.</p>
                        <p>ANOTHER 1,000,000,000 MEN WANTED."</p>
                        <p>"<name rend="sc">Wanted</name> proof-reader for the Egyptian Mail."
</p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>It certainly does want one; but for the sake of the gaiety
of nations we trust it won't get him.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"With regard to the expeditionary force, the unexampled heroism
and determination of our troops enabled them to establish a foothold
on the tip of the peninsula, but photographs confirm the reports of
eye-witnesses that they were literally holding on by their eyelids to
the positions they had occupied."—<title>Sunday Times.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>And the subsequent abandonment was performed like
winking.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>From a draper's notice:—</p>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"On Friday and Saturday the shops will be open until the usual
hours, although lights will not be visible outside. Customers are
requested to open the doors to obtain admittance."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Rugby Advertiser.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>And not to climb through the windows, or come down the
chimney, please.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page59" n="pg 59"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1961" type="div2">
                <head>OUR BOOKING-OFFICE.</head>
                <p>(<title>By Mr. Punch's Staff of Learned Clerks.</title>)</p>
                <p>I forget just how long it is since Mr. <name rend="sc">Arnold Bennett</name>
united <title>Edwin Clayhanger</title> and <title>Hilda Lessways</title> in the
bonds of matrimony. Time goes so fast these days that I
met them again, and <title>Auntie Hamps</title>, and <title>Maggie</title>, and
<title>Clara</title>, and the rest of the Three Towns company, as after
an enormous interval. They themselves however have
changed in nothing, except perhaps that the habit of
introspection and their phenomenal capacity for self-astonishment
have become more pronounced. "He thought,
'I am I; this wife is my wife; and if I put one foot before
the other I shall go inevitably forward.' And it seemed to
him stupendous." I do not say that this is a quotation,
but it represents a habit of mind that is in danger of
growing, upon <title>Edwin</title> especially. He seems never able to
share my own entire confidence in Mr. <name rend="sc">Bennett's</name> efficiency
as creator. Of course nothing very much happens in the
course of <title>These Twain</title> (<name rend="sc">Methuen</name>). It is simply a study
of conjugal existence in its effect upon character; briefly,
how to be happy though married. In the end <title>Edwin</title>
seems to hit upon a sort of solution with the discovery
that injustice is a natural condition to be accepted rather
than resented. So one leaves the two with some prospect,
a little insecure, of happiness. Needless to say the study
of both <title>Edwin</title> and <title>Hilda</title> is marvellously penetrating and
minute, almost to the point of defeating its own end. I
had, not for the first time with Mr. <name rend="sc">Bennett's</name> characters,
a feeling that I knew them too well to have complete belief
in them. They become not portraits but anatomical
diagrams. But for all that the accuracy of his observation
is undeniable. One sees it in those minor personalities of
the tale whom he is content to record from without.
<title>Auntie Hamps</title>, for example, and Clara are two masterpieces
of portraiture. You must read <title>These Twain</title>; but if possible
take time over it.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>American improvements are the wonder of the world.
America seems to have the knack of taking hold of old
stuff and turning it into something full of pep and punch.
You remember a play called <title>Hamlet</title>? No? Well, there
is a scene in it, rather an impressive scene, where a man
chats with his father's ghost. Mr. <name rend="sc">Robert W. Chambers</name>,
America's brightest novelist, has taken much the same
idea and put a bit of zip in it. In his latest work, <title>Athalie</title>
(<name rend="sc">Appleton</name>), the heroine, who is clairvoyant, sees the ghost
of the hero's mother, who prevented the hero from marrying
her, and cuts it. "A hot proud colour flared in her
cheeks as she drew quietly aside and stood with averted
head to let her pass." In all my researches in modern
fiction I cannot recall a more dramatic and satisfying
situation. It is, I believe, the first instance on record of a
spectre being snubbed. <name rend="sc">Shakspeare</name> never thought of anything
like that. As regards the other aspects of <title>Athalie</title>,
the book, I cannot see what else a reviewer can say but
that it is written by Mr. <name rend="sc">Chambers</name>. The world is divided
into those who read every line Mr. <name rend="sc">Chambers</name> writes, irrespective
of its merits, and those who would require to be
handsomely paid before reading a paragraph by him. A
<pb xml:id="page60" n="pg 60"/>
million eager shop-girls, school-girls, chorus-girls, factory-girls
and stenographers throughout America are probably
devouring <title>Athalie</title> at this moment. My personal opinion
that the book is a potboiler, turned out on a definite
formula, like all of Mr. <name rend="sc">Chambers'</name> recent work, to meet a
definite demand, cannot deter a single one of them from
sobbing over it. As for that section of the public which
remembers <title>The King in Yellow</title> and <title>Cardigan</title>, it has long
ago become resigned to Mr. <name rend="sc">Chambers'</name> decision to take the
cash and let the credit go, and has ceased to hope for a
return on his part to the artistic work of his earlier period,
when he wrote novels as opposed to Best Sellers.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Let me heartily commend to you a book of stories by
doughty penmen turned swordsmen for the period of the
War—<name rend="sc">A. E. W. Mason</name>, of the Manchester Regiment;
<name rend="sc">A. A. M.</name>, of the Royal Warwicks; <name rend="sc">W. B. Maxwell</name>, Royal
Fusilier; <name rend="sc">Ian Hay</name>, A. and S. <name rend="sc">Highlander</name>; <name rend="sc">Compton Mackenzie</name>,
R.N.; "<name rend="sc">Q.</name>," of the
Duke of Cornwall's L.I.;
<name rend="sc">Oliver Onions</name>, A.S.C.; <name rend="sc">Barry
Pain</name>, R.N.A.S.; and just short
of a dozen others. Published
by Messrs. <name rend="sc">Hodder and
Stoughton</name>, under title, <title>The
Red Cross Story Book</title>, to be
sold for the benefit of <title>The
Times</title> Fund. It's the sort of
book about which even the
most conscientious reviewer
feels he can honestly say
nice things without any too
thorough examination of the
contents. With that thought I
started turning over the pages
casually, but found myself dipping
deeper and deeper, until,
becoming entirely absorbed, I
abandoned all pretence of professional
detachment and had
a thoroughly good time. I
should like to be able to state
that the quality of these stories
of humour, adventure and sentiment
was uniform, if only for
the sake of this appropriate word. But I can say that the
best are excellent, the average is high, and the tenor so
varied as to suit almost any age and taste.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/060.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Mr. <name rend="sc">B. G. O'Rorke</name>, Chaplain to the Forces, has written
a short account of his experiences in confinement—<title>In The
Hands of the Enemy</title> (<name rend="sc">Longmans</name>). Seeing that he was
allowed, as a minister of religion, unique opportunities of
meeting our officers (though not men of the ranks) shut up
in different fortresses, and particularly because he has been
thoughtful enough to mention many of them by name, his
narrative is one which nobody with near friends now in
Germany can afford to miss. The general reader, on the
other hand, may have to confess to some disappointment,
since the foggy shadow of the Censor, German or English,
still looms over the pages here and there, blotting out the
sensational episodes which we felt we had reason, if
not right, to expect; and if their absence is really due to
Mr. <name rend="sc">O'Rorke's</name> steady refusal to indulge us by embellishing
his almost too unvarnished recital the effect is just the same.
Or perhaps the suggestion of flatness is to be ascribed to
the enemy's failure on the whole to treat certain of his
victims in any very extraordinary manner, and if so we
can accept it and be thankful. There are lots of interesting
passages all the same, such as the account of the specially
favourable treatment of officers from Irish regiments,
accorded in all Teutonic seriousness as preparatory to an
invitation to serve in the ranks of Prussia; or the pathetic
incident of the white-haired French priest sent to the cells
for urging his congregation to pray <title>pour nos âmes</title>. Nowhere
outside the Fatherland, I should imagine, would
prisoners be forbidden to pray even <title>pour nos armes</title>, and
the stupidity of the misunderstanding is typical enough.
The cheerful dignity shown by prisoners under provocation
makes a fine contrast to such pitiful smallness, and of that
this little book is a notable record.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>I suppose it would not be possible to travel in the Pacific
without a fountain-pen and a note-book. At all events this
seems a privation from which the staunchest of our literary
adventurers have hitherto shrunk. Do not however regard
this as anything more than a casual observation, certainly
not as implying any complaint
against so agreeable a volume
as <title>Voyaging in Wild Seas</title>
(<name rend="sc">Mills and Boon</name>). There
must be many among the
countless admirers of Mr. <name rend="sc">Jack
London</name> who will be delighted
to read this intimate journal
of his travellings in remote
waters, written by the wife
who accompanied him, and
who is herself, as she proves
on many pages, one of the
most enthusiastic of those admirers.
You may say there is
nothing very much in it all,
but just some pleasant sea-prattle
about interesting ports
and persons, and a number of
photographs rather more intimate
than those that generally
illustrate the published travel-book.
But the general impression
is jolly. Stevensonians
will be especially curious over
the visit to Samoa, concerning
her first impressions of which
Mrs. <name rend="sc">London</name> writes: "As the <title>Snark</title> slid along, we began
to exclaim at the magnificent condition of this German
province—the leagues of copra plantation, extending from
the shore up into the mountainous hinterland, thousands
of close-crowded acres of heavy green palms." This was
in May, 1908. Vailima was at that time the residence of
the German Governor (a desecration since happily removed);
but the <name rend="sc">Londons</name> were able to explore the gardens
and peep in at the rooms whose planning <name rend="sc">Stevenson</name> had
so enjoyed. Later of course they climbed to the lonely
mountain grave of "the little great man"—a phrase oddly
reminiscent of one in an unpublished letter of <name rend="sc">Rupert Brooke</name>
(about the same expedition) that I had just been reading.
Mrs. <name rend="sc">London</name> deserves our thanks for letting us share so
interesting a holiday in these restricted days.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e2183" type="div3">
                    <head>IN MEMORY OF "MARTIN ROSS"</head>
                    <p>(<name rend="sc">Violet Martin</name>).</p>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>With <title>Flurry's</title> Hounds, and you our guide,</l>
                            <l>We've learned to laugh until we cried;</l>
                            <l>Dear <name rend="sc">Martin Ross</name>, the coming years</l>
                            <l>Find all our laughter lost in tears.</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>