<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Punch, or the London Charivari, Vol. 150, March 22, 1916</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <idno type="gutenberg">22805</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>This text is freely available for re-use under US and UK law, consult
                            your local legal restrictions if elsewhere.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This text is a TEI version of a Project Gutenberg text originally located at
                            <ptr target="http://www.gutenberg.org/dirs//////"/>. As per their license agreement we have removed
                        all references to the project's trademark, however have included this
                        pointer to the original in case you want the plain text, or their XHTML
                        version. </p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2008-06-27T16:13:27.053+01:00"/>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:id="d1e44" type="div2">
                <head>March 22, 1916.</head>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page193" n="pg 193"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/193.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e59" type="div2">
                <head>CHARIVARIA.</head>
                <p>Portugal is now officially at war
with Germany, and the dogs of frightfulness
are already toasting "<title>der Tagus</title>."</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>At first the report that <name rend="sc">Enver Pasha</name>
had gone to pay a visit to the tomb of
the <name rend="sc">Prophet</name> at Medina caused a feeling
of profound depression in Constantinople;
but it is now recognised that
there was no other course open to him,
as <name rend="sc">Mahomet</name> was not in a position to
visit the Pasha.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>
                    <name rend="sc">Sven Hedin</name> is reported to be at
Constantinople, on his way to the
Turkish Front. It is supposed that he
will undertake the writing of the official
despatches, a duty to which the innate
modesty of the Osmanli prevents him
from doing full justice.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A salmon containing a label marked
"U 100" was recently caught in the
Avon. No trace of the crew has been
found.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>It has been discovered in Germany
that General <name rend="sc">Hindenberg</name> is descended
from <name rend="sc">Charlemagne</name>, and an attempt
by certain admirers of the Prussian
General to visit the scenes of his
ancestor's exploits has only been
abandoned as the result of an unaccountable
opposition on the part of
the French.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>"Bigamy," declares Mr. Justice Low,
"is as low a form of crime as drunkenness."
On the other hand there is this
to be said for it, that it is seldom found,
like drunkenness, to develop into a habit.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A large number of German barbers,
it is said, have become naturalized
since the commencement of the War,
and are now engaged in capturing the
trade from the British barbers, many
of whom have been taken for military
service. Not for nothing, it seems,
did the <name rend="sc">Kaiser</name> say in one of his famous
speeches, "The razor must be in our
fist."</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Mr. <name rend="sc">Tennant</name> told the House of
Commons last week that the War
Office had 3,000,000 goat skins. As
the statement has given rise to a certain
uneasiness it should be explained that
all the goats have been safely extracted.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Notwithstanding reports to the contrary,
says an official German telegram,
the new submarine warfare is in full
swing. It should only be a matter of
time before those responsible for it find
themselves in a similar situation.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A draughtsman of Babylonian and
Assyrian antiquities has been discharged
by the British Museum in the
interests of economy. The artist, it is
reported, has already had several
attractive offers of employment as a
Parliamentary cartoonist.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>Onions, we are told, have reached the
unprecedented price of thirty shillings
a hundredweight, and several of the old
established onion bars in the City may
have to close their doors.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>It is useless, Mr. <name rend="sc">Hughes</name> warns his
English admirers, to defeat Germany
in the field unless adequate steps are
also taken to stop her inroads upon
the Empire's trade. What is wanted
is, of course, a counter-stroke.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>A well-informed neutral states that
the Grand Admiral <name rend="sc">Tirpitz's</name> unexpected
retirement was caused by a rush
of blood to the hands.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e165" type="div3">
                    <head>Another Bulgarian Atrocity.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"The position in Monastir is intolerable,
owing to the orgies of the Bulgarian comitadjis.
The Greek refugees are in a pitiable
plight, especially now the Greek consul has
1 ft."—<title>Balkan News.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Thus crippled he cannot, of course,
display his usual activity.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page194" n="pg 194"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e185" type="div2">
                <head>THE KAISER ON KILIMANJARO.</head>
                <p>Correspondence in <title>The Times</title> has recalled the fact that Kilimanjaro,
from whose neighbourhood the enemy has just been expelled, was included
in German East Africa at the special desire of the <name rend="sc">Kaiser</name> (then
<name rend="sc">Prince William of Prussia</name>). It appears that he took a peculiar
interest in the fauna and flora of that district. Incidentally, the
highest peak of Kilimanjaro (19,000 feet) is named Kaiser Wilhelm
Spitze. The author of these lines does not claim a close acquaintance
with the natural history and botany of this region, and cannot therefore
vouch for the accuracy of his details.</p>
                <lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>O mountain of the sounding name,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                        <l>Almost as loud as my own fame,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                        <l>Plucked from my Empire's jewelled hem</l>
                        <l>I deemed you once the fairest gem</l>
                        <l>In my Colonial diadem,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Not for your height, though you are high,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                        <l>And practically scrape the sky,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                        <l>But for the beasts and birds and flowers</l>
                        <l>That nestle in your snowy bowers</l>
                        <l>I loved you best of all my dowers,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>In one of my Imperial jaunts,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                        <l>I looked to penetrate their haunts,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                        <l>It was among my dearest hopes</l>
                        <l>To slay canaries on your slopes</l>
                        <l>Or trap elusive antelopes,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>I had a passionate wish to snare</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        (Kilimanjaro!)</l>
                        <l>Your local beetle in his lair,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                        <l>O'er precipices stiff with ice</l>
                        <l>(Perils for me are full of spice)</l>
                        <l>To cull your starry edelweiss,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>Alas! the lovely vision fades,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                        <l>Never amid your musky glades,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro—</l>
                        <l>Never shall I (<title>Gott strafe</title>
                            <name rend="sc">Smuts</name>!)</l>
                        <l>Surprise your monkeys gathering nuts</l>
                        <l>Or chase your wombats' flying scuts,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                    </lg>
                    <lg>
                        <l>And when, as I suppose it must,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                        <l>My spirit sheds its mortal crust,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                        <l>They'll find beneath my mailéd vest</l>
                        <l>Your name indelibly impressed</l>
                        <l>(Along with Calais) on my chest,</l>
                        <l rend="i10">                        Kilimanjaro!</l>
                    </lg>
                </lg>
                <p>O.S.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>
"With the use of the various kinds of periscopes we could see quite
clearly every movement on the German side, and even hear them
talking."—<title>Daily Chronicle.</title>
                </p>
                <p>Try our new periscope, with telephone-attachment.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <p>From a sale catalogue:—</p>
                <p>
"Remains of Summer Waistcoats, from 3/11."
</p>
                <p>Nothing doing. Our motto is <title>Vestigia nulla retrorsum</title>.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e410" type="div2">
                <head>UNWRITTEN LETTERS TO THE KAISER.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e414" type="div3">
                    <head>No. XXXVI.</head>
                    <head rend="it">( From Herr <name rend="sc">Wolfgang Offenmaul</name>, an actor).</head>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Most Gracious Majesty</name>,—How strangely and uncomfortably
the Fates sport with us! It is but two years ago,
I remember, that it came into my head to look forward to
the far-off day when I should shake off the stage and all
its agitations, its triumphs, its disappointments and even
its jealousies and its quarrels, and should be able to live
my own life in the pleasant and happy world of reality.
But I put the thought by, for much still remained to me
to be endured and achieved in my profession, and I thought
that some day, if matters turned out favourably, I might
have the supreme glory of impersonating <title>Hamlet</title> or <title>Macbeth</title>
under the very eye of your Imperial Majesty and of noting
that you were not displeased with the performance of one
of the most devoted of your subjects. This hope, springing
up in my breast, gave me new strength and a fresh joy in
the often dull round of my daily task, for in matters of the
stage your Majesty, being, as we often say among ourselves,
the greatest actor of us all and having from the earliest
years imbibed the love of the footlights and the limelight,
is an incomparable judge of the true histrionic art, and a
word of praise from you is worth columns and columns in
the newspapers. It is to us as when a cobbler's boots are
praised by a rival cobbler.</p>
                    <p>And there is another point which then kept me from
giving way any further to my dreams of retirement from
the theatre. Real life, so calm for the most part and so
regular, is but a dull thing to those who live a fictitious life
on the boards, in the midst of excitements and honour and
crimes, with murder and sudden death awaiting them, as it
were, round the corner. After <title>Hamlet</title> has seen his mother's
death, has killed <title>Laertes</title> and the <title>King</title> and has himself
expired, what is it to him to come to life again and to sit
down, without his royal trappings to a supper of sausage
and potatoes, while his wife sits by and darns his stockings
and the baby begins to cry in its cot? So thought I, and
resolved to continue my career of acting, though I acknowledged
that some day, perhaps, in the very distant future,
retirement might have its attractions.</p>
                    <p>All this was before the War broke out. When that
happened I, like the rest, was seized and thrust into a
uniform and made to remember my drill and was presented
with a rifle and a bayonet. Finally, with my regiment I
was marched off to the Front in France, where I still
linger in daily expectation of death. Dreadful things have
I seen, men blown into nothingness by shells, men pierced
through and through by the steel, women murdered and
worse than murdered, and children crushed under fallen
walls—sights I cannot bear to think of, though they force
themselves upon me and murder sleep. I was, perhaps,
unduly contemptuous of real life, but now I abhor it and try
in vain to put it away from me. I desire with a full-hearted
longing to return to that life of imagination where the
most dreadful bloodshed ends at about eleven o'clock every
evening, without leaving any impression on those who take
part. Yes, give me again the life of the theatre and remove
far away this brutal scenery of trenches and shells and
bombs and quick-firers and men summoned from peace
and ease to cut one another's throats because a histrion
<name rend="sc">Kaiser</name> has so willed it and none of his subjects dared to
say him nay. To get away from this and never to return
to it I would willingly consent to play the <title>First Murderer</title> in
<title>Macbeth</title> for the remainder of my life. It would be an
innocent and an honourable occupation compared with
what I am forced day by day and night by night to endure.</p>
                    <p>Yours, in respectful despair, <name rend="sc">Wolfgang Offenmaul</name>.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page195" n="pg 195"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e471" type="div3">
                    <head>ANOTHER CONSCIENTIOUS OBJECTOR.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/195.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page196" n="pg 196"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e484" type="div2">
                <head>THE WATCH DOGS.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e488" type="div3">
                    <head>XXXVI.</head>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">My dear Charles</name>,—I am afraid
you'll be worrying about me again,
wondering why I'm lying doggo, what
mischief I'm up to, or whether anything
has happened to me. Something
has happened, but I'm not quite sure
myself what it is. Anyhow, I'll tell you
all I know. It wasn't in the <title>Gazette</title>
proper; it was in the "Memoranda."
It referred to a Second Lieutenant
(Temporary Lieutenant), intimating
that he was to hold the acting rank
of Captain while engaged in
present duties, which looks to
me as if they are giving nothing
away but want to keep in with
me till they have settled up
matters with the Bosch. When
the trouble shows signs of being
about to end, they'll either make
me a Temporary General and
hand me over to the enemy as a
sop, or else they will turn round
on me and tell me that, being a
Temporary Memorandum, I'm
nothing at all; am I going quietly
or must they put the handcuffs
on me? As the saying is,
"it ain't 'ardly safe"; at any
moment one may find oneself
in a bowler hat being jostled
by the crowd and wholly estranged
from Mr. Cox, of
Charing Cross. Meanwhile I'm
a Captain, or parading as such,
and I carry in my pocket a
leash of "crowns" and a yard
of braid (with adhesive back) in
case of further developments.</p>
                    <p>Talking of civilian hats, by the
way, my particular class of soldier,
never spoilt by over-fussing,
has dismal expectations as to
the <hi rend="it">finale</hi>. We feel that, when
the other side sees light and is
prepared to submit to judgment,
with costs, we shall be the last to leave
for home, and when we get there all
the beer will be sold out.</p>
                    <p>Meanwhile I'm going along nicely,
and by saying nothing but looking a
lot I've created quite an air of importance
around me, which induces all
sorts of regimental officers to salute me
at first sight and to wish they hadn't
on further acquaintance. It's an ever-increasing
difficulty, this matter of
saluting: in a part of the world where
there's a General round every other
corner I can never make up my mind
on the spur of the moment what to
do about Majors and suchlike. Some
like a salute, others don't. I have
invented a gesture of my own which is
entirely non-committal and gives satisfaction
to both. Those who don't look
for a salute put it down to an excess
of geniality; those who do expect one
put it down to ignorance combined
with anxiety to please.</p>
                    <p>Only once has it got me into trouble
so far. The occasion is worth mentioning,
since I was at the time talking to
a General in a public place. (Yes,
there we were, talking away about
nothing in particular, "conversing," I
might say, just as it might have been
you and myself passing the time of
day. <title>Very</title> impressive). A Major, one
of the expectant sort, came up from
behind the General; when he was
within distance of the august back he
saluted it. It was one of those salutes
which could be felt, but, as it happened,
the General didn't feel it. The problem
at once arose, what was I to do, with
the Major's stony eye full upon me?
The waggle, obviously, but in a modified
degree, since it doesn't do to be
fidgetting with your hands when you're
being talked to by your elders and
betters. I went through the motions,
therefore, meaning them to mean that,
though I was chatting with a General,
yet I wasn't above saluting a Major.
He mistook the movement, however,
and thought that I thought that, because
I was chatting with a General,
therefore he'd saluted me! My goodness,
we nearly lost the War that time!</p>
                    <p>But don't you believe all this talk
about military discipline. Take the
case of my own Colonel, for instance,
a man who, before he took to staff work,
had probably dug enough trenches, put
out enough barbed wire and, generally,
made enough mess of respectable agricultural
land to earn for himself a
special vote of censure from the United
Association of French and Belgian
Farmers. Now, there's a soldier, if
ever there was one; but are his orders
obeyed when they don't fit in with the
convenience of his subordinates?</p>
                    <p>You shall judge for yourself. The
other day he made up his mind, not
casually or by the way, but in
writing, duly signed, sealed and
circulated, that "The moon will
rise to-morrow at 4.43 <name rend="sc">A.M.</name>"
Did the moon comply? No, Sir,
it did not; I'm told it was absent
from parade altogether. Did my
Colonel put it under arrest? Did
he even call for its reasons in
writing? Again, no. On the contrary,
he weakly gave in, saying
that he'd got the time out of an
almanack supplied by his Insurance
Company, and that "the
man from the Insurance" was
to blame for sticking the pages
together and getting him into an
inappropriate month. What I
say is an order's an order, and
it is nothing to do with the
moon where the Colonel gets
his ideas from.</p>
                    <p>Call it fear or favour, I only
know that when I'm informed
that I am to rise at 5 <name rend="sc">A.M.</name> to-morrow
morning, and, with no
intention of disobeying, I ask
very quietly and very politely
if they remember that this is
March and not July, at the very
least I shall be told that I
ought to be ashamed of being a
civilian instead of openly behaving
as such. Yours ever, <name rend="sc">Henry</name>.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e537" type="div3">
                    <head>ANOTHER INDISPENSABLE.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/196.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e548" type="div3">
                    <head>Herodias?</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Any lady requiring Head of two Parlourmaids
or Under Parlourmaid, we know of
several."—<title>Morning Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Bombardier G. Dougherty, R.A.M.C. ...
has been given the D.C.M. ... for twice repairing
telephone wires under a terrific storm
of fire."—<title>Morning Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Conscientious objectors will note the
new rank and duty of R.A.M.C. men.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Two large jewel robberies in London, in
which property to the value of several thousands
of pounds has been stolen, are being
invested by the police."—<title>Morning Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>In Exchequer Bonds, no doubt. But
we hope they have reserved a few pairs
of bracelets for the thieves when they
catch them.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page197" n="pg 197"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e594" type="div2">
                <head>MR. JOHN'S PORTRAIT OF MR. GEORGE.</head>
                <p>The generally favourable opinion of
<name rend="sc">Mr. Augustus John's</name> striking portrait
of <name rend="sc">Mr. Lloyd George</name> is not shared by
everybody. The following criticism of
the picture has reached us, and as it
represents a point of view which, so far
as we know, has not found sympathy
in the Press opinions which have
already appeared, we print it for the
edification of the artist, the sitter and
any others who may have a few moments
to devote to the subject.</p>
                <p>I should like to say (writes our correspondent)
on behalf of myself and of
many worthy members of my congregation
that <name rend="sc">Mr. Augustus John</name> has
missed a great opportunity in painting
his portrait of our greatest Welshman.</p>
                <p>In the first place, surely it lacks
dignity. In it Mr. <name rend="sc">Lloyd George</name>,
who is pre-eminently a man capable
of looking you straight in the eye,
is depicted as looking someone else
obliquely in the eye. I would that his
strong features had been accompanied
by a direct and thoughtful gaze, instead
of that petulant side-glance, which to
all of us who know the smiling candour
of the <name rend="sc">Minister of Munitions</name> is so
foreign an expression.</p>
                <p>I cannot speak with authority about
the sitter's raiment. At the same time
I must register my dislike of these
clothes, which appear to have the mud
of the golf-links still fresh upon them.
Surely the artist should have persuaded
Mr. <name rend="sc">Lloyd George</name> to wear his black
coat and vest for the occasion.</p>
                <p>Hanging from a cord is something in
the nature of an aid to vision. I cannot
determine whether it is a pince-nez
or a monocle. The uncertainty is
irritating. Is it possible that the
<name rend="sc">Minister</name> has taken to wearing a single
eye-glass? If so, why has not the artist
put it in the sitter's eye? And as to
the hair—Heaven forbid that I should
cast any reflection upon any man of
Mr. <name rend="sc">Lloyd George</name>'s age possessing
abundant locks; on the contrary, I congratulate
him; but in all my experience
I have never yet known a portrait
to be taken without the sitter being
requested first of all to brush his
hair. Why has Mr. <name rend="sc">Augustus John</name>
flown in the face of all precedent by
neglecting this simple yet desirable
precaution?</p>
                <p>I feel very strongly that nothing in
the portrait indicates the sitter's nationality,
his profession, his love of home,
his favourite recreation or his religious
convictions. These, I venture to say,
are grave omissions. The picture is
sadly wanting in suitable accessories.
If I had been painting it I should have
put a simple yellow daffodil in the
<name rend="sc">Minister's</name> buttonhole, and pictured
through an open window a sunlit bed
of leeks, with perhaps a goat gambolling
among them. I should have represented
the <name rend="sc">Minister of Munitions</name>
in his study practising putting with a
small bomb. And on the wall should
have been a life-size portrait of the
Rev. Dr. <name rend="sc">Clifford</name>.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/197.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e662" type="div3">
                    <head>"The elements so mixed" again.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"The air is the new element, and all the
evidence suggests that we are at sea in it."
<title>Star.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e677" type="div3">
                    <head>Le Mouton Enragé.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Sheep, and also other wild animals, have
a trying time in procuring their necessary
food."
</p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>That's what makes them so wild.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e692" type="div3">
                    <head>A Hero at Zero.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Fish for the Canadian troops. The supply
has been organised by Major Hughie Green,
who is known as the 'Canadians' Fishmonger-General,'
and has travelled in a
frozen condition 2,000 miles across the
Dominion."—<title>Daily Mirror.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"A young farm hand who appealed to the
Coalville Tribunal for exemption yesterday,
when asked whether an older brother could
not take his place on the farm, replied that
his brother's feet were too small for work on
the land."—<title>Morning Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>We hope that his own are not too cold
for work in the trenches.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Mr. Mark Blow will be known henceforth
as 'Mr. Mark.'"—<title>Theatrical Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>The Blow may have fallen, but this
British Mark shows no decline.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page198" n="pg 198"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e738" type="div2">
                <head>THE NEW PATRIOTISM.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e742" type="div3">
                    <head>Epoch-Making Assembly.</head>
                    <p>A public meeting, summoned under
the auspices of the Candid Friends of
England, has just been held at the Hall
of the Grousers' Company, in Little
Britain. The chair was taken by Mr.
<name rend="sc">Outhwaite</name>.</p>
                    <p>The Chairman, opening the meeting,
said that the inception of the League
was due to a number of public-spirited
men who had come to the conclusion,
very unwillingly, that the country was
still insufficiently instructed as to the
inherent and abysmal incapacity of
every member of the Government.
(Cheers.) It was true that certain
sections of the Press did what they
could to point this out, and there was
also the noble, patriotic and self-sacrificing
work carried on in the House at
Question-time. (Loud cheers.) But
he was sorry to say that there still
remained a considerable and, alas!
not wholly negligible number of persons
in the country who hugged the
quaint superstition that a Cabinet
Minister could be earnest, capable
and diligent. It was these benighted
folk whom they desired to reach and
convert. Not till every Englishman
had been convinced that England was
rotten could he (the speaker) and his
friends rest content. (Frantic applause.)
They were met to-day to listen to the
views of various eminent gentlemen as
to how best to spread this gospel.</p>
                    <p>Sir <name rend="sc">Arthur Markham</name>, who was
received with cheers, said that no one
who had followed his recent speeches
could be in any doubt as to the turpitude
and sloth of the men whom
a mischievous caprice had set at the
head of this country's affairs. He for
one should never cease to clamour for
their dismissal. He begged to move a
resolution that in the opinion of that
important and representative meeting
a complete change of Government was
instantly necessary. (A Voice: "Not
only now, but always.") No doubt
there was something in what that
gentleman said, but for the present perhaps
"always" had better be omitted.
The essence of the truest patriotism was
distrust of one's rulers and dissatisfaction
with one's country. (Hear! Hear!).</p>
                    <p>Mr. <name rend="sc">Austin Harrison</name>, in seconding,
said that the finest heritage of an
Englishman was freedom of speech, and
the more that freedom became licence
the finer the Englishman. (Cheers.) By
freedom of speech he meant the right to
say instantly whatever came into one's
head, particularly if it appeared to belittle
one's own country. Because one
could not belittle England really. England
was too great for that. But it
was salutary to try. It was also valuable
to our Allies, because it tended to
prove to them how much in earnest
and how united we must be.</p>
                    <p>A great sensation was now caused
by the appearance of "An Englishman"
from Carmelite Street. This gentleman,
who, like the man who dined with
the <name rend="sc">Kaiser</name>, desiring his anonymity to
be respected, wore a John Bull mask
and brandished an ebony cane, made
the <name rend="sc">Prime Minister</name> the special mark
of his attack. What, he asked, could
be expected of a politician so crafty
and lost to shame as to bid the House
wait and see? Was it not the very
essence of good statesmanship to blurt
out everything at once? Only a craven
time-server would say wait and see.
Waiting was a contemptuous proceeding
wherever practised, and seeing required
eyes, which Heaven knows the <name rend="sc">Premier</name>
woefully lacked. (Cheers.) What right
had an incorrigible hoodwinker such as
Mr. <name rend="sc">Asquith</name> to advise anyone to see?
It was monstrous. Let the people get
rid of this impostor without a twinge of
compunction, and the sooner the better.
As to swapping horses in mid-stream
being unwise, perhaps it was, but it
was not unwise in the way that waiting
to see was. (Applause.)</p>
                    <p>Another masked gentleman, who
was understood to be "Callisthenes"
of Oxford Street, now rose to make
a few useful suggestions. He said
that as the only journalist who wrote
what was practically the leading article
in four evening papers every day, he
surely was entitled to speak with some
authority. The question was how to
get it into the country's head that
England's only chance for recovering
her self-respect and winning the War
was to cry stinking fish? (Loud
cheers.) Well, the best way was to
keep on saying it in and out of season.
His experience had taught him that
everything will bear saying not merely
three times, but three thousand times
and three.</p>
                    <p>Mr. <name rend="sc">Amery</name> said it was ridiculous to
suppose that any Cabinet Minister
wished the War to end or England to
be victorious. The contrary was an
axiom on which the whole future of
his political creed was based. One had
but to look at them to see how flabby
and vacillating they were and how
devoted to the pickings of office.</p>
                    <p>Mr. <name rend="sc">Hogge</name> said that the Chairman
in his opening remarks had disregarded
one of the most valuable media for
spreading the blessed news that England
was at her last gasp, throttled by
place-hunters and parasites. That was
the variety stage. It was wonderful
what a good comic song could do. He
had heard one only the night before, in
which its singer had been vociferously
applauded at the end of a verse which
stated that there were now no German
spies in England because they had all
been naturalised and given War Office
clerkships. That was the kind of
home truth which the public appreciated
and even paid their money to
hear. There could not be too many
songs of that kind.</p>
                    <p>Mr. <name rend="sc">Bernard Shaw</name> said that another
way was to induce publishers to
issue new and amended editions of those
popular writers who had been betrayed
by impulsiveness or short-sight into
eulogies of England. He remembered
several such unfortunate outbursts in
the works of the national poet. There
was, for example, that ill-balanced
utterance of the dying <name rend="sc">John of Gaunt</name>
in praise of our little isle; but of course
one could not expect the intellect to
be at its best just before dissolution.
Still, they would all agree that <name rend="sc">Shakspeare</name>
would be the wholesomer without
that passage. (Cheers.)</p>
                    <p>The Chairman then put the resolution
to the meeting and it was carried
unanimously. In bidding the gathering
farewell the Chairman impressed upon
them that their rule of life should be a
constant and voluble mistrust of our
leaders. It should be a point of honour
with them to deny that the <name rend="sc">First Lord
of the Admiralty</name> could possibly know
anything about the Navy, or wish it to
succeed; that the <name rend="sc">Chancellor of the
Exchequer</name> could possibly know anything
about finance; or the <name rend="sc">Prime
Minister</name> have the elements even of
common intelligence. (Loud cheers.)</p>
                    <p>The meeting then broke up singing
either "For they (the Cabinet) are
wholly bad fellows," or "Fool Britannia,
Britannia's fooled and slaved."</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e828" type="div3">
                    <head>Fashions for Fathers.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"The bride was given away by her father,
who was daintily gowned in a pale blue silk
dress, with veil and orange blossoms lent by
the bride's eldest sister."—<title>Provincial Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Very often it happens that a blank space
is seen in the press, especially in the <title>Sheung
Po</title>, the organ of the Seventy-two Guilds. It
is surprising to see to-day's issue of that paper.
A space, about one and a half feet long and six
feet wide, is vacant. Only five words remain
in that space, namely, 'Taken away by the
Censor.'"—<title>South China Morning Post.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Some of our censors should go to China.
They would have real scope there.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"The French Government emphatically and
categorically denounce as lies many statements
made in the German official reports on the
fighting in the Verdun theatre. Although,
they say, the Germans usually travesty the
truth, they have not before issued such fragrant
lies."—<title>Provincial Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Their offence is rank; it smells to
heaven.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page199" n="pg 199"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e877" type="div2">
                <head>DRESS "AS USUAL."</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e881" type="div3">
                    <head> (<title>A Protest from Mr. Punch</title>.)</head>
                    <quote type="note">The National Organising Committee for
War Savings has issued an appeal against
extravagance in women's dress.</quote>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>Certain ladies—just a section</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Of our spindle side—</l>
                            <l>Swerving in a wrong direction,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Dress have deified;</l>
                            <l>And, as incomes grow more slender,</l>
                            <l>Bring discredit on their gender</l>
                            <l>By refusing to surrender</l>
                            <l> Fashion for their guide.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>Most of England's wives and daughters</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Play a noble part,</l>
                            <l>In the very deepest waters</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Never losing heart;</l>
                            <l>Danger and privation braving,</l>
                            <l>Nursing, helping, toiling, slaving,</l>
                            <l>Thinking vastly more of saving</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Than of looking smart.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>Highly-paid officials slate us,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Dwelling on the ills</l>
                            <l>Which infallibly await us</l>
                            <l rend="i2">In our empty tills;</l>
                            <l>But these frenzied fair ones, furious</l>
                            <l>in the quest of the luxurious,</l>
                            <l>Still pursue a most injurious</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Cult of frocks and frills.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>True, our Ministerial teachers</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Fail us in the fight,</l>
                            <l>For the practice of the preachers</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Sins against the light;</l>
                            <l>Still "Two Wrongs"—for so the sages</l>
                            <l>Crystallize the lore of ages</l>
                            <l>Gathered at successive stages—</l>
                            <l rend="i2">"Do not make a Right."</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>Birds of Paradise are grateful</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Under skies serene;</l>
                            <l>But the human type is hateful</l>
                            <l rend="i2">On a tragic scene;</l>
                            <l>When the outlook's drear and cloudy</l>
                            <l>
                                <title>Punch</title> would rather see you dowdy</l>
                            <l>Than extravagant and rowdy</l>
                            <l rend="i2">In your dress and mien.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>True simplicity is tasteful;</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Think before you spend;</l>
                            <l>Woeful want attends the wasteful</l>
                            <l rend="i2">In the bitter end;</l>
                            <l>You who, when the world is mourning,</l>
                            <l>All remonstrance lightly scorning,</l>
                            <l>Only think of self-adorning,</l>
                            <l rend="i2">Sadden <title>Punch</title>, your friend.</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1071" type="div3">
                    <head>Let Sleeping Birds Lie.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Someone had said it was 'far better to
have the birds driven over one than to have to
wake them up.'"—<title>Scottish Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"The Council of the Poetry Society has
confirmed the appointment of Mr. Galloway
Kyle as acting editor of the 'Poultry Review.'"
</p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>Now that official action has been taken
we may expect an increase in the
number of lays.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/199.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1105" type="div2">
                <head>EYE-WASH.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e1109" type="div3">
                    <head>(<title>A Military Episode in Two Scenes</title>.)</head>
                    <p rend="it">
                        <name rend="sc">Scene I.</name> — The outskirts of a wood.
Time, during an inspection of our
Battalion "at its duties."
         </p>
                    <p rend="it">
                        <name>Second Lieutenant Wood</name> and his platoon
are erecting a wire entanglement.
To them enter <name>Second Lieutenant
Brown</name> in great excitement.</p>
                    <p>S.-L. Brown. I say——</p>
                    <p>S.-L. Wood. Run away, dear. No
time for you. Brass hats expected in
large numbers.</p>
                    <p>S.-L. B. I've lost my platoon.</p>
                    <p>S.-L. W. Have you looked in <hi rend="it">all</hi>
your pockets, Freddy?</p>
                    <p>S.-L. B. I sent it up under the Sergeant,
and he must have mistaken the
place, strafe him! And I told the Adjutant
I'd be the other side of this
wood, doing Visual Training, when the
General came round.</p>
                    <p>S.-L. W. (<title>impressed at last</title>). My hat,
you're in for it! Look out, here they
come.</p>
                    <p rend="it">
                        <name>Second-Lieutenant Brown</name> fades into
the landscape.</p>
                    <p rend="it">
            Enter the <name>General</name> and the <name>C.O.</name>, with
<name>Staff-Captain</name>, <name>Adjutant</name> and <name>Sergeant-Major</name>.
The Platoon labours
on and takes no notice. <name>Second-Lieutenant
Wood</name> comes to attention and
salutes. The <name>General</name> remarks on the
fine physique of the men, inspects the
wire entanglement and explains how
            <pb xml:id="page200" n="pg 200"/>
            he used to do it when he was a subaltern.
<name>Private Hogg</name>, a recruit unused
to Generals, stands gazing awestruck,
but catches the <name>Adjutant's</name> eye and,
gets on feverishly with his work. The
cortège passes on, and the platoon
heaves a sigh of relief and stands easy.</p>
                    <p rend="it">
            Re-enter Second-Lieutenant Brown.</p>
                    <p>
            S.-L. W. Go away, my good man;
we've nothing for you.</p>
                    <p>
            S.-L. B. I say, like a good chap—— They
confer earnestly. </p>
                    <p rend="sc">Curtain.
         </p>
                    <p rend="it">
                        <hi rend="sc">Scene II.</hi> —  The other side of the wood.
Time, two minutes later.
         </p>
                    <p rend="it">
            Enter Second-Lieutenant Brown at the
double with Second-Lieutenant
Wood's platoon. He hurriedly gets
it to work at Visual Training.</p>
                    <p rend="it">
            Enter <name>General</name>, with suite as before. The
platoon carries on, taking no notice.
Second-Lieutenant Brown comes to
attention and salutes. The <name>General</name>
praises the appearance of the men
and explains how Visual Training
was taught before the Crimean War.
The <name>Adjutant</name> suddenly recognises
<name>Private Hogg</name> and develops a nasty
cough.
         </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi>The General (to C. O. as they move
away).</hi> But do you think, Colonel, that
either of those smart young officers of
yours would keep their heads in a
sudden emergency?</p>
                    <p rend="it">
            The <name>Adjutant</name> restrains a natural desire
to wink at the <name>Sergeant-Major</name>.</p>
                    <p>
                        <name rend="sc">Curtain.</name>
                    </p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/200.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1261" type="div2">
                <head>NURSERY RHYMES OF LONDON TOWN.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e1265" type="div3">
                    <head>I.—KINGSWAY.</head>
                    <lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>Walking on the King's Way, lady, my lady,</l>
                            <l>Walking on the King's Way, will you go in red?</l>
                            <l>With a silken wimple, and a ruby on your finger,</l>
                            <l>And a furry mantle trailing where you tread?</l>
                            <l>Neither red nor ruby I'll wear upon the King's Way;</l>
                            <l>I will go in duffle grey with nothing on my head.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>Walking on the King's Way, lady, my lady,</l>
                            <l>Walking on the King's Way, will you go in blue?</l>
                            <l>With an ermine border, and a plume of peacock feathers,</l>
                            <l>And a silver circlet, and a sapphire on your shoe?</l>
                            <l>Neither blue nor sapphire I'll wear upon the King's Way;</l>
                            <l>I will go in duffle grey, and barefoot too.</l>
                        </lg>
                        <lg>
                            <l>Walking on the King's Way, lady, my lady,</l>
                            <l>Walking on the King's Way, will you go in green?</l>
                            <l>With a golden girdle, and a pointed velvet slipper,</l>
                            <l>And a crown of emeralds fit for a queen?</l>
                            <l>Neither green nor emerald I'll wear upon the King's Way;</l>
                            <l>I will go in duffle grey so lovely to be seen,</l>
                            <l>And Somebody will kiss me and call me his queen.</l>
                        </lg>
                    </lg>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"The depression in northern India has
continued to travel eastwards and is to-day
affecting north-east India.</p>
                        <p>Forecast: Some rain in the submarine districts
of north-east India."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Amrita Bazar Patrika.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>It's a wet life anyhow, and submarines
were made to be depressed.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page201" n="pg 201"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1366" type="div3">
                    <head>ARMLETS AND THE MAN.</head>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/201.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page202" n="pg 202"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1380" type="div2">
                <head>ESSENCE OF PARLIAMENT.</head>
                <p>
                    <title>Tuesday, March 14th.</title>—Ministers as
they passed through Palace Yard on
their way to the House shuddered as
they observed a long, black, wicked-looking
motor-car, shaped like a torpedo.
In this machine Mr. <name rend="sc">Pemberton-Billing</name>,
the new Air-Member for
East Herts, had done most of his electioneering.
Now he had arrived to
take his seat and, rumour said, to make
his maiden speech. Would the Front
Bench survive it?</p>
                <p>If the new Member could have
jumped straight from the steering-wheel
into the Chamber, and
with his eloquence still at
white-heat have got his
fulminating message off
his chest, strange things
might have happened.
But fortunately or unfortunately
the procedure
of the House discourages
these dramatic effects.
For nearly an hour he
had to wait and listen to
Ministerial replies to questions
which he must have
found painfully trivial.</p>
                <p>Even when the weary
catechism was at last over
there was a further delay.
With great lack of consideration
for the dignity
of East Herts the <name rend="sc">Prime
Minister</name> had been so
careless as to catch a bad
cold, and was not in his
place. On his behalf,
therefore, Sir <name rend="sc">Edward
Grey</name> made a statement
regarding the entry of
Portugal into the War.
The gist of it was that
the most ancient of our
Allies has acquired a good-sized
Fleet at no expense to herself,
and that Germany is confronted by a
new enemy in Africa.</p>
                <p>At last the new Member was called
upon to take his seat. Belonging to no
party he could not, of course, enjoy the
usual official escort to the Table. But,
like another young man in a hurry
who in somewhat similar circumstances
preferred scorpions to whips, Mr. <name rend="sc">Pemberton-Billing</name>
seemed quite satisfied
with the ministrations of Mr. <name rend="sc">Ronald
McNeill</name> and Sir <name rend="sc">Henry Dalziel</name>.</p>
                <p>Dispensing with the usual period of
rest and refreshment, he assumed his
seat immediately after shaking hands
with the <name rend="sc">Speaker</name>. Who knew but
that Mr. <name rend="sc">Lowther</name>, recognising the
anxiety of Members to hear the latest
War news from East Herts, might call
him at once?</p>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/202.png"/>
                </figure>
                <p>Routine, however, was too much for
romance. For an hour or more Mr.
<name rend="sc">Tennant</name> rambled over the wide field
provided for him, but without stumbling
upon anything very fresh or startling,
unless indeed it was the discovery that
"Intelligence is a very delicate matter."
This occurred in the course of a
protracted description of what was
being done to protect the country
against air raids. The organisation of
the anti-aircraft defences was now
complete for London and was approaching
completion for the country. But Mr.
<name rend="sc">Tennant</name> hastened to add for Mr.
<name rend="sc">Billing's</name> benefit—the standard would
be still further raised when more
material was available.</p>
                <p>When he was in the Government
Mr. <name rend="sc">Hobhouse</name> was not less economical
of information in his official utterances
than any of his Ministerial colleagues.
Now that he is out of it he is all for
full disclosure. Why had Mr. <name rend="sc">Tennant</name>
said nothing of Gallipoli or Salonika,
Loos and Neuve Chapelle? Why, if
we were allowed to know that three
million goatskins had been provided for
the Army, might we not know how
many men were going to wear them?
In his view the result of the East Herts
election was due to the Government
having kept Parliament in the dark.</p>
                <p>At last the stage was clear for Mr.
<name rend="sc">Pemberton-Billing</name>, who, considering
how long he had been kept waiting,
made a creditable <title>début</title>. He had, it is
true, no startling revelations to make,
or, at any rate, did not make them. His
principal point was that we must exterminate
the Zeppelins, and that we
had aeroplanes enough and pilots enough
to do it now. He would be delighted to
introduce Mr. <name rend="sc">Tennant</name> to the men and
the machines, while as for bombs he
was prepared to lay them on the Table
of the House. For a first performance
it was quite good, even if not entirely
equal to the advance-billing.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Wednesday, March 15.</title>—I am rather
surprised that none of the evening papers
had the enterprise to come out
to-night with a contents bill bearing
the words—</p>
                <p>"<name rend="sc">Great Attack on
Portsmouth</name>,"</p>
                <p>for the legend would have
been not only startling but
unusually accurate. The
House of Lords assembled
this afternoon in the expectation
of hearing important
statements from
the Earl of <name rend="sc">Derby</name> and
Earl <name rend="sc">Kitchener</name> on the
recruiting crisis. What
it was at first compelled
to listen to was the Earl
of <name rend="sc">Portsmouth</name> giving his
views on the Anglo-Danish
Agreement. With dogmatic
ponderosity he declared
that the Agreement
was losing us the friendship
of the other Scandinavian
countries, that it
was not preventing goods
getting into Germany, and
that it ought to be abrogated
forthwith.</p>
                <p>I doubt if any of the
Peers present had ever
heard anything like the
castigation which the
Marquis of <name rend="sc">Lansdowne</name> administered.
Where did the noble Earl collect the
kind of information that he had seen fit
to pour forth? He seemed to have
swallowed a lot of stories purveyed
by people who were no friends to
this country. There was not a word
of truth in the suggestions he had
made, and the Government, far from
abrogating the Agreement, intended to
maintain and develop the policy on
which it was based. It was a great
pity that the noble earl should have
identified himself with an agitation
that was neither wise nor patriotic.</p>
                <p>Lord <name rend="sc">Portsmouth's</name> family name is
<name rend="sc">Wallop</name>; this afternoon he lived up
to it.</p>
                <p>At the present moment Lord <name rend="sc">Derby</name> is
perhaps the most prominent man in the
country next to the Prime <name rend="sc">Minister</name>.
<pb xml:id="page203" n="pg 203"/>
Yet he is not a member of the Government.
When to-day he rose from the
Opposition benches to defend his conduct
as Director-General of Recruiting
and inspirer of the <name rend="sc">Prime Minister's</name>
famous pledge to married men, he illustrated
the anomaly by the remark
that, while he was doing his best to get
that pledge fulfilled, Lord <name rend="sc">Selborne</name>,
who was a member of the Government,
had been telling the farmers that
he (Lord <name rend="sc">Derby</name>) did not speak with
authority.</p>
                <p>Later he did a second turn—this
time in his capacity as Chairman of
the Joint Air Committee. Quite the
most satisfactory part of his reply was
the announcement that Lord <name rend="sc">Montagu</name>
himself had consented to become
a member of the Committee. It is, of
course, contrary to all the traditions of
the British Government to give a man
a job which he understands already.
But in war-time even the most sensational
experiments must not be
ruled out.</p>
                <p>
                    <title>Thursday, March 16th.</title>—The House
of Commons is so constructed that no
matter how often the party-system is
expelled it will always return. In spite
of the Coalition, or perhaps because of
it, the old strife of Whigs and Tories
has revived, though the lines of cleavage
are quite different from what they
were.</p>
                <p>The new Tories are the men who
believe that the War is going to be
decided by battles in Flanders and the
North Sea, and would sacrifice everything
for victory, even the privilege of
abusing the Government. The new
Whigs are the men who consider that
the House of Commons is the decisive
arena, and that even the defeat of the
Germans would be dearly purchased at
the cost of the individual's right to say
and do what he pleased.</p>
                <p>Naturally these latter object to the
shortening of the Parliamentary week,
and to-day they took a division on the
subject. Into the "No" Lobby flocked
a motley crew—the champions of the
single men who don't want to fight at
all, the upholders of the married men
who protest against being called upon
to fulfil their engagement until every
single "<title>embusqué</title>" has been dragged
out of his lair, and, paradoxically
enough, the universal conscriptionists
who would force everyone to serve, but
are opposed to piecemeal compulsion.
The Government carried their point
easily enough by 128 votes to 67, but
evidently have to reckon with a new
concentration of forces which may be
more dangerous in the future.</p>
                <p>When the House of Commons passed
the Bill prohibiting duelling it ought
to have made an exception in favour
of its own members. Nothing would
have done more to raise the tone of
debate, for offenders against decorum
would gradually have eliminated one
another. This afternoon, for example,
Sir <name rend="sc">Hamar Greenwood</name> twitted Mr.
<name rend="sc">Hogge</name> with sheltering himself under
the patriotism of a soldier stepson, and
Mr. <name rend="sc">Hogge</name> retaliated with the suggestion
that Sir <name rend="sc">Hamar</name> ought to be
with his regiment. A hundred years
ago this would have meant a meeting in
Hyde Park and a possible vacancy at
Sunderland or East Edinburgh. To-day
it merely brought a rebuke from the
<name rend="sc">Chairman of Committees</name>.</p>
                <p>Again, in the days of our rude fore-fathers
Sir <name rend="sc">John Simon</name> would have felt
constrained to send a challenge to Mr.
<name rend="sc">Walter Long</name>. The late <name rend="sc">Home Secretary</name>
had delivered an attack upon the
Government which Mr. <name rend="sc">Long</name> declared
would be heartily welcomed in Berlin.
For a much less serious accusation than
that the Duke of <name rend="sc">Wellington</name> called
out Lord <name rend="sc">Winchelsea</name>. Sir <name rend="sc">John Simon</name>
has no such resource, and must continue
to suffer under the imputation—a
little consoled, no doubt, by the companionship
of Mr. <name rend="sc">Hogge</name>.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/203.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <quote>
                    <p>
"Young Lady, competent, <name rend="sc">wishes drive
taxi</name>, commercial or private car; preferably a
doctor; advertiser has had three years' surgical
training."—<title>Provincial Paper.</title>
                    </p>
                </quote>
                <p>She should be useful, whatever happens.</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <pb xml:id="page204" n="pg 204"/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1623" type="div2">
                <head>AT THE PLAY.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e1627" type="div3">
                    <head>"Kultur at Home."</head>
                    <p>Each of the authors—Mr. <name rend="sc">Rudolf
Besier</name> and Mrs. <name rend="sc">John Spottiswoode</name>—has
personal knowledge of the home-life
of the Bosch; and their excellent
sketch of Prussian manners might have
served usefully as a warning to us if we
could have seen it a few years ago.
But at this time of day, after nineteen
months' experience of the enemy, I
doubt its utility as a source of illumination.</p>
                    <p>It would be futile to represent the
Prussian officer as an angel in the
house, for we have long since learned to
know him as a devil in the field. And
it is almost as futile to picture his prodigious
self-conceit, his vile taste in
dress and furniture, his conjugal infidelity,
his habit of treating his women-folk
as menials, since these vices are
human and venial in comparison with
what the War has revealed. Anyone
might easily hazard the conjecture that
the murderers of Belgium had never
entertained too fastidious a respect
for womanhood; and after the destruction
of Louvain and Ypres it is mere
bathos to insist that the perpetrators
of these outrages against art had previously
cherished a Philistine affection
for antimacassars and plush sofas.</p>
                    <p>A common difficulty with me when
I witness stage tragedies arising out of
a marriage of uncongenial types is to
understand how the couple ever came
together. And so here, when the
English girl, <title>Margaret Tinworth</title>, in
face of poverty and parental disapproval,
marries a Prussian officer in
a small garrison town, and then finds
all sorts of unbearable conditions in her
surroundings, one asks oneself, and
fails to discover, what kind of glamour
he had cast over her that most of these
conditions, already patent enough in
the society in which she had moved,
had contrived either to escape her
notice or to appear tolerable. True,
she had gone to Germany to find
release from the solitude of a motherless
home, where an unsympathetic
father had no attention to spare from
his art treasures; but, with so admirable
an aunt as <title>Lady Lushington</title> to chaperon
her in her own country, it was not easy
to see why she must needs resort to
exotic consolation.</p>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/204.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <p>However, I do not propose to set my
judgment up against that of the
authors, male and female, in regard to
the credibility of her taste in men,
since, after all, the heart of a woman
is a thing past finding out. But I do
venture to dispute the reasonableness
of her ultimate attitude in conditions
where this enigmatic organ was not
directly concerned. For you are to
understand that in the Third Act the
brutality of her husband and the insults
hurled at England, which she
was expected, as a Prussianised wife,
to approve, had become more than she
could bear; and in the last Act we find
her in a Luxembourg hotel on her way
home to England under the care of
<title>Lord</title> and <title>Lady Lushington</title>. It is the
4th of August, 1914; Germany has
declared war; German regiments are
marching through the town; England
has not yet spoken. The girl is in
grievous doubt as to whether she ought
not, in the changed circumstances, to
return to her Prussian home. One
could easily appreciate her attitude if
she had argued, "I am German by
marriage; though I have lost my love
for my husband it is my duty, when he
is risking his life for his country, the
country of my adoption, to go back
and watch over his home for him."
But that was not her argument; her
argument was that England—the
England that she had so stoutly defended
against German ridicule and
contempt—had been false to her honour
as the sworn friend of France, and that
it was her business to go back to
Germany and eat humble pie. Whatever
the audience may have felt about
these reflections on the conduct of
England, they must at least have been
irritated by the fantastic improbability
of the girl's motive. Very fortunately
at this juncture the voice of the paper-boy
is heard in the street conveying
the thrilling news of our tardy entry
into the quarrel; and a glad <title>Margaret</title>,
having recovered her respect for her
native land, consents to return home
to it.</p>
                    <p>Miss <name rend="sc">Rosalie Toller</name> played the
part with great charm and sympathy,
and with a lightly-worn grace and dignity
that were pure English. Serving
as a foil to her in taste and deportment
and social tradition, the <title>Elsa Kolbeck</title>
of Miss <name rend="sc">Dolly Holmes-Gore</name> was
extraordinarily German—a quite remarkable
performance.</p>
                    <p>Miss <name rend="sc">Marianne Caldwell</name> as <title>Frau
Major Kolbeck</title>, the hostess of <title>Margaret</title>,
made a most lovable drudge; and Miss
<name rend="sc">Dora Gregory</name> had no difficulty in
showing how the wife of a Prussian
Colonel, though in her husband's eyes
her main purpose in life may be to
minister to his inner man, can wield
an authority little less than that of
the All-Highest over the wives of the
regiment. Female society in the little
garrison town was further represented
by Miss <name rend="sc">May Haysack</name> and Miss <name rend="sc">Una
Venning</name>, who played, with more than
enough vivacity, a brace of giggling
flappers, very curious about the more
private portion of the bride's trousseau.</p>
                    <p>Miss <name rend="sc">Vane Featherston</name>, as <title>Lady
Lushington</title>, had too little to do, and
did it most humanly; and Mr. <name rend="sc">Otho
Stuart</name> illustrated with a very natural
ease the kind of simple friendship, as
between a man and a woman, which it
takes an Anglo-Saxon intelligence to
understand.</p>
                    <p>The officers, though there might have
been more of the blond beast about
them, were sufficiently Prussian, and
Mr. <name rend="sc">Malcolm Cherry</name>, as <title>Margaret's</title>
husband, indicated with much precision
the change in the behaviour of a
German gentleman, after marriage,
towards the lady he has consented to
honour with the thing he calls his
heart.</p>
                    <p>Apart from the one or two doubtful
points which I have referred to, the
play went well, though it seems a pity
that so much insistence should have
been laid upon the lack of culture
(English sense) in households where
the strictest economy was essential.
One was conscious of a rather painful
note of vulgarity in the attitude of
<title>Margaret's</title> father, where he sniffs at
the sordid environment of her German
home. Impecuniosity is of course a
prevalent trouble among German officers
in small garrison towns; but one
would have preferred that if bad taste
in dress and furniture had to be ridiculed
the laugh should have been at
the expense of a richer society. Finally,
<pb xml:id="page205" n="pg 205"/>
I wonder a little that the authors, who
must have known better, should have
helped to perpetuate the popular misconception
by which the German word
"Kultur" is regarded as the equivalent
of our "culture."</p>
                    <p>O. S.</p>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1736" type="div3">
                    <head>"A Kiss for Cinderella."</head>
                    <p>No well-fed person need ever quite
expect to understand one of Sir <name rend="sc">J. M.
Barrie's</name> mystery plays at a single
sitting. That's one of his best trumps,
of course. But it always seems to me
that, like so many writers of genius, he
never quite knows what are his best
and what his poorest things, and just
tosses them to us to sort out for ourselves.
In this new instance, to work
off a piece of strictly professional
criticism, it is clear that both prologue
and epilogue are much too protracted.
It is a sound dramatic canon, which
not even our most brilliant chartered
libertine of stage-land can flout with
impunity, not to keep your audience
in too long a suspense while preparing
your salient theme, nor, after quickening
their interest and firing their imagination,
to chill with the obvious or
distract with the irrelevant.</p>
                    <p>Sir <name rend="sc">James's</name>
                        <title>Cinderella</title> is maid-of-all-work
to the housekeeper of a retired
humourist turned painter (Mr. <name rend="sc">O. B.
Clarence</name>), a vague peppery sentimental
old bachelor with an ideal of which
a full-sized cast of the "Venus di Milo"
stands for symbol in his studio.
<title>Cinderella</title> is dumpy and plain (that
is the idea which Miss <name rend="sc">Hilda Trevelyan</name>
tries loyally but without much
success to suggest to us), but she
has the tiniest possible feet. Regretfully
admitting the superiority of
Venus's "uppers" she takes heart of
grace, knowing from history how important
in princely eyes is her own
particular endowment. She is always
asking odd questions, such as "why
doctors ask you to say ninety-nine"
and tailors measuring gentlemen's legs
call out "42-6; 38-7." She also has
a queer <hi rend="it">penchant</hi> for stealing boards,
betrays some connection with a firm,
Celeste et Cie. of Bond Street, and
knows some German words. Which
concatenation of facts justifies the old
bachelor in consulting a friendly policeman
(Mr. <name rend="sc">Gerald du Maurier</name>). Bond
Street turns out to be a mean street,
Celeste et Cie the name under which
<title>Cinderella</title> trades, dealing in medical
treatment, shaves, friendly counsel or
dressmaking all at a penny fee. Also
she keeps in a Wendyish sort of way
a <title>crêche</title> for orphan babes in boxes
evidently made of the borrowed boards.</p>
                    <p>Our policeman, coming to work up
his case, loses his heart. But <title>Cinderella's</title>
mind is preoccupied with her ball.
Ill from overwork and underfeeding,
she wanders into the street, falls faint—and
dreams her ball. Whereupon our
authentic magician, coming to his
own, lifts a curtain of her queer little
mind and gives us an all too short
glimpse of the state function, with
an <hi rend="it">h</hi>-dropping, strap-hanging King and
Queen out of a pack of cards; their disdainful
Prince, who is none other, of
course, than our policeman done into a
bewigged <title>Monsieur Beaucaire</title>; a moody
and peremptory Peer, <title>Lord Times</title>; the
Censor (black-visored, with an axe);
a grotesquely informal Lord Mayor; a
bevy of preposterous revue beauties
with their caps set at the Prince,
against an all-gold background with the
orphans babbling in a royal box above
the throne. Of course you have the
heroine's belated entry, her triumph
<pb xml:id="page206" n="pg 206"/>
and her abrupt flight, and the voice of
the distraught Prince crying after her,
which is of course the voice of her own
policeman, who finds her and takes her
to hospital. Then convalescence in a
cottage (alleged, really a palace) by the
sea and the final declaration of
"romantical" policeman's love.</p>
                    <p>Sir <name rend="sc">James</name> banked heavily on Miss
<name rend="sc">Hilda Trevelyan</name> as his <title>Cinderella</title>.
The English tradition of manufacturing
parts to fit your players, instead of
training players to create your parts,
was never more shrewdly followed.
She was most adorable in the exquisite
business of arranging the offer of her
policeman's hand. Mr. <name rend="sc">du Maurier's</name>
bobby was as delightfully honest,
plain-witted, heavy-booted and friendly
a fellow as ever held up
a bus or convoyed a
covey of children across
a street. But as the
Prince, who was "so
blasted particular," he
had a chance of showing
that rare talent for
the grotesque which no
part has given him since
his inimitable <title>Captain
Hook</title>, I wish indeed we
could see more of him
in this rich vein. <title>Mr.
Clarence</title> was the vague
old gentleman (or the
vague old gentleman,
<title>Mr. Clarence</title>) to the life.
Miss <name rend="sc">Henrietta Watson</name>,
as the hospital doctor,
bullied her patients
and probationers in the
approved manner of
medical autocrats of the
gentler sex. An excellent
<title>Lord Mayor</title> (Mr. <name rend="sc">Liston
Lyle</name>), an irrepressible wounded Tommy
by Mr. A. E. <name rend="sc">George</name> and an aristocratic
probationer by Miss <name rend="sc">Elizabeth
Pollock</name>, were notable performances.
Many others also ran—and ran well.
The piece should do the same.</p>
                    <p>T.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="d1e1841" type="div3">
                    <head>Kennel Companions.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Lady wishes join another in dogs' boarding
home; trial first as paying guest."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Bournemouth Daily Echo.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"The wedding was a quiet one. The bridegroom's
party, who motored from Colombo,
were met some distance away from the
Walauwa by a procession of forty-five elephants,
dancers, etc., and was conducted to
the bride's residence, where they were welcomed.
Shortly after the arrival of the bridegroom's
party, a wedding breakfast was served,
seventy-five sitting down to a sumptuous
repast."—<title>Ceylon Observer.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <p>We wonder how many elephants,
dancers and guests are required for a
noisy wedding, This, we note, was a
quiet one.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1873" type="div2">
                <head>THE GREAT PETITION.</head>
                <quote type="note">
"A notice has been received by parents
whose sons are at Rugby School that, owing to
increased cost of living, an extra week's holiday
is to be given in the Easter vacation so that
boarding-house masters should not feel the
strain."—<title>Letter to "The Daily Mail."</title>
                </quote>
                <p>Chapman major put down <title>The Daily
Mail</title> and looked round No. 11 study.
"Think of those Rugby blighters having
all the luck," he protested.</p>
                <p>"These prices will ruin old Dabs,
and a jolly good job. The old beast
needs ruining." This from Dyson,
occupied in writing out two hundred
Greek lines (with accents).</p>
                <p>"The Head," said Chapman major,
"may be a beast, but he's a bally
patriot. He swishes twice as hard on
a day when the War news is bad. I
felt the fall of Namur more than anyone
in England. What do you chaps
say to getting up a petition to him
stating that under the distressing circumstances
we are ready to make
sacrifices and give up two weeks'
school?"</p>
                <p>"Rot," cried Dyson. "Hundred-and-seventy
more to do before call-over.
I'd rather go on ruining Dabs."</p>
                <p>But even Dyson, when once his lines
were finished, caught the infectious
spirit of patriotism, and, like the rest,
appended his signature to the following
prose composition from the laborious
pen of Chapman major:—</p>
                <p>"To the <name rend="sc">Rev. the Head Master</name>,—Whereas
the Great War for the liberties
of Europe involves sacrifices from all,
and the rise in prices must cause considerable
difficulties, hitherto endured
with noble self-effacement, to house-masters,
We, the undersigned, feel
that a corresponding sacrifice on our
part is necessary, and respectfully pray
that we may be permitted to give up
two weeks of the Easter term, thus
allowing ourselves more time for war-work
in our respective homes and
relieving our house-masters from an
overwhelming burden."</p>
                <p>The petition was formally handed to
the Head.</p>
                <p>For two days he gave no sign. Then
on the morning of the third day he
arose to address the school:</p>
                <p>"In the dark days through which
we are passing, when the liberties of
Europe tremble in the balance ("Hear,
hear," from Chapman), it gratifies me
very much to receive a petition from
the school suggesting that in consequence
of the financial
strain there should be a
prolongation of the customary
Easter vacation.
It pleases me to see that
the financial responsibilities
of the house-masters
are appreciated by their
charges. Would that our
<title>Government</title> had the
same patriotic horror of
extravagance! However
we must consider the
<title>post-bellum</title> conditions.
All the intellect of England
will be needed after
the War ("Double holiday
task," prophesied
Dyson). Yet I feel that
steps must be taken on
the lines of your petition
(an enthusiastic friend
here patted Chapman on
the back). So, after
consultation with the
house-masters, I have
arranged that in future only two courses
will be served at dinner, and that there
will be a reduction in the number of
breakfast dishes. Thus without your
being handicapped in the intellectual
contest your laudable and patriotic
desire to reduce expenses will be met.
I may repeat that your consideration
for your house-masters, who perform
useful and necessary functions, has
gratified me."</p>
                <p>Number 11 study that night was
barricaded against all comers. A howling
crowd in the corridor was demanding
the blood of Chapman major.</p>
                <p>"Didn't I tell you to keep on ruining
Dabs?" said Dyson. "Now the old
beast will be wallowing in Exchequer
Bonds bought out of our sausages and
suet."</p>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="images/206.png"/>
                </figure>
                <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                <div xml:id="d1e1939" type="div3">
                    <head>Daylight-Saving.</head>
                    <quote>
                        <p>
"Cook-General Wanted ... Comfortable
home ... No washing or windows."</p>
                        <p>
                            <title>Morning Paper.</title>
                        </p>
                    </quote>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page207" n="pg 207"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/207.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="d1e1966" type="div2">
                <head>OUR BOOKING-OFFICE.</head>
                <div xml:id="d1e1970" type="div3">
                    <head>(<title>By Mr. Punch's Staff of Learned Clerks</title>.)</head>
                    <p>Even those who have overloaded their shelves with books
about the War must, I think, find a place for <title>From Mons
to Ypres with French</title>, by <name rend="sc">Frederic Coleman (Sampson
Low)</name>. It is a most remarkably vivid and varied record of
the writer's experiences, set down in a very simple and
direct style, without the least effort at flummery and high-falutin.
I can speak for one reader at any rate on whom
it made a very deep impression. Mr. <name rend="sc">Coleman</name> is, by his
own account, an American and an automobilist. Those
who get his book will judge him, by the unadorned
account of what he did, to be a man of great courage and
modesty, with an imperturbable shrewdness and a humour
proof against all dangers and disappointments. Driving,
as he did, a motor-car for the British Headquarters, and
in particular for General <name rend="sc">de Lisle</name>, he saw as much fighting
as any man need wish for and had magnificent
opportunities of forming a judgment on the effects of
German shell-fire. There is a pathetic photograph of his
car hit by a shell outside Messines. I have spoken of the
simplicity and directness of Mr. <name rend="sc">Coleman's</name> style; he himself
describes his book as a plain tale. It has, indeed,
that kind of plainness which in dealing with enterprises of
great pith and moment has a peculiar brilliancy of its own.
The account, for instance, of the Cambrai—Le Cateau battle,
with all its vicissitudes, is extraordinarily graphic and
interesting, and the story of the charge of some fifty men
of the 9th Lancers against more than twice their number
of German Dragoons of the Guard stirs the blood as with
the sound of a trumpet. Delightful too is the narrative
of how Major <name rend="sc">Bridges</name> found two hundred completely
exhausted stragglers seated despairingly upon the pavement
of the square at St. Quentin, and how by means of a
penny whistle and a toy drum he got them to move and
brought them eventually to Roye and safety. Altogether
a capital book.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>
                        <title>A Great Success</title> (<name rend="sc">Smith, Elder</name>) is about a new-risen
literary star, <title>Arthur Meadows</title>, his loving, unbrilliant wife,
and a coruscating society lion-huntress, <title>Lady Dunstable</title>.
Having heard this much, you will hardly need to be told
that <title>Lady D.</title> takes up the author violently, that he is
dazzled by the glitter of her conversational snares, and that
the story resolves itself into a duel between her ladyship
and (I quote the publishers) "the wife whom she despises
and tries to set down." Nor are you likely to be in any
uncertainty about the final victory. This is brought about,
with the assistance of the long arm of coincidence, by
<title>Doris</title>, the neglected wife, finding herself in a position to
prevent her rival's unsatisfactory son from contracting
matrimony with a very undesirable alien. <title>Doris</title> indeed,
and another female victim of <title>Lady Dunstable</title> (also deposited
on the scene by the same obliging arm), get busy
unearthing so various a past for the undesirable one that
she retires baffled, epigrammatic brilliance bites the dust,
and domesticity is left triumphant. It is a jolly little story,
very short, refreshingly simple, and constructed throughout
on the most approved library lines. If the writer's name
were not Mrs. <name rend="sc">Humphry Ward</name>, I should say that she
ought to be encouraged to persevere, and even recommended
to try her hand next time at something a little
more substantial.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <pb xml:id="page208" n="pg 208"/>
                    <p>Let me recommend Mr. <name rend="sc">Rothay Reynolds</name>' <title>My Slav
Friends</title> (<name rend="sc">Mills and Boon</name>) as a corrective to Mr. <name rend="sc">Stephen
Graham's</name>
                        <title>Holy Russia</title>, which I prescribed some while ago
with faint reservations. Both writers set out to interpret our
mysterious ally to us. Mr. <name rend="sc">Graham</name> always looks through
a rosy-tinted monocle. Mr. <name rend="sc">Reynolds</name> takes the road of
balanced appreciations, candour and kindly humour—unquestionably
more effective in the matter of making sincere
proselytes. He has produced a fascinating book, discreetly
discursive—a book that seems to let you into the real secrets
of a people's soul. He believes in the sincerity of Russian
promises to Poland, and claims that the Poles share his
belief, but he does not pretend that this most unfortunate
of nations has no grievances against its suzerain. I wonder
whether our perverse Intelligences are capable of making
the deduction that, if the progressives in Russia can forget
their quarrel with reaction for sake of our great common
cause, they themselves might mitigate some of the severity
of their anti-tsarism. Mr. <name rend="sc">Reynolds</name> has much that is
to the point to say about the good old British legends of
darkest Russia now chiefly
kept going by third-rate
novelists and unscrupulous
journalists. He makes it
clear that, though there is
much to change, changes are
coming as fast as they can
be assimilated, indeed even
a little faster. Finally I
wish that those who control
the destinies of our theatre
might read what is written
here of the traditions of the
stage in a country where the
drama is an art, not a mere
speculation.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>Despite its name there is
a simple directness about
the theme of Mr. <name rend="sc">Warwick
Deeping's</name>
                        <title>Unrest</title> (<name rend="sc">Cassell</name>)
that I found refreshing.
<title>Martin Frensham</title> was a
dramatist, and the fortunate
possessor of an adoring wife, a charming home and a
successful reputation. So quite naturally he grew bored
with all three. Then there came on the scene one
<title>Judith Ruddiger</title>, a widow, with red lips, who drove a
great touring-car with abandon, played masculine golf and
generally appealed in <title>Frensham</title> to the elemental what-d'you-call-'ems.
So these two decided to plunge into the
freer life by the process of elopement. I was a little disappointed
here. There had been so much chat about the
Big Things that I had expected a rather more expansive
setting to their adventure than Monte Carlo, followed by a
round of first-class hotels. Moreover <title>Judith</title>, had a way of
addressing her companion as "partner," which emphasised
her wild Western personality to a degree that must have
been almost painful at a winter-sports' resort full of schoolmasters.
So I was hardly at all astonished when before
long <title>Frensham</title> grew more bored than ever. Meanwhile
the adoring wife (whom the author has sketched very
sympathetically and well) had refused to divorce him; and
so in the long run—well, you can see from the start where
the long-run is destined to end. But you will probably not
like a pleasant tale the less for this. Mr. <name rend="sc">Deeping</name> certainly
has courage. There is a scene or two in which he
takes his amazonian <title>Judith</title> to the very edge of bathos.
"She could shoot straight with a pistol, and proved it by
bringing a revolver to the summer-house, and making
<title>Frensham</title> hang his hat on the rail-fence that ran along
the wood." Rough wooing for timid dramatists! I couldn't
resist picturing how the late Mr. <name rend="sc">Pélissier</name> would have
handled this situation.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="images/208.png"/>
                    </figure>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>I wonder whether <name rend="sc">Evelyn Braxscombe Petter</name> just
decided that her novel could not be up to date without a
German spy and so forth, or whether she really set out to
do her bit for the War by commenting on the Teutonic idea
of honour. Anyhow, one must admit that her <title>Gretchen
Meyer</title> is drawn with rather uncommon skill, even if her
subterranean mental processes are never exactly elucidated
in <title>Miss Velanty's Disclosure</title> (<name rend="sc">Chapman and Hall</name>). Though
educated in England and dependent, to their misfortune, on
English friends for maintenance, there always lurked in
<title>Gretchen's</title> attitude of impartial selfishness a certain muffled
hostility to the ways of this country, and particularly to an
objectionable habit she found in us of placing an exaggerated
value on straightforward dealing. This culminated in a
quite gratuitous, and indeed
even insane, demand on the
man who for his sins was in
love with her that he should
surrender either his English
ideal or her. That he did as
wisely as honestly in letting
her go and be d——d to her,
I for one had no doubt, nor
I think had the authoress,
for, although she could never
quite forget that <title>Gretchen</title>
was her heroine, endowing
her with a kind of beauty
and even baldly labelling her
attractive, it is really, on
the whole, a designedly repulsive
person she has presented
to us. Though an
interesting study in Teuton
perfidy and certainly better
written than the columns of
most evening papers, I can
hardly recommend the book
as a restful change from that class of literature.</p>
                    <milestone rend="hr" unit="rule"/>
                    <p>Mr. <name rend="sc">H. B. Marriott Watson</name> has invented a gentleman
of the road, <title>Dick Ryder</title>, of whom his publishers, <name rend="sc">Methuen</name>,
confess themselves very proud in that nice way they have.
Armed with a bodkin and a barker he rushes and tushes
his way through life, slitting weasands and dubbing every
cully he meets a muckworm in the pleasant idiom current
(so I take it on faith) in the time of our second <name rend="sc">James</name>.
I should have been more impressed with this hero's feats
in the first few tales of <title>As it Chanced</title> if they had been in
the very faintest degree plausible. Never surely were such
preposterous fights, in which the whole action of a score
of desperate opponents is completely suspended while the
redoubtable one brings off his splendid stunts. I gratefully
remember once having been helped through a dull day by
<title>The House on the Downs</title>. Unless memory gilds my judgment
the author put some reasonable amount of invention
into that. But these collected tales are rather indifferent
pot-boiling if you are to take any other standard but that
of the gallery's formula for yarns of adventure. Perhaps,
"as it chanced," my war lunch did not agree with me. But
anyway I really cannot quite honestly commend this
volume to any but the most stalwart of Mr. <name rend="sc">Marriott
Watson's</name> many loyal friends.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>